<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – narratives</title>
    <link>/data_type/narratives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in narratives on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/data_type/narratives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Adamdar/CA</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adamdar.ca/&#34;&gt;Adamdar/CA&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage and storytelling narratives from Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Uzbekistan, and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: FemAgora</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/femagora/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/femagora/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://femagora.org/&#34;&gt;FemAgora&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to fostering transnational feminist solidarity in Central Asia. The organization is involved in organization of Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march and the issue of employment of transgender people. FemAgora hosts annual FemAgora Central Asian festival for those involved in feminist, gender-sensitive, and/or women-led work.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminist Translocalities</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminisms.co/&#34;&gt;Feminist Translocalities&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots transnational feminist organization aiming to bring together and support feminist and LGBTQ+ activists from Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia. The organization publishes magazine articles and zines, hosts events, and engages in other various projects. Although the website describes the organization as primarily focused on Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia, it frequently publishes works by Central Asian authors.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: NeMolchikz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.kz/&#34;&gt;#NeMolchikz&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots public fund dedicated to protection of victims of gender-based violence. The fund defines its activities along the three components, including legal protection, promotion of awareness, and legislative.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Artyq Emes</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artyqemes&#34;&gt;Artyq Emes&lt;/a&gt; is a human rights project that researches fat phobia and fat-shaming in Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram and YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Crisis Centers Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telefon150.kz/&#34;&gt;Crisis Centers Union&lt;/a&gt; unites 18 organizations from 12 regions of Kazakhstan. The Union is aimed at prevention and eradication of all forms of gender-based violence, formation of a non-violent culture in Kazakhstani society. The website offers news articles, photo and video materials, informational materials, webinars, and infographics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Fading.TSE</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/fading.tse/&#34;&gt;Fading.TSE&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project documenting urban history of Kazakhstan and its capital. Primary focused on photography, oral histories, and cultural heritage. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram, Facebook, TikTok, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kaz Fem</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kazfem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kazfem/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/kaz_fem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots feminist organization dedicated to research and development of feminist theory in Kazakhstan. One of the leading organizations behind Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march. Available mostly in Russian with occasional material in Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kok.team</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kok.team/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kok.team/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017 and dissolved in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kok.team/&#34;&gt;Kok.team&lt;/a&gt; was a grassroots LGBT organization dedicated to providing information on the LGBT issues in Kazakh. Digital archive contains articles, podcasts and videos of Kazakhstani LGBT  community. Available in Kazakh and Russian with occasional translation to English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qara Magan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qara.magan/&#34;&gt;Qara Magan&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project is dedicated to visibility and storytelling of the LGBTQ+ community of Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Schitaetsya</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/schitaetsya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/schitaetsya/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://schitaetsya.kz/&#34;&gt;Schitaetsya&lt;/a&gt; is a collaborative project by the Kaz Fem feminist organization and other experts and organization to collect accurate information about domestic violence in Kazakhstan and provide informational resources for victims of domestic abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Women of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/women_of_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/women_of_kz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/womenofkz/&#34;&gt;Women of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is a first online museum of documenting the past and present of Kazakhstani women with a focus on historical research. Available in English, Kazakh, and Russian on Instagram, Twitter, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
