<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – narratives</title>
    <link>/data_type/narratives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in narratives on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/data_type/narratives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bashtan Bashta</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bashtan_bashta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bashtan_bashta/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@bashtanbashta/&#34;&gt;Bashtan Bashta&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bashtan_bashta/&#34;&gt;a social media project&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to raising civil consciousness in Kyrgyzstan. It also covers news and politics of other Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA&#43;)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mofa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/mofa/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/femmuseum/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA+)&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots media spotlighting feminist and queer artists from Central Asia. MoFA+ also shares art exhibits, events, and publications on feminist and queer art in Central Asia. It appears to be primarily based at the Kyrgyz National Museum of Fine Arts named after Gapar Aitiev and located in Bishkek.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Dope Soz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@DOPESOZ/&#34;&gt;Dope Soz&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series offering discussions and conversations about social, historical, political, and cultural events and discourses.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: FemAgora</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/femagora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/femagora/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://femagora.org/&#34;&gt;FemAgora&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to fostering transnational feminist solidarity in Central Asia. The organization is involved in organization of Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march and the issue of employment of transgender people. FemAgora hosts annual FemAgora Central Asian festival for those involved in feminist, gender-sensitive, and/or women-led work.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminist Translocalities</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminisms.co/&#34;&gt;Feminist Translocalities&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots transnational feminist organization aiming to bring together and support feminist and LGBTQ+ activists from Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia. The organization publishes magazine articles and zines, hosts events, and engages in other various projects. Although the website describes the organization as primarily focused on Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia, it frequently publishes works by Central Asian authors.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kaz Fem</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kazfem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kazfem/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/kaz_fem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots feminist organization dedicated to research and development of feminist theory in Kazakhstan. One of the leading organizations behind Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march. Available mostly in Russian with occasional material in Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kok.team</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kok.team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kok.team/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017 and dissolved in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kok.team/&#34;&gt;Kok.team&lt;/a&gt; was a grassroots LGBT organization dedicated to providing information on the LGBT issues in Kazakh. Digital archive contains articles, podcasts and videos of Kazakhstani LGBT  community. Available in Kazakh and Russian with occasional translation to English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Loyiha</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/loyiha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/loyiha/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@loyiha_project/&#34;&gt;Loyiha&lt;/a&gt; is a video podcast platform designed to &amp;ldquo;inspire and motivate women.&amp;rdquo; It platforms several women-centered podcast series that provide educational content on various career fields, from marketing to education, as well as information on such topics as misogyny, infertility, ecology, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qara Magan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qara.magan/&#34;&gt;Qara Magan&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project is dedicated to visibility and storytelling of the LGBTQ+ community of Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Queernyi squirt</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mira Ungarova and Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://podcast.kz/1657513218/info&#34;&gt;Queernyi Squirt&lt;/a&gt; is an 18+ podcast dedicated to inclusive LGBTQIA+ sex education in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: TEDxAbayStWomen</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;First held in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tedxabaystwomen/&#34;&gt;TEDxAbayStWomen&lt;/a&gt; is a noncommercial conference on gender equality usually held in Almaty, Kazakhstan. Next conference is expected to be held in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: The Fish that changed gender (Рыба, которая сменила пол)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fish/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://beacons.ai/rybaipol&#34;&gt;the Fish that changed gender&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast project in conversation with transgender people living in Kazakhstan. It brings forward stories and experiences of transpeople. The podcast also has a presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/rybaipol/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Tolk</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tolk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tolk/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@tolkkz/&#34;&gt;Tolk&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast studio and an audio-hub dedicated to researching contemporary Kazakhstani through interpersonal conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Womxn of Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/womxn_of_ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/womxn_of_ca/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/womxnofcentralasia/&#34;&gt;Womxn of Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; is a social media project sharing stories and success of Central Asian women in various professional fields. It also has a Spotify-based podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: NeMolchiKZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.kz/&#34;&gt;#NeMolchiKZ&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots public fund dedicated to protection of victims of gender-based violence. The fund defines its activities along the three components, including legal protection, promotion of awareness, and legislative.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Anhor</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/anhor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/anhor/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anhor.uz/&#34;&gt;Anhor&lt;/a&gt; is an independent media that positions itself as a platform for &amp;ldquo;analytics, investigations, and news.&amp;rdquo; The publication&amp;rsquo;s mission is to contribute to effective governing.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Art - Review</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/art_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/art_review/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artreviewuz/&#34;&gt;Art - Review&lt;/a&gt; is local media about art and culture in Uzbekistan. It has presence on Instagram, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/artreviewuz&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.facebook.com/artreview.uz&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ayt Community</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ayt_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ayt_community/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ayt_community/&#34;&gt;Ayt Community&lt;/a&gt; is a local media with a focus on feminism, legislature, and ethics. Ayt Community also organizes various events and advocates for an inclusive future for women.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bahor/Vesna</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bahor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bahor/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;facebook.com/people/Bahor-%D0%92%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BD%D0%B0/&#34;&gt;Bahor/Vesna&lt;/a&gt; is a self-organized group of cultural immigrant-workers from Russia, Belarus, and Ukraine who have migrated to Uzbekistan following the escalation of Russia&amp;rsquo;s invasion of Ukraine. The initiative covers educational and cultural events in Uzbekistan. Bahor/Vesna is described as a project born out of necessity to &amp;ldquo;find connections during the tragic events affecting millions of residents in Ukraine, Russia, and other countries.&amp;rdquo; The initiative mostly focuses on music and contemporary art, as well as cinematography, literature, and research. It has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bahorvesnaa/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/bahorvesna&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8YmBSTfITo0VZ9zZkG6ShQ&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Center for the Development of Contemporary Journalism in the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mjdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/mjdc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mjdc.uz/&#34;&gt;Center for the Development of Contemporary Journalism in the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is an nongovernmental and noncommercial media institution aimed at improving the quality of journalism in Uzbekistan through &amp;ldquo;identifying problem areas, education, creating quality content that meets the highest standards of truthfulness and objectivity.&amp;rdquo; The center offers trainings for journalists, bloggers, and mass communication professionals, as well as workshops for a wider audience on media literacy.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Exponaut</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/exponaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/exponaut/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/exponautz/&#34;&gt;Exponaut&lt;/a&gt; is an independent media geared toward a younger audience. It covers art and culture, as well as creating projects meant to spotlight women and LGBTQIA+ community of Uzbekistan. Exponaut also has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/exponautz/729&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kun.Uz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kun_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kun_uz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2012, Kun.Uz is an online publication platform with a wide presence across social media platforms. It offers coverage of news events in Uzbekistan and across the world. The publication works in cooperation with the state and public organizations operating on the territory of Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Manarifat</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/manarifat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/manarifat/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/manarifat/&#34;&gt;Manarifat&lt;/a&gt; is a social media initiative dedicated to matters of sexual and reproductive health of women. It offers educational content on often stigmatized topics related to sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Moc Creative Org</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/moc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/moc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.facebook.com/org.moc&#34;&gt;Moc Creative Org&lt;/a&gt; is a collective of creators, producers, artists, designers, musicians, and photographers. The initiative is focused on organization of events in Uzbekistan, including music festivals, educational and professional trainings, and art exhibits. It is present on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/moc__org/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/moc24&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qizlar</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qizlar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qizlar/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qizlarqizlarqizlar/&#34;&gt;Qizlar&lt;/a&gt; is an independent collective of women-creators from Uzbekistan. The collective&amp;rsquo;s mission is described as spotlighting projects and products created by women and non-binary people, as well as fostering safe and friendly space for minorities. Qizlar also works on projects with a decolonial agenda aimed at &amp;ldquo;understanding and working out identities as a product of complex post-colonial processes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Sarpa</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sarpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/sarpa/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sarpa.media&#34;&gt;Sarpa&lt;/a&gt; is independent Uzbek media with a focus on human rights, democracy, and gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Sening mening haqqimiz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sening_mening_haqqimiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/sening_mening_haqqimiz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/sening_mening_haqqimiz/&#34;&gt;Sening mening haqqimiz&lt;/a&gt; is a social media account advocating for women&amp;rsquo;s rights, education, and development in Uzbekistan. On its Instagram page, sening mening haqqimiz shares relevant resources and news. The initiative is particularly focused on issues of violence against women.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Uzbekistan Art and Culture Development Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/acdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/acdf/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.acdf.uz/&#34;&gt;The Art and Culture Development Foundation of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; fosters international cooperation
and promotes the culture of Uzbekistan on the international arena. Its mission is to create an &amp;ldquo;inclusive and accessible environment in the country&amp;rsquo;s cultural institutions, contribute to renovation of museums, and to develop cultural patronage and professional training for the arts and culture sector.&amp;rdquo; It appears to be a state-affiliated organization.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Uzbekistan with a Female Voice</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uzbekistan_with_a_female_voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/uzbekistan_with_a_female_voice/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/uzbekistanwithafemalevoice/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan with a Female Voice&lt;/a&gt; is a social media initiative that advocates for gender equality and women empowerment in Uzbekistan by spotlighting stories of Uzbek women and sharing relevant events and news. It has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Ozbekistonayollarkozibilan/&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.me/uzbekayol&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Hook Report</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/hook_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/hook_report/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hook.report/&#34;&gt;Hook Report&lt;/a&gt; is an independent Uzbek media offering coverage of political, economic, art, and cultural news in the country. According to its mission, Hook Report aims to bring quality news coverage using a less traditional and formal approach.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Adamdar/CA</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adamdar.ca/&#34;&gt;Adamdar/CA&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage and storytelling narratives from Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Uzbekistan, and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Artyq Emes</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artyqemes&#34;&gt;Artyq Emes&lt;/a&gt; is a human rights project that researches fat phobia and fat-shaming in Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram and YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Crisis Centers Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telefon150.kz/&#34;&gt;Crisis Centers Union&lt;/a&gt; unites 18 organizations from 12 regions of Kazakhstan. The Union is aimed at prevention and eradication of all forms of gender-based violence, formation of a non-violent culture in Kazakhstani society. The website offers news articles, photo and video materials, informational materials, webinars, and infographics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Fading.TSE</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/fading.tse/&#34;&gt;Fading.TSE&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project documenting urban history of Kazakhstan and its capital. Primary focused on photography, oral histories, and cultural heritage. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram, Facebook, TikTok, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Schitaetsya</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/schitaetsya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/schitaetsya/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://schitaetsya.kz/&#34;&gt;Schitaetsya&lt;/a&gt; is a collaborative project by the Kaz Fem feminist organization and other experts and organization to collect accurate information about domestic violence in Kazakhstan and provide informational resources for victims of domestic abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Women of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/women_of_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/women_of_kz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/womenofkz/&#34;&gt;Women of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is a first online museum of documenting the past and present of Kazakhstani women with a focus on historical research. Available in English, Kazakh, and Russian on Instagram, Twitter, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
