<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – education</title>
    <link>/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in education on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Antiuniversity of Feminism</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/antiuniversity_of_feminism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/antiuniversity_of_feminism/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/antiuniversity_of_feminism/&#34;&gt;Antiuniversity of Feminism&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project aimed at creating a safe space for women and people with all gender identities to learn about feminism and gender theory. Antiuniversity offers free online courses in Kyrgyz. The project was founded and created by Elvira Tilek.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qizlar Ovozi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qizlar_ovozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qizlar_ovozi/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qizlarovozi.uz/&#34;&gt;Qizlar Ovozi&lt;/a&gt; is a school aimed at motivating and helping girls and young women aged 14 to 30 years in their professional development. The school also intends to increase and strengthen women&amp;rsquo;s role in public life. Qizlar Ovozi was founded by Nilufar Kiyamova.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Bank</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_bank/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/&#34;&gt;World Bank Gender Data Portal&lt;/a&gt; covers &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/kyrgyz-republic/&#34;&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/mongolia/&#34;&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/tajikistan/&#34;&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/Turkmenistan/&#34;&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/uzbekistan/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;, and offers a breakdown of gender-related data in regards to adolescent fertility rates, education completion rates, literacy levels, labor force participation, vulnerable employment, unpaid domestic work, business and bank account ownership, internet usage, and parliament membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data sources annotation is available under all indicators. It includes development relevance, limitation and exceptions, and statistical concepts and methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datasets are available via CVS, API, and Databank formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wbl.worldbank.org/en/reports&#34;&gt;Women, Business, and the Law Reports&lt;/a&gt; Annual report measuring the laws and regulations that affect women’s economic opportunity in 190 economies, including Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports are available in English with executive summaries in French, Spanish, and Arabic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodology section is available on the website and is based on feedback of &amp;ldquo;more than 2,000 respondents&amp;rdquo; which includes local experts on family, labor, and criminal law, including lawyers, judges, academics, and civil society. It is unclear whether the questionnaires sent out to experts are in English, Russian, or Kazakh languages.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bureau of National Statistics / Gender</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.gov.kz/en&#34;&gt;Bureau of National Statistics / Gender&lt;/a&gt; is the official government resource representing a collection of gendered data on population, family, healthcare, education and communication, employment, human rights, and politics. The Bureau has received criticism of its data from a feminist organization &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CUmGoyNsJPu/&#34;&gt;Kaz Fem&lt;/a&gt;. Kaz Fem created &lt;a href=&#34;https://schitaetsya.kz/&#34;&gt;its own alternative platform&lt;/a&gt; about the domestic violence situation in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Gender Economics Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/gerc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/gerc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 with the assistance of the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.narxoz.kz/research/institutes/gerc&#34;&gt;Gender Economics Research Center (GERC)&lt;/a&gt; is a research center at Narxoz University, Almaty. GERC is dedicated to development and coordination of research on gender and economy. The center publishes research articles and reports on the topics of labor market, education, COVID-19 impact, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nghrdc.kz/&#34;&gt;New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a coalition of Kazakhstani human rights defenders including practicing experts in the field of international human rights law, human rights researchers, leaders, and members of NGOs. The Coalition is engaged in informational campaigns, educational training, and other public events organization.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oecd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oecd/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is not a member of the OECD and acts as its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;partner for the Eurasian region&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of available data on Kazakhstan found on the OECD portal, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/gender-policy-delivery-in-kazakhstan-9789264280359-en.htm&#34;&gt;2017 Gender Policy Delivery in Kazakhstan review&lt;/a&gt; is so far the only gender-related publication on Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The review contains policy assessment and recommendation. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Research Institute for Social and Gender Studies</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/research_institute_for_social_and_gender_studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/research_institute_for_social_and_gender_studies/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2000 on the basis of the Kazakh National Women’s Teacher Training University, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazmkpu.kz/en/ob-institute-sgi&#34;&gt;Research Institute for Social and Gender Studies&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to promoting gender and social equality through the implementation of multidisciplinary research projects and social initiatives. Research and publications are particularly focused on education and teaching in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Soros Kazakhstan Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1995 by the Open Society Institute, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soros.kz&#34;&gt;Soros Kazakhstan Foundation&lt;/a&gt; funds multiple scholarship programs, educational courses, and research and activist initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundation publishes research works of various organizations and authors produced with the foundation’s support and/or collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available primarily in Russian with translations into Kazakh and English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Economic Forum’s Global Gender Gap Report</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weforum.org/reports/global-gender-gap-report-2022&#34;&gt;World Economic Forum’s Global Gender Gap Report&lt;/a&gt; includes countries’ score cards summarizing key gendered data findings broken down into 11 categories: economic participation and opportunity, educational attainment, health and survival, political empowerment, general indicators, work participation and leadership, access to finance, civil and political freedom, family and care, education and skills, and health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available. User’s guide how to read the economy profiles &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weforum.org/reports/global-gender-gap-report-2022/in-full/user-s-guide-how-to-read-the-economy-profiles&#34;&gt;is provided&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
