<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – Tajikistan</title>
    <link>/countries/tajikistan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tajikistan on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/countries/tajikistan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ariadna</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ariadna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ariadna/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ariadna.media&#34;&gt;Ariadna&lt;/a&gt; is a Central Asia media dedicated to covering the art scene of the region using accessible language. It provides reviews, editorials, and audioguides.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA&#43;)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mofa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/mofa/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/femmuseum/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA+)&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots media spotlighting feminist and queer artists from Central Asia. MoFA+ also shares art exhibits, events, and publications on feminist and queer art in Central Asia. It appears to be primarily based at the Kyrgyz National Museum of Fine Arts named after Gapar Aitiev and located in Bishkek.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Crossroads Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/crossroads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/crossroads/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crossroads-ca.org/&#34;&gt;Crossroads Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; is a Bishkek-based non-profit research institute with an aim to &amp;ldquo;promote better understanding of political, economic and security affairs of Central Asia and its wider Eurasian neighborhood.&amp;rdquo; It publishes analytical commentary and research reports.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: European Sex Workers Rights Alliance</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eswra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eswra/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002 under the name of International Committee for Sex Workers in Europe (ICRSE), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eswalliance.org/&#34;&gt;European Sex Workers Rights Alliance&lt;/a&gt; is a sex worker-led network representing more than 100 organizations in 30 countries across Europe and Central Asia. One of its recent publication is &amp;ldquo;Sex work &amp;amp; racism: the impact of structural racism on racialized sex workers in Europe and Central Asia&amp;rdquo; report.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ILGA-Europe</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ilga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ilga/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ilga-europe.org/&#34;&gt;ILGA-Europe&lt;/a&gt; is an International NGO advocating for the protection of LGBTI people and uniting over 600 organizations from 54 countries across Europe and Central Asia. ILGA conducts its work through resourcing and connecting communities, driving political change, and amplifying voices. Its mission is to provide a solid foundation for activists and organizations. ILGA publishes reports on the protection of rights of LGBTI people in Central Asia, specifically related to violence and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Invisible Rainbow Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/invisible_rainbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/invisible_rainbow/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/invisible_rainbow_union/&#34;&gt;Invisible Rainbow Union&lt;/a&gt; is a social media community of queer ethnic minorities from Central Asia and Russia. The media focuses on preserving oral histories of the LGBTQIA+ community.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ruyo Journal</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ruyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ruyo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruyojournal.com&#34;&gt;Ruyo Journal&lt;/a&gt; is an artist-led digital media focused on critical discourse on art, film, and theory in Central Asia. Its goal is to &amp;ldquo;support the development of a flourishing cultural scene in Central Asia by providing a platform for thoughtful and engaging discussions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Unit </title>
      <link>/sources/sources/unit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/unit/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021 by n-ost, a Berlin-based media NGO, &lt;a href=&#34;https://unit.n-ost.org&#34;&gt;Unit&lt;/a&gt; is a crossborder community of journalists and activists from Central Asia, Eastern Europe, and South Caucasus who work on the LGBTQIA+ issues.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Womxn of Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/womxn_of_ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/womxn_of_ca/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/womxnofcentralasia/&#34;&gt;Womxn of Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; is a social media project sharing stories and success of Central Asian women in various professional fields. It also has a Spotify-based podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Artif</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/artif/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artif.ication/&#34;&gt;Artif&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform connecting artists, human rights defenders, and activists from Eastern Europe and Central Asia. The platform&amp;rsquo;s mission is to voice social problems using art accessible to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ECOM</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ecom/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecom.ngo/&#34;&gt;ECOM (Eurasian Coalition for Health, Rights, Gender and Sexual Diversity)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional NGO working the sphere of health of LGBTI communities in Eastern Europe and Central Asia. It is a membership association open to non-profit organizations and activists working in the field. ECOM publishes regular reports on violation of rights of the LGBTI people in various Central Asian countries, including Uzbekistan and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Trans*Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transcoalition.net/&#34;&gt;Trans*Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a platform for trans- and non-binary activists from the countries of the Caucasus, Central Asia and Eastern Europe. It advocates for uniting, solidarizing, strengthening the voice of the trans-activist community in our region through the development of a sustainable, effective, authoritative, and resourceful organization. Key areas of Trans&lt;em&gt;Coalition&amp;rsquo;s work include response to the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, depathologizing, sex work, and legislation. In Central Asia, Trans&lt;/em&gt;Coalition offers a hot line, a map of resources and aid, and information for trans sex workers.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Country Data Sheet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/&#34;&gt;UN Women Country Data Sheet&lt;/a&gt; offers country specific gender-related data across four main components: economic, social, political, and environmental. Data sheets are available for &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kyrgyzstan&#34;&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/mongolia&#34;&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/tajikistan&#34;&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/turkmenistan&#34;&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;,. Some of the economic data is missing, while environmental data does not include a gender-based breakdown. Gender-specific indicators have at least 50% of data missing across the 17 indicators listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection is &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/modules/custom/country_fact_sheet/pdf/MethodologicalNote.pdf&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Bank</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_bank/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/&#34;&gt;World Bank Gender Data Portal&lt;/a&gt; covers &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/kyrgyz-republic/&#34;&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/mongolia/&#34;&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/tajikistan/&#34;&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/Turkmenistan/&#34;&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/uzbekistan/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;, and offers a breakdown of gender-related data in regards to adolescent fertility rates, education completion rates, literacy levels, labor force participation, vulnerable employment, unpaid domestic work, business and bank account ownership, internet usage, and parliament membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data sources annotation is available under all indicators. It includes development relevance, limitation and exceptions, and statistical concepts and methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datasets are available via CVS, API, and Databank formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wbl.worldbank.org/en/reports&#34;&gt;Women, Business, and the Law Reports&lt;/a&gt; Annual report measuring the laws and regulations that affect women’s economic opportunity in 190 economies, including Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports are available in English with executive summaries in French, Spanish, and Arabic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodology section is available on the website and is based on feedback of &amp;ldquo;more than 2,000 respondents&amp;rdquo; which includes local experts on family, labor, and criminal law, including lawyers, judges, academics, and civil society. It is unclear whether the questionnaires sent out to experts are in English, Russian, or Kazakh languages.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
