<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – qualitative</title>
    <link>/data_type/qualitative/</link>
    <description>Recent content in qualitative on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/data_type/qualitative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: NeMolchikz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.kz/&#34;&gt;#NeMolchikz&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots public fund dedicated to protection of victims of gender-based violence. The fund defines its activities along the three components, including legal protection, promotion of awareness, and legislative.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Artyq Emes</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artyqemes&#34;&gt;Artyq Emes&lt;/a&gt; is a human rights project that researches fat phobia and fat-shaming in Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram and YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Crisis Centers Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telefon150.kz/&#34;&gt;Crisis Centers Union&lt;/a&gt; unites 18 organizations from 12 regions of Kazakhstan. The Union is aimed at prevention and eradication of all forms of gender-based violence, formation of a non-violent culture in Kazakhstani society. The website offers news articles, photo and video materials, informational materials, webinars, and infographics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Eurasian Cultural Alliance</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasian_cultural_alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasian_cultural_alliance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2011, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.cultura.kz/&#34;&gt;Eurasian Cultural Alliance&lt;/a&gt; is a NGO dedicated to cultivating the contemporary art scene of Kazakhstan. The mission of the Alliance is to stimulate the creative economy, improve social and economic standing of the region&amp;rsquo;s key cultural players, and advance the integration of the Kazakhstani identity into a larger global context.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Fading.TSE</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/fading.tse/&#34;&gt;Fading.TSE&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project documenting urban history of Kazakhstan and its capital. Primary focused on photography, oral histories, and cultural heritage. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram, Facebook, TikTok, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: FemAgora</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/femagora/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/femagora/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://femagora.org/&#34;&gt;FemAgora&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to fostering transnational feminist solidarity in Central Asia. The organization is involved in organization of Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march and the issue of employment of transgender people. FemAgora hosts annual FemAgora Central Asian festival for those involved in feminist, gender-sensitive, and/or women-led work.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminita</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminita/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminita/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminita.kz/&#34;&gt;Feminita&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots queer feminist collective. Feminita aims to create and strengthen the rights of women and activist communities and empower the most oppressed groups of Kazakhstani population (lesbian, bisexual, queer, women with disabilities, women in sex work). Currently, the organization works on three research projects: assessment of needs of LBQ women; health conditions of LBQT women and transgender men; and sexual wellness of LBQ women. Methodology and research design sections are included in the first two project reports. The reports are available in Russian with occasional translation to Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Friedrich Ebert Stiftung</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1925 in Germany with a Kazakhstani office opened in 1993, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.fes.de/&#34;&gt;Friedrich Ebert Stiftung&lt;/a&gt; is a foundation funded by the German government. The INGO focuses on social and gender justice issues, as well as political participation and youth leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications on Kazakhstan include population surveys, particularly focused on youth, and are available in English, Kazakh, and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published surveys include &amp;ldquo;Youth and Education,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Values,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Social Justice.&amp;rdquo; Gendered breakdown of data is included for some survey questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://library.fes.de/pdf-files/bueros/kasachstan/18450.pdf&#34;&gt;Youth in Kazakhstan 2021 survey&lt;/a&gt; has five main section, including (1) values and orientations, (2) life plans, education, employment, and immigration, (3) youth and politics, and (4) foreign policy and attitudes toward Central Asia. The values and orientation section incorporates questions on attitudes toward abortion, homosexuality, different sexual practices, and other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey uses mixed method approach and includes a methodology chapter.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kaz Fem</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kazfem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kazfem/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/kaz_fem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots feminist organization dedicated to research and development of feminist theory in Kazakhstan. One of the leading organizations behind Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march. Available mostly in Russian with occasional material in Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kok.team</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kok.team/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kok.team/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017 and dissolved in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kok.team/&#34;&gt;Kok.team&lt;/a&gt; was a grassroots LGBT organization dedicated to providing information on the LGBT issues in Kazakh. Digital archive contains articles, podcasts and videos of Kazakhstani LGBT  community. Available in Kazakh and Russian with occasional translation to English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nghrdc.kz/&#34;&gt;New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a coalition of Kazakhstani human rights defenders including practicing experts in the field of international human rights law, human rights researchers, leaders, and members of NGOs. The Coalition is engaged in informational campaigns, educational training, and other public events organization.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Oyan, Qazaqstan!</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/oyanqazaqstankz/&#34;&gt;Oyan, Qazaqstan!&lt;/a&gt; is a social movement advocating for political reforms in Kazakhstan. The organization shares news about political events, activist campaigns, organizing efforts, as well as prosecution of activists by the state authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: PaperLab</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/paperlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/paperlab/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015 and supported by the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://paperlab.kz/&#34;&gt;PaperLab&lt;/a&gt; is a public policy research organization in Kazakhstan. PaperLab publishes research, organizes public discussions, and offers training and networking opportunities to Central Asian experts. Most publications are in Kazakh and Russian and sometimes in English. PaperLab has done extensive research on sex education in Kazakhstan and frequently collaborates with other NGOs and INGOs on the topic of violence against women. Methodology note and description of sources are not always included in the publications.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Policy Solutions Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://policysolutions.kz/&#34;&gt;Policy Solutions Center&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots organizations of Kazakhstani researchers involved in the study of socio-political and socio-economic problems in Kazakhstan, as well as the development of policy and management recommendations. The Center publishes analytical pieces and develops projects on political, economic, and social issues.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qara Magan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qara.magan/&#34;&gt;Qara Magan&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project is dedicated to visibility and storytelling of the LGBTQ+ community of Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Research Institute for Social and Gender Studies</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/research_institute_for_social_and_gender_studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/research_institute_for_social_and_gender_studies/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2000 on the basis of the Kazakh National Women’s Teacher Training University, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazmkpu.kz/en/ob-institute-sgi&#34;&gt;Research Institute for Social and Gender Studies&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to promoting gender and social equality through the implementation of multidisciplinary research projects and social initiatives. Research and publications are particularly focused on education and teaching in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Schitaetsya</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/schitaetsya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/schitaetsya/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://schitaetsya.kz/&#34;&gt;Schitaetsya&lt;/a&gt; is a collaborative project by the Kaz Fem feminist organization and other experts and organization to collect accurate information about domestic violence in Kazakhstan and provide informational resources for victims of domestic abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Soros Kazakhstan Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1995 by the Open Society Institute, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soros.kz&#34;&gt;Soros Kazakhstan Foundation&lt;/a&gt; funds multiple scholarship programs, educational courses, and research and activist initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundation publishes research works of various organizations and authors produced with the foundation’s support and/or collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available primarily in Russian with translations into Kazakh and English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/central-asia&#34;&gt;Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt; is a research and advocacy campaign dedicated to eliminating sexual and gender-based violence and harmful practices in Central Asia. The program involves UN Women, UNDP, and UNFPA with funding from the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan 2020 report is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/publications/spotlight-initiative-central-asia-and-afghanistan-programme-report-2020&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt; in English. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/projects/spotlight-initiative-regional-programme-central-asia-and-afghanistan&#34;&gt;UNDP project page for the Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oxus_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oxus_society/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oxussociety.org/&#34;&gt;The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs&lt;/a&gt; is a Washington, DC-based NGO aimed at fostering academic exchange between Central Asia and the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Oxus Society publishes datasets on articles and books on Central Asia, as well as a directory of researchers studying Central Asia. The NGO also publishes reports on various topic, particularly pertaining to international relations, religion, and domestic politics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Tselinny Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tselinny_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tselinny_center/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 by Kairat Boranbayev, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tselinny.org/&#34;&gt;Tselinny Center&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to studying and developing cultural scene in Kazakhstan. The center publishes educational books, hosts art exhibitions, and organizes events.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Kazakhstan Annual Report 2021</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_kazakhstan_annual_report_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_kazakhstan_annual_report_2021/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Pages 24-27 of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.un.org/en/176526-un-kazakhstan-annual-report-2021&#34;&gt;UN Kazakhstan Annual Report 2021&lt;/a&gt; summarize the UN’s efforts in fostering gender equality and human rights development in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Population Fund in Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_population_fund_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_population_fund_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unfpa.org&#34;&gt;UN Population Fund&lt;/a&gt; produces country-specific landing pages. The work of the Fund includes data on sexual and reproductive health, gender equality, young people, and population matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unfpa.org/data/world-population/KZ&#34;&gt;Data Portal for Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; gender-related data across six main components: population, sexual and reproductive health, family planning, education, gender, rights, and human capital, and harmful practices.   Their semi-regularly published &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.unfpa.org/en/publications&#34;&gt;reports and surveys&lt;/a&gt; address these topics. Survey publcations contain a methodology section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unfpa.org/data/transparency-portal/unfpa-kazakhstan&#34;&gt;Transparency portal&lt;/a&gt; that details expenses and program activities of the Population Fund in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Country Data Sheet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UN Women Country Data Sheet&lt;/a&gt; offers country specific gender-related data across four main components: economic, social, political, and environmental. Some of the economic data is missing, while environmental data does not include a gender-based breakdown. Gender-specific indicators have at least 50% of data missing across the 17 indicators listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection is &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/modules/custom/country_fact_sheet/pdf/MethodologicalNote.pdf&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Data Hub</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_data_hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_data_hub/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Publications on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/publications&#34;&gt;UN Women Data Hub&lt;/a&gt; have an option to filter by region.
Eurasia and Central Asia region primarily focuses on Eastern European and Balkan countries with occasional inclusion of Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themes of publications include data use, disabilities, economic empowerment, ending violence against women, environment, gender and COVID-19, HIV and AIDS, migration, sustainable development, and peace and security.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women: Europe and Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_europe_and_central_asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_europe_and_central_asia/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://eca.unwomen.org/en/where-we-are/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UN Women: Europe and Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; provides an overview of the UN initiatives in Kazakhstan, including a list of major international treaties ratified by the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overview includes four main themes: women’s economic empowerment, ending violence against women, national planning and budgeting, and sustainable development agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UNDP in Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/undp_in_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/undp_in_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UNDP in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; page includes a section on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/gender-equality-0&#34;&gt;gender equality&lt;/a&gt; that focuses on causes of gender inequality in Kazakhstan in the context of the Sustainable Development Goals. The website provides a brief overview of the UNDP gender equality agenda in Kazakhstan and key general statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications/gender-profile-sustainable-development-goals-kazakhstan&#34;&gt;2019 Gender Profile of Sustainable Development Goals in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is available only Russian. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications about Kazakhstan are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications&#34;&gt;available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications/girls-and-education&#34;&gt;Girls and Education infographic about Afghan women receiving their education in Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan.&lt;/a&gt; Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hdr.undp.org/reports-and-publications&#34;&gt;Human Development Reports&lt;/a&gt; are available in English and Russian with methodological update note and sources list included in the report and data and statistics readers guide &lt;a href=&#34;https://hdr.undp.org/reports-and-publications/2020-human-development-report/data-readers-guide&#34;&gt;available separately&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Uyat Emes</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uyat_emes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/uyat_emes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uyatemes.kz/&#34;&gt;Uyat Emes&lt;/a&gt; is an educational site about sex and relationships for Kazakhstani teenagers and their parents. The mission of the initiative is to help young people become more literate about reproductive health and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Women of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/women_of_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/women_of_kz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/womenofkz/&#34;&gt;Women of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is a first online museum of documenting the past and present of Kazakhstani women with a focus on historical research. Available in English, Kazakh, and Russian on Instagram, Twitter, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Bank</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_bank/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;World Bank Gender Data Portal&lt;/a&gt; offers a breakdown of gender-related data in regards to adolescent fertility rates, education completion rates, literacy levels, labor force participation, vulnerable employment, unpaid domestic work, business and bank account ownership, internet usage, and parliament membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data sources annotation is available under all indicators. It includes development relevance, limitation and exceptions, and statistical concepts and methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datasets are available via CVS, API, and Databank formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wbl.worldbank.org/en/reports&#34;&gt;Women, Business, and the Law Reports&lt;/a&gt; Annual report measuring the laws and regulations that affect women’s economic opportunity in 190 economies, including Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports are available in English with executive summaries in French, Spanish, and Arabic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodology section is available on the website and is based on feedback of &amp;ldquo;more than 2,000 respondents&amp;rdquo; which includes local experts on family, labor, and criminal law, including lawyers, judges, academics, and civil society. It is unclear whether the questionnaires sent out to experts are in English, Russian, or Kazakh languages.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
