<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – reports</title>
    <link>/data_type/reports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reports on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/data_type/reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Eurasia Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2004 and based in Washington, DC, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/where-we-work/asia/&#34;&gt;Eurasia Foundation&lt;/a&gt; works with international, national, and local partners for community action. The foundation has a variety of international and local donors. Areas of expertise include civil society, youth and leadership, media, governance, and [gender and marginalized communities] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&#34;&gt;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: OCCRP</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/occrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/occrp/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005 in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.occrp.org/&#34;&gt;Organized Crime and Corruption Reporting Project&lt;/a&gt; aims to develop and equip a global network of investigative journalists, as well as publish stories exposing crime and corruption. The project regularly covers post-Soviet and Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Prague Civil Society Centre</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2014 and based in Prague, the Czech Republic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.praguecivilsociety.org/&#34;&gt;Prague Civil Society Centre&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to enabling civic groups and journalists to connect with their communities through grant making, capacity building, and learning. The Centre is funded by governments of Sweden, the Czech Republic, the UK, and the US, as well as the European Commission, the Oak Foundation, and the Wellspring Philanthropic Fund. Focuses on Eastern Europe and Central Asia. In addition to civil society programs, the Centre publishes media and publications on various topics related to the civic groups in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Data Hub</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_data_hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_data_hub/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Publications on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/publications&#34;&gt;UN Women Data Hub&lt;/a&gt; have an option to filter by region.
Eurasia and Central Asia region primarily focuses on Eastern European and Balkan countries with occasional inclusion of Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themes of publications include data use, disabilities, economic empowerment, ending violence against women, environment, gender and COVID-19, HIV and AIDS, migration, sustainable development, and peace and security.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminita</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminita/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminita/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminita.kz/&#34;&gt;Feminita&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots queer feminist collective. Feminita aims to create and strengthen the rights of women and activist communities and empower the most oppressed groups of Kazakhstani population (lesbian, bisexual, queer, women with disabilities, women in sex work). Currently, the organization works on three research projects: assessment of needs of LBQ women; health conditions of LBQT women and transgender men; and sexual wellness of LBQ women. Methodology and research design sections are included in the first two project reports. The reports are available in Russian with occasional translation to Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Gender Economics Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/gerc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/gerc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 with the assistance of the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.narxoz.kz/research/institutes/gerc&#34;&gt;Gender Economics Research Center (GERC)&lt;/a&gt; is a research center at Narxoz University, Almaty. GERC is dedicated to development and coordination of research on gender and economy. The center publishes research articles and reports on the topics of labor market, education, COVID-19 impact, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: PaperLab</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/paperlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/paperlab/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015 and supported by the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://paperlab.kz/&#34;&gt;PaperLab&lt;/a&gt; is a public policy research organization in Kazakhstan. PaperLab publishes research, organizes public discussions, and offers training and networking opportunities to Central Asian experts. Most publications are in Kazakh and Russian and sometimes in English. PaperLab has done extensive research on sex education in Kazakhstan and frequently collaborates with other NGOs and INGOs on the topic of violence against women. Methodology note and description of sources are not always included in the publications.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: </title>
      <link>/sources/sources/public_opinion_research_institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/public_opinion_research_institute/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opinions.kz/&#34;&gt;Public Opinion Research Institute&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani sociological institute specializes in public opinion, marketing, and sociological studies of Kazakhstan and other countries. The institute publishes research reports on various topics, including COVID-19, migration, social values, etc. Most publications are available in Kazakh and Russian with occasional translation to English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Research Institute for Social and Gender Studies</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/research_institute_for_social_and_gender_studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/research_institute_for_social_and_gender_studies/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2000 on the basis of the Kazakh National Women’s Teacher Training University, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazmkpu.kz/en/ob-institute-sgi&#34;&gt;Research Institute for Social and Gender Studies&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to promoting gender and social equality through the implementation of multidisciplinary research projects and social initiatives. Research and publications are particularly focused on education and teaching in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Kazakhstan Annual Report 2021</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_kazakhstan_annual_report_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_kazakhstan_annual_report_2021/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Pages 24-27 of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.un.org/en/176526-un-kazakhstan-annual-report-2021&#34;&gt;UN Kazakhstan Annual Report 2021&lt;/a&gt; summarize the UN’s efforts in fostering gender equality and human rights development in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UNDP in Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/undp_in_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/undp_in_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UNDP in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; page includes a section on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/gender-equality-0&#34;&gt;gender equality&lt;/a&gt; that focuses on causes of gender inequality in Kazakhstan in the context of the Sustainable Development Goals. The website provides a brief overview of the UNDP gender equality agenda in Kazakhstan and key general statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications/gender-profile-sustainable-development-goals-kazakhstan&#34;&gt;2019 Gender Profile of Sustainable Development Goals in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is available only Russian. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications about Kazakhstan are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications&#34;&gt;available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications/girls-and-education&#34;&gt;Girls and Education infographic about Afghan women receiving their education in Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan.&lt;/a&gt; Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hdr.undp.org/reports-and-publications&#34;&gt;Human Development Reports&lt;/a&gt; are available in English and Russian with methodological update note and sources list included in the report and data and statistics readers guide &lt;a href=&#34;https://hdr.undp.org/reports-and-publications/2020-human-development-report/data-readers-guide&#34;&gt;available separately&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
