<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – INGO</title>
    <link>/category/ingo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in INGO on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/category/ingo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Eurasia Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2004 and based in Washington, DC, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/where-we-work/asia/&#34;&gt;Eurasia Foundation&lt;/a&gt; works with international, national, and local partners for community action. The foundation has a variety of international and local donors. Areas of expertise include civil society, youth and leadership, media, governance, and [gender and marginalized communities] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&#34;&gt;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminist Translocalities</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminisms.co/&#34;&gt;Feminist Translocalities&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots transnational feminist organization aiming to bring together and support feminist and LGBTQ+ activists from Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia. The organization publishes magazine articles and zines, hosts events, and engages in other various projects. Although the website describes the organization as primarily focused on Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia, it frequently publishes works by Central Asian authors.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Foreign Policy Research Institute</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/foreign_policy_research_institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/foreign_policy_research_institute/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002, based in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fpri.org/central-asia-initiative/&#34;&gt;Foreign Policy Research Institute&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to producing research and policy analysis with the focus on foreign policy and national security challenges facing the US. Its Central Asia Initiative produces analyses of trends in the region concerning the US national security.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Friedrich Ebert Stiftung</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1925 in Germany with a Kazakhstani office opened in 1993, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.fes.de/&#34;&gt;Friedrich Ebert Stiftung&lt;/a&gt; is a foundation funded by the German government. The INGO focuses on social and gender justice issues, as well as political participation and youth leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications on Kazakhstan include population surveys, particularly focused on youth, and are available in English, Kazakh, and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published surveys include &amp;ldquo;Youth and Education,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Values,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Social Justice.&amp;rdquo; Gendered breakdown of data is included for some survey questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://library.fes.de/pdf-files/bueros/kasachstan/18450.pdf&#34;&gt;Youth in Kazakhstan 2021 survey&lt;/a&gt; has five main section, including (1) values and orientations, (2) life plans, education, employment, and immigration, (3) youth and politics, and (4) foreign policy and attitudes toward Central Asia. The values and orientation section incorporates questions on attitudes toward abortion, homosexuality, different sexual practices, and other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey uses mixed method approach and includes a methodology chapter.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: International Organization for Migration</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/iom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/iom/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.iom.int/&#34;&gt;International Organization for Migration&lt;/a&gt; publishes &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.iom.int/data-and-resources&#34;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; on migration issues in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is usually presented in gendered format splitting respondents between male and female. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available. Reports are available in English, Kazakh, and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: OCCRP</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/occrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/occrp/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005 in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.occrp.org/&#34;&gt;Organized Crime and Corruption Reporting Project&lt;/a&gt; aims to develop and equip a global network of investigative journalists, as well as publish stories exposing crime and corruption. The project regularly covers post-Soviet and Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oecd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oecd/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is not a member of the OECD and acts as its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;partner for the Eurasian region&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of available data on Kazakhstan found on the OECD portal, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/gender-policy-delivery-in-kazakhstan-9789264280359-en.htm&#34;&gt;2017 Gender Policy Delivery in Kazakhstan review&lt;/a&gt; is so far the only gender-related publication on Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The review contains policy assessment and recommendation. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Prague Civil Society Centre</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2014 and based in Prague, the Czech Republic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.praguecivilsociety.org/&#34;&gt;Prague Civil Society Centre&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to enabling civic groups and journalists to connect with their communities through grant making, capacity building, and learning. The Centre is funded by governments of Sweden, the Czech Republic, the UK, and the US, as well as the European Commission, the Oak Foundation, and the Wellspring Philanthropic Fund. Focuses on Eastern Europe and Central Asia. In addition to civil society programs, the Centre publishes media and publications on various topics related to the civic groups in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Soros Kazakhstan Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1995 by the Open Society Institute, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soros.kz&#34;&gt;Soros Kazakhstan Foundation&lt;/a&gt; funds multiple scholarship programs, educational courses, and research and activist initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundation publishes research works of various organizations and authors produced with the foundation’s support and/or collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available primarily in Russian with translations into Kazakh and English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/central-asia&#34;&gt;Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt; is a research and advocacy campaign dedicated to eliminating sexual and gender-based violence and harmful practices in Central Asia. The program involves UN Women, UNDP, and UNFPA with funding from the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan 2020 report is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/publications/spotlight-initiative-central-asia-and-afghanistan-programme-report-2020&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt; in English. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/projects/spotlight-initiative-regional-programme-central-asia-and-afghanistan&#34;&gt;UNDP project page for the Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Kazakhstan Annual Report 2021</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_kazakhstan_annual_report_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_kazakhstan_annual_report_2021/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Pages 24-27 of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.un.org/en/176526-un-kazakhstan-annual-report-2021&#34;&gt;UN Kazakhstan Annual Report 2021&lt;/a&gt; summarize the UN’s efforts in fostering gender equality and human rights development in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Population Fund in Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_population_fund_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_population_fund_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unfpa.org&#34;&gt;UN Population Fund&lt;/a&gt; produces country-specific landing pages. The work of the Fund includes data on sexual and reproductive health, gender equality, young people, and population matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unfpa.org/data/world-population/KZ&#34;&gt;Data Portal for Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; gender-related data across six main components: population, sexual and reproductive health, family planning, education, gender, rights, and human capital, and harmful practices.   Their semi-regularly published &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.unfpa.org/en/publications&#34;&gt;reports and surveys&lt;/a&gt; address these topics. Survey publcations contain a methodology section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unfpa.org/data/transparency-portal/unfpa-kazakhstan&#34;&gt;Transparency portal&lt;/a&gt; that details expenses and program activities of the Population Fund in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Country Data Sheet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UN Women Country Data Sheet&lt;/a&gt; offers country specific gender-related data across four main components: economic, social, political, and environmental. Some of the economic data is missing, while environmental data does not include a gender-based breakdown. Gender-specific indicators have at least 50% of data missing across the 17 indicators listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection is &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/modules/custom/country_fact_sheet/pdf/MethodologicalNote.pdf&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Data Hub</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_data_hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_data_hub/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Publications on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/publications&#34;&gt;UN Women Data Hub&lt;/a&gt; have an option to filter by region.
Eurasia and Central Asia region primarily focuses on Eastern European and Balkan countries with occasional inclusion of Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themes of publications include data use, disabilities, economic empowerment, ending violence against women, environment, gender and COVID-19, HIV and AIDS, migration, sustainable development, and peace and security.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women: Europe and Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_europe_and_central_asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_europe_and_central_asia/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://eca.unwomen.org/en/where-we-are/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UN Women: Europe and Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; provides an overview of the UN initiatives in Kazakhstan, including a list of major international treaties ratified by the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overview includes four main themes: women’s economic empowerment, ending violence against women, national planning and budgeting, and sustainable development agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UNDP in Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/undp_in_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/undp_in_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UNDP in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; page includes a section on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/gender-equality-0&#34;&gt;gender equality&lt;/a&gt; that focuses on causes of gender inequality in Kazakhstan in the context of the Sustainable Development Goals. The website provides a brief overview of the UNDP gender equality agenda in Kazakhstan and key general statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications/gender-profile-sustainable-development-goals-kazakhstan&#34;&gt;2019 Gender Profile of Sustainable Development Goals in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is available only Russian. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications about Kazakhstan are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications&#34;&gt;available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications/girls-and-education&#34;&gt;Girls and Education infographic about Afghan women receiving their education in Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan.&lt;/a&gt; Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hdr.undp.org/reports-and-publications&#34;&gt;Human Development Reports&lt;/a&gt; are available in English and Russian with methodological update note and sources list included in the report and data and statistics readers guide &lt;a href=&#34;https://hdr.undp.org/reports-and-publications/2020-human-development-report/data-readers-guide&#34;&gt;available separately&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Value Survey</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_value_survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_value_survey/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSOnline.jsp&#34;&gt;World Value Survey&lt;/a&gt; studies social, political, economic, religious and cultural values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is included in waves 6 (2010-2014) and 7 (2017-2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some relevant questions include questions about women’s leadership skills, women’s rights, familial fiscal responsibilities, acceptance of homosexuality, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sample size is 1,500 and 1,276 in waves 6 and 7 respectively. A lot of questions are missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Economic Forum’s Global Gender Gap Report</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weforum.org/reports/global-gender-gap-report-2022&#34;&gt;World Economic Forum’s Global Gender Gap Report&lt;/a&gt; includes countries’ score cards summarizing key gendered data findings broken down into 11 categories: economic participation and opportunity, educational attainment, health and survival, political empowerment, general indicators, work participation and leadership, access to finance, civil and political freedom, family and care, education and skills, and health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available. User’s guide how to read the economy profiles &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weforum.org/reports/global-gender-gap-report-2022/in-full/user-s-guide-how-to-read-the-economy-profiles&#34;&gt;is provided&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
