<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – CAMGDP sources</title>
    <link>/sources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CAMGDP sources on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/sources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Generations and Gender Survey - Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/generations_and_gender_survey_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/generations_and_gender_survey_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ggp.colectica.org/item/int.ggp/009e728f-77f1-4c45-88be-e3bc1acb5bfa/1&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan data&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ggp-i.org/&#34;&gt;Generations and Gender Survey&lt;/a&gt; for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data covers the non-institutionalized, resident population aged 18-79 in Kazakhstan on 2nd April 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Generations and Gender Survey (GGS) data provides micro-level data that can be used to investigate partnership dynamics, transition to adulthood, fertility, care and support networks, division of household tasks, and contraception, among other topics. These data are an essential resource in the understanding of fundamental societal challenges across Europe and beyond and form a substantial basis for the formulation of evidence-based policies. Key features of the survey are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cross-national comparability: The comparative focus allows analyses of the ways in which policies, culture and economic circumstances influence dependencies between men and women and between the young and the old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A longitudinal design: The GGP survey applies a panel design - collecting information on the same persons at three-year intervals - to allow the examination of causes and consequences of inequalities between genders and generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large sample size: The GGP survey has an average of 10,000 respondents per country, making it possible to study numerical minorities and uncommon events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A broad age range: The GGP collects data on the whole life course by interviewing respondents aged 18-79. It also enables analysis of multiple generations by asking extensive questions about intergenerational exchange and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combination of micro and macro data: Alongside the micro data collected via surveys, the GGP has a contextual database with over 100 indicators which cover not only the year of the survey but also retrospective indicators covering the past 40 years to be used alongside the retrospective data in the surveys. A theory-driven and multidisciplinary questionnaire: The GGS questionnaire is developed and maintained by a team of leading social scientists from demography, sociology and economics. The questionnaire seeks to bring together a wide range of subjects that examine the causes and consequences of family change.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Living Standards Measurement Study (LSMS) - World Bank - Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/living_standards_measurement_survey_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/living_standards_measurement_survey_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbank.org/en/programs/lsms&#34;&gt;Living Standards Measurement Study (LSMS)&lt;/a&gt; is the World Bank&amp;rsquo;s flagship household survey program focused on strengthening household survey systems in client countries and on improving the quality of microdata to better inform development policies. The LSMS is housed in the Data Production and Methods Unit of the World Bank’s Development Data Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://microdata.worldbank.org/index.php/catalog/2292&#34;&gt;Data on Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is available for 1996.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of the study includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;household roster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;housing conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;durable goods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;agriculture and livestock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consumption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;food purchases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;home production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;expenditures in last 12 months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caring for children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;occupation, employment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time budget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;health, medical care, women&amp;rsquo;s health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anthropometrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Living Standards Measurement Study (LSMS) - World Bank - Kyrgyzstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/living_standards_measurement_survey_kyrgyzstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/living_standards_measurement_survey_kyrgyzstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbank.org/en/programs/lsms&#34;&gt;Living Standards Measurement Study (LSMS)&lt;/a&gt; is the World Bank&amp;rsquo;s flagship household survey program focused on strengthening household survey systems in client countries and on improving the quality of microdata to better inform development policies. The LSMS is housed in the Data Production and Methods Unit of the World Bank’s Development Data Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://microdata.worldbank.org/index.php/catalog/lsms/?page=1&amp;amp;country%5B%5D=118&amp;amp;ps=15&amp;amp;repo=lsms&#34;&gt;Data on Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt; is available from 1993 to 1998 through the &lt;strong&gt;Poverty Monitoring Survey&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of the study includes household and family, jobs and employment, education, health, and other variables.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Living Standards Measurement Study (LSMS) - World Bank - Tajikistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/living_standards_measurement_survey_tajikistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/living_standards_measurement_survey_tajikistan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbank.org/en/programs/lsms&#34;&gt;Living Standards Measurement Study (LSMS)&lt;/a&gt; is the World Bank&amp;rsquo;s flagship household survey program focused on strengthening household survey systems in client countries and on improving the quality of microdata to better inform development policies. The LSMS is housed in the Data Production and Methods Unit of the World Bank’s Development Data Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://microdata.worldbank.org/index.php/catalog/lsms/?page=1&amp;amp;country%5B%5D=210&amp;amp;ps=15&amp;amp;repo=lsms&#34;&gt;Data on Tajikistan&lt;/a&gt; is available from 1999 to 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of the study includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal Migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International Migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Family Members Living Away from the Household&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preschool Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education (6 years and older)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilization of Outpatient Health Care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hospitalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to Health Care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Labor Force Participation in Labor Market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview Last 14 Days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Main and Secondary Jobs in the Last 14 Days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activities over the Last 24 Months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water and Sanitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Durable Goods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transfers from Another Household&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tansfers to Another Household&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Assistance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subjective Poverty and Food Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coping Strategies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expenditure on Food in the Last Seven Days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nonfood Purchases Past 30 Days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nonfood Purchases Past 6 Months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nonfood Purchases Past 12 Months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Household and Population Weights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Loyiha</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/loyiha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/loyiha/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@loyiha_project/&#34;&gt;Loyiha&lt;/a&gt; is a video podcast platform designed to &amp;ldquo;inspire and motivate women.&amp;rdquo; It platforms several women-centered podcast series that provide educational content on various career fields, from marketing to education, as well as information on such topics as misogyny, infertility, ecology, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Values Survey (KZ)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_values_survey_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_values_survey_kz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSOnline.jsp&#34;&gt;World Values Survey&lt;/a&gt; studies social, political, economic, religious and cultural values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is included in waves 6 (2010-2014) and 7 (2017-2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some relevant questions include questions about women’s leadership skills, women’s rights, familial fiscal responsibilities, acceptance of homosexuality, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sample size is 1,500 and 1,276 in waves 6 and 7 respectively. A lot of questions are missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Values Survey (UZ)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_values_survey_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_values_survey_uz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSOnline.jsp&#34;&gt;World Values Survey&lt;/a&gt; studies social, political, economic, religious and cultural values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some relevant questions include questions about women&amp;rsquo;s leadership skills, women&amp;rsquo;s rights, familial fiscal responsibilities, acceptance of homosexuality, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uzbekistan is included in wave 6 (2010-2014). Sample size for Uzbekistan is 1487.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Akimat of the city of Astana</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/astana/about?lang=en&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Astana&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the akimat (regional administration) of the capital city Astana. Contains official documents, press releases, and statistical data of the city. Offers latest news about the capital’s governance. The information is divided into several directions, including familial and demographic policies, culture, civil society, youth, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Family and Women&#39;s Committee of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/family_and_womens_committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/family_and_womens_committee/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wcu.uz/ru/&#34;&gt;Family and Women&amp;rsquo;s Committee of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is a state institution aimed at protecting women&amp;rsquo;s civil, labor, and human rights. It publishes reports and shares other updates on issues of women and family in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Institute of Oriental Studies of the Academy of Sciences</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/institute_of_oriental_studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/institute_of_oriental_studies/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1943, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://beruni.uz/ru/glavnaya/struktura-instituta/item/329-o/&#39;92zr-fa.html&#34;&gt;Institute of Oriental Studies of the Academy of Sciences&lt;/a&gt; is a Tashkent-based research institution that specializes on collection of manuscripts. At the present time, its manuscript collection contains about 26,000 volumes and includes works written in Uzbek, Arabic, Persian, Tajik, Urdu, Azeri, Ottoman Turkish, Tatar, Turkmen, Uighur and other languages.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: National Archive of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kz_national_archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kz_national_archive/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Opened in 2006, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ulttykarhiv.kz/en/&#34;&gt;National Archive of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is a central repository for historical documents in Kazakhstan. It is located in Astana.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kazakh Research Institute of Culture</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kz_research_institute_of_culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kz_research_institute_of_culture/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;First founded in 1934, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cultural.kz/en/&#34;&gt;Kazakh Research Institute of Culture&lt;/a&gt; is a research center for art, culture, history, and archaeology. Its mission is to &amp;ldquo;conduct an in-depth systemic analysis in the sphere of culture in accordance with the Conception of cultural policy of the Republic of Kazakhstan, integration into world cultural space and effective international cooperation.&amp;rdquo; The institute is located in Almaty.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: National Library of Uzbekistan named after Alisher Navoi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/national_library_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/national_library_uz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Originally founded in 1870, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.natlib.uz/&#34;&gt;National Library of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; received its current name in 2002. It is the main state book depository for national and foreign press, information and research institution, and a methodological center for all libraries of the country. The National Library is located in Tashkent.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Museum of Contemporary Women&#39;s and Queer Art of Central Asia (MoFA&#43;)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mofa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/mofa/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://femmuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA+)&lt;/a&gt; is a museum spotlighting feminist and queer artists from Central Asia and advocating for the rights and freedoms of women and LGBTQIA+ community. MoFA+ hosts solo and group exhibits, workshops, and events. The museum also grants art fellowships and is involved in documentary filmmaking.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Adil Qala</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adil_qala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/adil_qala/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adilqala.kz/&#34;&gt;Adil Qala&lt;/a&gt; is a project on social justice in the field of urban planning and development. It aims to create a platform for a &amp;ldquo;broad public dialogue about the priority of the human dimension in urban policies and practices.&amp;rdquo; Adil Qala hosts public discussions and educational programs, including on the topic of LGBTQIA+ safe spaces and visibility and safety of women in urban settings.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Against Frotterizm</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/against_frotterizm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/against_frotterizm/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/frotterizm.uz/&#34;&gt;Against Frotterizm&lt;/a&gt; is a social campaign project based on voluntary involved. It is combating frotteurism and harassment of women in Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s public transport. The project aims to increase public awareness of the issue, develop mechanisms to detect cases of harassment in public transport, and develop instructions on what to do and how to protect victims if they are harassed on public transport.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Amerika Ovozi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/amerika_ovozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/amerika_ovozi/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amerikaovozi.com/&#34;&gt;Amerika Ovozi (Voice of America)&lt;/a&gt; is an international multimedia agency launched in 1942 and funded by the US Congress. Its charter was founded in 1976. Since 2016, Amerika Ovozi legally established itself as an independent media with a neutral coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ariadna</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ariadna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ariadna/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ariadna.media&#34;&gt;Ariadna&lt;/a&gt; is a Central Asia media dedicated to covering the art scene of the region using accessible language. It provides reviews, editorials, and audioguides.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bashtan Bashta</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bashtan_bashta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bashtan_bashta/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@bashtanbashta/&#34;&gt;Bashtan Bashta&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bashtan_bashta/&#34;&gt;a social media project&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to raising civil consciousness in Kyrgyzstan. It also covers news and politics of other Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bulbul Podcasts</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bulbul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bulbul/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bulbulpodcasts/&#34;&gt;Bulbul Podcasts&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast studio that produces shows about Kazakhstani women&amp;rsquo;s histories and stories, as well as culture and music.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Crossroads Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/crossroads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/crossroads/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crossroads-ca.org/&#34;&gt;Crossroads Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; is a Bishkek-based non-profit research institute with an aim to &amp;ldquo;promote better understanding of political, economic and security affairs of Central Asia and its wider Eurasian neighborhood.&amp;rdquo; It publishes analytical commentary and research reports.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Daryo</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/daryo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/daryo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://daryo.uz&#34;&gt;Daryo&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news media offering coverage of politics, economics, sport, and culture in Uzbekistan and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Dope Soz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@DOPESOZ/&#34;&gt;Dope Soz&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series offering discussions and conversations about social, historical, political, and cultural events and discourses.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Education Community</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/edu_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/edu_community/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 in partnership with USAID and Eurasia Foundation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/edu.community.kz/&#34;&gt;Education Community&lt;/a&gt; is an activist project that aims to connect gender and sexuality minorities to provide them with opportunities for personal, psychological, and legal support and development. Education Community creates and shares projects and programs advocating for diversity, inclusivity, and tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: European Sex Workers Rights Alliance</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eswra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eswra/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002 under the name of International Committee for Sex Workers in Europe (ICRSE), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eswalliance.org/&#34;&gt;European Sex Workers Rights Alliance&lt;/a&gt; is a sex worker-led network representing more than 100 organizations in 30 countries across Europe and Central Asia. One of its recent publication is &amp;ldquo;Sex work &amp;amp; racism: the impact of structural racism on racialized sex workers in Europe and Central Asia&amp;rdquo; report.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: FemAgora</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/femagora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/femagora/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://femagora.org/&#34;&gt;FemAgora&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to fostering transnational feminist solidarity in Central Asia. The organization is involved in organization of Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march and the issue of employment of transgender people. FemAgora hosts annual FemAgora Central Asian festival for those involved in feminist, gender-sensitive, and/or women-led work.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminist Translocalities</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminisms.co/&#34;&gt;Feminist Translocalities&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots transnational feminist organization aiming to bring together and support feminist and LGBTQ+ activists from Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia. The organization publishes magazine articles and zines, hosts events, and engages in other various projects. Although the website describes the organization as primarily focused on Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia, it frequently publishes works by Central Asian authors.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminita</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminita/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminita.kz/&#34;&gt;Feminita&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots queer feminist collective. Feminita aims to create and strengthen the rights of women and activist communities and empower the most oppressed groups of Kazakhstani population (lesbian, bisexual, queer, women with disabilities, women in sex work). Currently, the organization works on three research projects: assessment of needs of LBQ women; health conditions of LBQT women and transgender men; and sexual wellness of LBQ women. Methodology and research design sections are included in the first two project reports. The reports are available in Russian with occasional translation to Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Human Rights Focus</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/human_rights_focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/human_rights_focus/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by USAID and Kazakhstan Public Association &amp;ldquo;Dignity&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://humanrightsfocus.kz/&#34;&gt;Human Rights Focus&lt;/a&gt; is a project mobilizing and organizing various groups, including human rights defenders, NGOs, civil society leaders, and others, for empowering and encouraging women in Kazakhstan to participate more fully in public administration and decision-making and for prevention of bullying in Kazakhstani schools. Human Rights Focus offers trainings and workshops to Kazakhstani teachers, hosts conferences, and provides educational content on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ILGA-Europe</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ilga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ilga/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ilga-europe.org/&#34;&gt;ILGA-Europe&lt;/a&gt; is an International NGO advocating for the protection of LGBTI people and uniting over 600 organizations from 54 countries across Europe and Central Asia. ILGA conducts its work through resourcing and connecting communities, driving political change, and amplifying voices. Its mission is to provide a solid foundation for activists and organizations. ILGA publishes reports on the protection of rights of LGBTI people in Central Asia, specifically related to violence and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Invisible Rainbow Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/invisible_rainbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/invisible_rainbow/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/invisible_rainbow_union/&#34;&gt;Invisible Rainbow Union&lt;/a&gt; is a social media community of queer ethnic minorities from Central Asia and Russia. The media focuses on preserving oral histories of the LGBTQIA+ community.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kaz Fem</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kazfem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kazfem/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/kaz_fem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots feminist organization dedicated to research and development of feminist theory in Kazakhstan. One of the leading organizations behind Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march. Available mostly in Russian with occasional material in Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kibhr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kibhr/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bureau.kz/&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law (KIBHR)&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani bureau of human rights. It engages in human rights advocacy, shares relevant reports, and engages in human rights monitoring in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kok.team</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kok.team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kok.team/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017 and dissolved in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kok.team/&#34;&gt;Kok.team&lt;/a&gt; was a grassroots LGBT organization dedicated to providing information on the LGBT issues in Kazakh. Digital archive contains articles, podcasts and videos of Kazakhstani LGBT  community. Available in Kazakh and Russian with occasional translation to English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Legal Policy Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/lprc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/lprc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2008 by a group of Kazakhstani lawyers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lprc.kz/&#34;&gt;Legal Policy Research Center (LPRC)&lt;/a&gt; is a non-political, independent research institute promoting the principle of the rule of law and liberal values through the implementation of research, publishing and educational activities in the field of legal policy. Its mission is to strengthen democratic values through effective legal reforms. Its projects include promoting anti-discrimination agenda and combating sexual harassment.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Official Website of the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/president_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/president_website/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://president.uz/&#34;&gt;Official Website of the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; publishes updates, media, infographics, and legislative documents.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qalampir</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qalampir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qalampir/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://qalampir.uz/&#34;&gt;Qalampir&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news and analytics publication with an aim to achieve transparent and quality informational space in the media sector of Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qara Magan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qara.magan/&#34;&gt;Qara Magan&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project is dedicated to visibility and storytelling of the LGBTQ+ community of Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: QAZAQUEER</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qazaqueer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qazaqueer/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qazaqueer/&#34;&gt;QAZAQUEER&lt;/a&gt; is a social media project on the lives of the LGBTQIA+ community in Kazakhstan. It primarily produces content in Kazakh and offers educational resources on queer identity, relationships, and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Queernyi squirt</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mira Ungarova and Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://podcast.kz/1657513218/info&#34;&gt;Queernyi Squirt&lt;/a&gt; is an 18+ podcast dedicated to inclusive LGBTQIA+ sex education in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Repost</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/repost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/repost/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://repost.uz/&#34;&gt;Repost&lt;/a&gt; is a Russian-language news media in Uzbekistan. It covers local and world affairs, as well as lifestyle and cultural events.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Right Now</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/right-now/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 in association with the US Embassy in Kazakhstan and the National Alumi Network of US programs graduates, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/rightnow.kz/&#34;&gt;Right Now&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform promoting awareness of legal rights in Kazakhstan. It offers online lectures on various topics, including violence against women and children.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ruyo Journal</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ruyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ruyo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruyojournal.com&#34;&gt;Ruyo Journal&lt;/a&gt; is an artist-led digital media focused on critical discourse on art, film, and theory in Central Asia. Its goal is to &amp;ldquo;support the development of a flourishing cultural scene in Central Asia by providing a platform for thoughtful and engaging discussions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Sof.uz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/sof/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2016, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sof.uz/&#34;&gt;Sof.uz&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news publication designed to deliver news to a wider audience using accessible language.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Spot</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/spot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/spot/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2017 as a part of the Afisha Media company, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spot.uz/&#34;&gt;Spot&lt;/a&gt; is a news media primarily covering business and economic news in Uzbekistan. It also offers editorial pieces on the same topics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Statistics Agency under the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/statistics_agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/statistics_agency/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz/&#34;&gt;Statistics Agency under the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; publishes official statistical reports and the state&amp;rsquo;s analysis of social and economic processes.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Stop Harass</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/stop-harass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/stop-harass/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stopharass.kz/&#34;&gt;Stop Harass&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani harassment prevention and tracking website. Its mission is to &amp;ldquo;engage all residents of Kazakhstan in creating an environment that is intolerant of sexual assault, harassment, stalking, catcalling, etc.&amp;rdquo; The platform allows anyone to report harassment instances either via Telegram bot or website.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: TEDxAbayStWomen</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;First held in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tedxabaystwomen/&#34;&gt;TEDxAbayStWomen&lt;/a&gt; is a noncommercial conference on gender equality usually held in Almaty, Kazakhstan. Next conference is expected to be held in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: The Fish that changed gender (Рыба, которая сменила пол)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fish/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://beacons.ai/rybaipol&#34;&gt;the Fish that changed gender&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast project in conversation with transgender people living in Kazakhstan. It brings forward stories and experiences of transpeople. The podcast also has a presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/rybaipol/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: The Government Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uz_gov_portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/uz_gov_portal/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/&#34;&gt;The Government Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is an official website of all thing related to the government of Uzbekistan. It includes information on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/ru/&#34;&gt;gender statistics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/en/pages/government_sites&#34;&gt;a list of government bodies&amp;rsquo; websites&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/en/organizations/kind/local&#34;&gt;a list of local authorities&amp;rsquo; websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
