<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – research</title>
    <link>/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asian Analytical Network</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_asian_analytical_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_asian_analytical_network/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded on the basis of the George Washington University’s Institute for European, Russian, and Eurasian Studies (IERES), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.caa-network.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Analytical Network&lt;/a&gt; offers editorial and opinion pieces, interviews, book and publication reviews, and expert projects on politics, society, and economics of Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Voices on Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/voices_on_central_asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/voices_on_central_asia/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in collaboration with the Central Asia Program and the Central Asian Analytical Network on the basis of the George Washington University’s Institute for European, Russian, and Eurasian Studies (IERES), &lt;a href=&#34;https://voicesoncentralasia.org/&#34;&gt;Voices on Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; offers analytical pieces, research insights, policy discussions, fieldwork recollections, photos, charts, and data on Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Gender Economics Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/gerc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/gerc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 with the assistance of the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.narxoz.kz/research/institutes/gerc&#34;&gt;Gender Economics Research Center (GERC)&lt;/a&gt; is a research center at Narxoz University, Almaty. GERC is dedicated to development and coordination of research on gender and economy. The center publishes research articles and reports on the topics of labor market, education, COVID-19 impact, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Research Institute for Social and Gender Studies</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/research_institute_for_social_and_gender_studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/research_institute_for_social_and_gender_studies/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2000 on the basis of the Kazakh National Women’s Teacher Training University, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazmkpu.kz/en/ob-institute-sgi&#34;&gt;Research Institute for Social and Gender Studies&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to promoting gender and social equality through the implementation of multidisciplinary research projects and social initiatives. Research and publications are particularly focused on education and teaching in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Tselinny Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tselinny_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tselinny_center/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 by Kairat Boranbayev, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tselinny.org/&#34;&gt;Tselinny Center&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to studying and developing cultural scene in Kazakhstan. The center publishes educational books, hosts art exhibitions, and organizes events.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
