<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – general NGO</title>
    <link>/tags/general-ngo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in general NGO on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/general-ngo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Eurasian Cultural Alliance</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasian_cultural_alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasian_cultural_alliance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2011, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.cultura.kz/&#34;&gt;Eurasian Cultural Alliance&lt;/a&gt; is a NGO dedicated to cultivating the contemporary art scene of Kazakhstan. The mission of the Alliance is to stimulate the creative economy, improve social and economic standing of the region&amp;rsquo;s key cultural players, and advance the integration of the Kazakhstani identity into a larger global context.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Fading.TSE</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/fading.tse/&#34;&gt;Fading.TSE&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project documenting urban history of Kazakhstan and its capital. Primary focused on photography, oral histories, and cultural heritage. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram, Facebook, TikTok, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: MISK</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/misk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/misk/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1998 &lt;a href=&#34;https://misk.org.kz/&#34;&gt;MISK (Kazakhstani Informational Youth Service)&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to research on youth, monitoring youth policy legislation, and human rights training. Key projects of the organization include School of Human Rights and School of Civil Education. MISK also regularly published surveys on various social issues. Summary of survey findings include brief information on sample sizes of each survey. Available in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nghrdc.kz/&#34;&gt;New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a coalition of Kazakhstani human rights defenders including practicing experts in the field of international human rights law, human rights researchers, leaders, and members of NGOs. The Coalition is engaged in informational campaigns, educational training, and other public events organization.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Oyan, Qazaqstan!</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/oyanqazaqstankz/&#34;&gt;Oyan, Qazaqstan!&lt;/a&gt; is a social movement advocating for political reforms in Kazakhstan. The organization shares news about political events, activist campaigns, organizing efforts, as well as prosecution of activists by the state authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Policy Solutions Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://policysolutions.kz/&#34;&gt;Policy Solutions Center&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots organizations of Kazakhstani researchers involved in the study of socio-political and socio-economic problems in Kazakhstan, as well as the development of policy and management recommendations. The Center publishes analytical pieces and develops projects on political, economic, and social issues.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: </title>
      <link>/sources/sources/public_opinion_research_institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/public_opinion_research_institute/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opinions.kz/&#34;&gt;Public Opinion Research Institute&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani sociological institute specializes in public opinion, marketing, and sociological studies of Kazakhstan and other countries. The institute publishes research reports on various topics, including COVID-19, migration, social values, etc. Most publications are available in Kazakh and Russian with occasional translation to English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Tselinny Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tselinny_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tselinny_center/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 by Kairat Boranbayev, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tselinny.org/&#34;&gt;Tselinny Center&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to studying and developing cultural scene in Kazakhstan. The center publishes educational books, hosts art exhibitions, and organizes events.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
