<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – LGBTQIA&#43;</title>
    <link>/tags/lgbtqia&#43;/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LGBTQIA&#43; on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/lgbtqia+/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ECOM</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ecom/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecom.ngo/&#34;&gt;ECOM (Eurasian Coalition for Health, Rights, Gender and Sexual Diversity)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional NGO working the sphere of health of LGBTI communities in Eastern Europe and Central Asia. It is a membership association open to non-profit organizations and activists working in the field. ECOM publishes regular reports on violation of rights of the LGBTI people in various Central Asian countries, including Uzbekistan and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Exponaut</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/exponaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/exponaut/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/exponautz/&#34;&gt;Exponaut&lt;/a&gt; is an independent media geared toward a younger audience. It covers art and culture, as well as creating projects meant to spotlight women and LGBTQIA+ community of Uzbekistan. Exponaut also has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/exponautz/729&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Trans*Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transcoalition.net/&#34;&gt;Trans*Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a platform for trans- and non-binary activists from the countries of the Caucasus, Central Asia and Eastern Europe. It advocates for uniting, solidarizing, strengthening the voice of the trans-activist community in our region through the development of a sustainable, effective, authoritative, and resourceful organization. Key areas of Trans&lt;em&gt;Coalition&amp;rsquo;s work include response to the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, depathologizing, sex work, and legislation. In Central Asia, Trans&lt;/em&gt;Coalition offers a hot line, a map of resources and aid, and information for trans sex workers.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
