<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – 2017</title>
    <link>/date_start/2017/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2017 on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/date_start/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: NeMolchiKZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.kz/&#34;&gt;#NeMolchiKZ&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots public fund dedicated to protection of victims of gender-based violence. The fund defines its activities along the three components, including legal protection, promotion of awareness, and legislative.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: NeMolchi.UZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchi_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchi_uz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.uz&#34;&gt;NeMolchi.UZ&lt;/a&gt; is an independent information project against gender-based violence in Uzbekistan. Its mission is to draw attention to violence against women and challenge societal attitudes towards the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asia Barometer</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_asia_barometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_asia_barometer/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ca-barometer.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asia Barometer (CAB)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional independent NGO for applied social research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAB Survey Project is a multinational empirical survey on human beliefs and values first conducted in 2017. Questionnaires identify gender of the respondents with two options included, male or female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAB provides free access to databases of the CAB Survey Project available in SPSS, Excel, and Stata formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note &lt;a href=&#34;https://ca-barometer.org/en/what-we-do/methodology/research-methods&#34;&gt;is available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/central-asia&#34;&gt;Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt; is a research and advocacy campaign dedicated to eliminating sexual and gender-based violence and harmful practices in Central Asia. The program involves UN Women, UNDP, and UNFPA with funding from the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan 2020 report is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/publications/spotlight-initiative-central-asia-and-afghanistan-programme-report-2020&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt; in English. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/projects/spotlight-initiative-regional-programme-central-asia-and-afghanistan&#34;&gt;UNDP project page for the Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oecd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oecd/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is not a member of the OECD and acts as its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;partner for the Eurasian region&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of available data on Kazakhstan found on the OECD portal, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/gender-policy-delivery-in-kazakhstan-9789264280359-en.htm&#34;&gt;2017 Gender Policy Delivery in Kazakhstan review&lt;/a&gt; is so far the only gender-related publication on Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The review contains policy assessment and recommendation. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
