<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</title>
    <link>/data_type/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 21:15:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/data_type/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Akimat of the city of Astana</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/astana/about?lang=en&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Astana&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the akimat (regional administration) of the capital city Astana. Contains official documents, press releases, and statistical data of the city. Offers latest news about the capital’s governance. The information is divided into several directions, including familial and demographic policies, culture, civil society, youth, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amerika Ovozi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/amerika_ovozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/amerika_ovozi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amerikaovozi.com/&#34;&gt;Amerika Ovozi (Voice of America)&lt;/a&gt; is an international multimedia agency launched in 1942 and funded by the US Congress. Its charter was founded in 1976. Since 2016, Amerika Ovozi legally established itself as an independent media with a neutral coverage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bashtan Bashta</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bashtan_bashta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/bashtan_bashta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@bashtanbashta/&#34;&gt;Bashtan Bashta&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bashtan_bashta/&#34;&gt;a social media project&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to raising civil consciousness in Kyrgyzstan. It also covers news and politics of other Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crossroads Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/crossroads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/crossroads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crossroads-ca.org/&#34;&gt;Crossroads Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; is a Bishkek-based non-profit research institute with an aim to &amp;ldquo;promote better understanding of political, economic and security affairs of Central Asia and its wider Eurasian neighborhood.&amp;rdquo; It publishes analytical commentary and research reports.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daryo</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/daryo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/daryo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://daryo.uz&#34;&gt;Daryo&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news media offering coverage of politics, economics, sport, and culture in Uzbekistan and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qalampir</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qalampir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/qalampir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://qalampir.uz/&#34;&gt;Qalampir&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news and analytics publication with an aim to achieve transparent and quality informational space in the media sector of Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repost</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/repost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/repost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://repost.uz/&#34;&gt;Repost&lt;/a&gt; is a Russian-language news media in Uzbekistan. It covers local and world affairs, as well as lifestyle and cultural events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sof.uz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/sof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2016, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sof.uz/&#34;&gt;Sof.uz&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news publication designed to deliver news to a wider audience using accessible language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spot</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/spot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/spot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2017 as a part of the Afisha Media company, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spot.uz/&#34;&gt;Spot&lt;/a&gt; is a news media primarily covering business and economic news in Uzbekistan. It also offers editorial pieces on the same topics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unit </title>
      <link>/sources/sources/unit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/unit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021 by n-ost, a Berlin-based media NGO, &lt;a href=&#34;https://unit.n-ost.org&#34;&gt;Unit&lt;/a&gt; is a crossborder community of journalists and activists from Central Asia, Eastern Europe, and South Caucasus who work on the LGBTQIA+ issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbek Review</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uzbek_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uzbek_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uzbek.review&#34;&gt;Uzbek Review&lt;/a&gt; is a news agency founded by Europe-Uzbekistan Association for Economic Cooperation (EUROUZ). It regularly publishes market reports and occasional analytical pieces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan Daily</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uzdaily/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uzdaily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2009, &lt;a href=&#34;http://uzdaily.uz/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan Daily (UzDaily)&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news media with a focus on business and occasional coverage of other Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan National News Agency</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 1992, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uza.uz/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan National News Agency (UzA)&lt;/a&gt; is a state-affiliated news media and one of &amp;ldquo;the leading information agency of the country. UzA covers activities of the government agencies in the country, as well as socio-political events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UzReport</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uzreport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uzreport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 1999, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uzreport.news/&#34;&gt;UzReport&lt;/a&gt; is one of the largest news portals in Uzbekistan. It offers coverage of politics, economics, culture, and sports, as well as analytical and interview pieces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xabar</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/xabar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/xabar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 1992 by what is currently Ministry of Digital Technologies of the Republic of Uzbekistan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://xabar.uz/&#34;&gt;Xabar&lt;/a&gt; is a state-affiliated news media covering local and world affairs, technology, and sports.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeMolchiKZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.kz/&#34;&gt;#NeMolchiKZ&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots public fund dedicated to protection of victims of gender-based violence. The fund defines its activities along the three components, including legal protection, promotion of awareness, and legislative.   &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anhor</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/anhor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/anhor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anhor.uz/&#34;&gt;Anhor&lt;/a&gt; is an independent media that positions itself as a platform for &amp;ldquo;analytics, investigations, and news.&amp;rdquo; The publication&amp;rsquo;s mission is to contribute to effective governing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art - Review</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/art_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/art_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artreviewuz/&#34;&gt;Art - Review&lt;/a&gt; is local media about art and culture in Uzbekistan. It has presence on Instagram, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/artreviewuz&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.facebook.com/artreview.uz&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ayt Community</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ayt_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/ayt_community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ayt_community/&#34;&gt;Ayt Community&lt;/a&gt; is a local media with a focus on feminism, legislature, and ethics. Ayt Community also organizes various events and advocates for an inclusive future for women.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Center for the Development of Contemporary Journalism in the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mjdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/mjdc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mjdc.uz/&#34;&gt;Center for the Development of Contemporary Journalism in the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is an nongovernmental and noncommercial media institution aimed at improving the quality of journalism in Uzbekistan through &amp;ldquo;identifying problem areas, education, creating quality content that meets the highest standards of truthfulness and objectivity.&amp;rdquo; The center offers trainings for journalists, bloggers, and mass communication professionals, as well as workshops for a wider audience on media literacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exponaut</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/exponaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/exponaut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/exponautz/&#34;&gt;Exponaut&lt;/a&gt; is an independent media geared toward a younger audience. It covers art and culture, as well as creating projects meant to spotlight women and LGBTQIA+ community of Uzbekistan. Exponaut also has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/exponautz/729&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kun.Uz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kun_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/kun_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2012, Kun.Uz is an online publication platform with a wide presence across social media platforms. It offers coverage of news events in Uzbekistan and across the world. The publication works in cooperation with the state and public organizations operating on the territory of Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeMolchi.UZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchi_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchi_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.uz&#34;&gt;NeMolchi.UZ&lt;/a&gt; is an independent information project against gender-based violence in Uzbekistan. Its mission is to draw attention to violence against women and challenge societal attitudes towards the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orda</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/orda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/orda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://orda.kz/&#34;&gt;Orda&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan, as well as journalistic investigations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oydin Nur</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oydin_nur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/oydin_nur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1999, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/oydinnur.uz/&#34;&gt;Regional Center for Social Protection of the Family &amp;ldquo;Oydin Nur&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a shelter in the the Bukhara Region of Uzbekistan that offers long term shelter to female victims of gender-based violence, as well as legal and medical services and resources for personal development. The center organizes seminars and trainings concerning issues of women in the country. State departments of internal affairs, education, and health are listed as partners of Oydin Nur.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sarpa</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sarpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/sarpa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sarpa.media&#34;&gt;Sarpa&lt;/a&gt; is independent Uzbek media with a focus on human rights, democracy, and gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hook Report</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/hook_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/hook_report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hook.report/&#34;&gt;Hook Report&lt;/a&gt; is an independent Uzbek media offering coverage of political, economic, art, and cultural news in the country. According to its mission, Hook Report aims to bring quality news coverage using a less traditional and formal approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adamdar/CA</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adamdar.ca/&#34;&gt;Adamdar/CA&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage and storytelling narratives from Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Uzbekistan, and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CABAR</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/cabar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/cabar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2016 and based under the Institute’s for War and Peace Reporting (IWPR) Central Asian Office, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cabar.asia/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Bureau for Analytical Reporting (CABAR)&lt;/a&gt; offers regional analytical, informational, and educational material on Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calvert Journal (The)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/calvert_journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/calvert_journal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013 and owned by a UK-based non-profit Calvert 22 Foundation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.calvertjournal.com/&#34;&gt;The Calvert Journal&lt;/a&gt; offers publications on culture, innovation, photography, and travel in Central Asia, Caucasus, Russia, the Balkans, and Eastern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Asian Analytical Network</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_asian_analytical_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_asian_analytical_network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded on the basis of the George Washington University’s Institute for European, Russian, and Eurasian Studies (IERES), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.caa-network.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Analytical Network&lt;/a&gt; offers editorial and opinion pieces, interviews, book and publication reviews, and expert projects on politics, society, and economics of Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current Time Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/current_time_asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/current_time_asia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based in Prague, Czech Republic, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.currenttime.tv/asia/&#34;&gt;Current Time Asia&lt;/a&gt; was created by the Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, a US Congress-funded broadcasting organization, with participation of Voice of America. Offers news, reports, investigations, and interviews covering Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diplomat (The)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/diplomat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/diplomat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002 and based in Arlington, Virginia, &lt;a href=&#34;https://thediplomat.com/&#34;&gt;The Diplomat&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eurasia Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2004 and based in Washington, DC, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/where-we-work/asia/&#34;&gt;Eurasia Foundation&lt;/a&gt; works with international, national, and local partners for community action. The foundation has a variety of international and local donors. Areas of expertise include civil society, youth and leadership, media, governance, and [gender and marginalized communities] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/%29&#34;&gt;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eurasianet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasianet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasianet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1999 and based at Columbia University’s Harriman Institute, &lt;a href=&#34;https://eurasianet.org/&#34;&gt;Eurasianet.org&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Central Asia and South Caucasus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mediazona Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mediazona/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/mediazona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2014 in Russia, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mediazona.ca/&#34;&gt;Mediazona Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; covers current events in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, and Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novastan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/novastan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/novastan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2011 in Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan and based in Paris and Berlin, &lt;a href=&#34;https://novastan.org/&#34;&gt;Novastan&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, Uzbekistan, and the Uyghur region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OCCRP</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/occrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/occrp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005 in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.occrp.org/&#34;&gt;Organized Crime and Corruption Reporting Project&lt;/a&gt; aims to develop and equip a global network of investigative journalists, as well as publish stories exposing crime and corruption. The project regularly covers post-Soviet and Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PONARS Eurasia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ponars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/ponars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in the late 1990s and currently based at the George Washington University’s Institute for European, Russian, and Eurasian Studies (IERES), the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ponarseurasia.org/&#34;&gt;Program on New Approaches to Research and Security in Eurasia (PONARS Eurasia)&lt;/a&gt; offers policy analysis and dialogue. The program aims to advance new approaches in research on security, politics, economics, and society in Russia and Eurasia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prague Civil Society Centre</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2014 and based in Prague, the Czech Republic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.praguecivilsociety.org/&#34;&gt;Prague Civil Society Centre&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to enabling civic groups and journalists to connect with their communities through grant making, capacity building, and learning. The Centre is funded by governments of Sweden, the Czech Republic, the UK, and the US, as well as the European Commission, the Oak Foundation, and the Wellspring Philanthropic Fund. Focuses on Eastern Europe and Central Asia. In addition to civil society programs, the Centre publishes media and publications on various topics related to the civic groups in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vlast</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/vlast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/vlast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vlast.kz/&#34;&gt;Vlast&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, as well as various editorial projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voices on Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/voices_on_central_asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/voices_on_central_asia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in collaboration with the Central Asia Program and the Central Asian Analytical Network on the basis of the George Washington University’s Institute for European, Russian, and Eurasian Studies (IERES), &lt;a href=&#34;https://voicesoncentralasia.org/&#34;&gt;Voices on Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; offers analytical pieces, research insights, policy discussions, fieldwork recollections, photos, charts, and data on Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akimat of the city of Almaty</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_almaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_almaty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/almaty?lang=en&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Almaty&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the akimat (regional administration) of Almaty, the largest city in Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, press releases, and statistical data of the city. Offers latest news about Almaty’s governance. The information is divided into several directions, including social sphere, culture, society, youth policies, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azattyq</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/azattyq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/azattyq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.azattyq.org/&#34;&gt;Azattyq&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani branch of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, a US Congress-funded broadcasting organization. Offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, as well as various editorial projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Batyr Jamal</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/batyr_jamal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/batyr_jamal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/batyrjamal/&#34;&gt;Batyr Jamal&lt;/a&gt; is a women-oriented media with coverage primarily focusing on women’s rights, safety, and self-worth. Available on Instagram and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Communication Service under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_communication_service_under_the_president_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_communication_service_under_the_president_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ortcom.kz/en/&#34;&gt;Central Communication Service under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is the official communication service for presidential and state affairs aimed at fostering communication between the government bodies and media. Contains latest news (including regional news), press releases, infographics, video announcements, and expert discussions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crisis Centers Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telefon150.kz/&#34;&gt;Crisis Centers Union&lt;/a&gt; unites 18 organizations from 12 regions of Kazakhstan. The Union is aimed at prevention and eradication of all forms of gender-based violence, formation of a non-violent culture in Kazakhstani society. The website offers news articles, photo and video materials, informational materials, webinars, and infographics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factcheck.kz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/factcheck_/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/factcheck_/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/factcheck.kz/&#34;&gt;Factcheck.kz&lt;/a&gt; is a publication focuses on fact checking news and viral media. Available on Instagram, Telegram, TikTok, and YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FemPoint</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fempoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/fempoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/fempoint_kz/&#34;&gt;FemPoint&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots organization for LBT women providing support resources and engaged in advocacy and activism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HolaNews</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/holanews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/holanews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/holanewskz/&#34;&gt;HolaNews&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan on Instagram, Facebook, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights KZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/human_rights_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/human_rights_kz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/humanrightskz/&#34;&gt;Human Rights KZ&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to sharing domestic and international human rights information and news in Kazakh. Available on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Informburo</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/informburo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/informburo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015 and affiliated with 31st Channel television station, &lt;a href=&#34;https://informburo.kz/&#34;&gt;Informburo&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage, informational and analytical materials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manshuq</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/manshuq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/manshuq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://manshuq.com/&#34;&gt;Manshuq&lt;/a&gt; is a women-oriented media with coverage primarily focusing on lifestyle, culture, career, and other editorial projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Masa Media</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/masa_media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/masa_media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://masa.media/&#34;&gt;Masa Media&lt;/a&gt; strives to explain political, legal, and legislative systems in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nghrdc.kz/&#34;&gt;New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a coalition of Kazakhstani human rights defenders including practicing experts in the field of international human rights law, human rights researchers, leaders, and members of NGOs. The Coalition is engaged in informational campaigns, educational training, and other public events organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Official Information Source of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/official_information_source_of_the_prime_minister_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/official_information_source_of_the_prime_minister_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://primeminister.kz/&#34;&gt;Official Information Source of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, such as the state addresses, policies breakdown of the state and advisory bodies, government composition, as well as an archive of the documents. The website is not search friendly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Policy Solutions Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://policysolutions.kz/&#34;&gt;Policy Solutions Center&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots organizations of Kazakhstani researchers involved in the study of socio-political and socio-economic problems in Kazakhstan, as well as the development of policy and management recommendations. The Center publishes analytical pieces and develops projects on political, economic, and social issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ratel</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ratel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/ratel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ratel.kz/&#34;&gt;Ratel&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events, opinion pieces, and journalistic investigations in Kazakhstan, specifically concerning corruption. The publication had its license rescinded in 2018 in a court ruling on the grounds of spreading misinformation due to the published investigations of various corruption cases. The site resumed its work in 2019. Available primarily in Russian with occasional publications in Kazakh and English.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SVET</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/svet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/svet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://svetpf.org/&#34;&gt;SVET&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani foundation dedicated to helping survivors of gender-based violence and sharing relevant news.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TAG news</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tag_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/tag_news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded first in 2008 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kaztag.kz/ru/&#34;&gt;TAG news agency&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Afghanistan, Iran, and the Silk Road region. Available in English, Kazakh, and Russian in Kazakhstan; Kyrgyz and Russian in Kyrgyzstan; Uzbek and Russian in Uzbekistan; and Tajik and Russian in Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TengriNews</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tengrinews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/tengrinews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2016, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tengrinews.kz/&#34;&gt;TengriNews&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage of current events in Kazakhstan and the world and a database of legislative documents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Til Kespek Joq</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/til_kespek_joq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/til_kespek_joq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tilkespekjoq/&#34;&gt;Til Kespek Joq&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh on Instagram, Telegram, Twitter, Facebook, TikTok, and YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uyat Emes</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uyat_emes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uyat_emes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uyatemes.kz/&#34;&gt;Uyat Emes&lt;/a&gt; is an educational site about sex and relationships for Kazakhstani teenagers and their parents. The mission of the initiative is to help young people become more literate about reproductive health and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Village Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/village_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/village_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.the-village-kz.com/&#34;&gt;The Village Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of cultural and social life, events, and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zakon.kz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/zakon_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/zakon_kz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1999, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zakon.kz/&#34;&gt;Zakon.kz&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, Central Asia, Russia, and the US, as well as analytical materials and interviews.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
