<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Report on CAMGDP</title>
    <link>https://camgdp.org/tags/report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Report on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 22:21:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://camgdp.org/tags/report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNDP</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/un_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/un_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;UN Development Program&lt;/a&gt; became active in Uzbekistan in 1993 and works on projects related to the national government, business, civil society and academic affairs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UNDP regularly published press releases on the topic of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/uzbekistan/gender-equality&#34;&gt;gender equality development&lt;/a&gt; in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://evaw-global-database.unwomen.org/en/countries/asia/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Global database on violence against women&lt;/a&gt; assembles UN data on different forms of violence against women, including all UN-issued reports and updates on Gender Equality Indexes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://uzbekistan.unfpa.org&#34;&gt;UN Population Fund&lt;/a&gt; produces country-specific landing pages. The work of the Fund includes data on sexual and reproductive health, gender equality, young people, and population matters. Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unfpa.org/data/UZ&#34;&gt;Data Portal for Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; gender-related data across six main components: population, sexual and reproductive health, family planning, education, gender, rights, and human capital, and harmful practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/oecd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/oecd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is not a member of the OECD and acts as its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;partner for the Eurasian region&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Out of available data on Kazakhstan found on the OECD portal, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/gender-policy-delivery-in-kazakhstan-9789264280359-en.htm&#34;&gt;2017 Gender Policy Delivery in Kazakhstan review&lt;/a&gt; is so far the only gender-related publication on Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The review contains policy assessment and recommendation. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Kazakhstan Annual Report 2021</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/un_kazakhstan_annual_report_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/un_kazakhstan_annual_report_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pages 24-27 of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.un.org/en/176526-un-kazakhstan-annual-report-2021&#34;&gt;UN Kazakhstan Annual Report 2021&lt;/a&gt; summarize the UN’s efforts in fostering gender equality and human rights development in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNDP in Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/undp_in_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/undp_in_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UNDP in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; page includes a section on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/gender-equality-0&#34;&gt;gender equality&lt;/a&gt; that focuses on causes of gender inequality in Kazakhstan in the context of the Sustainable Development Goals. The website provides a brief overview of the UNDP gender equality agenda in Kazakhstan and key general statistics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications/gender-profile-sustainable-development-goals-kazakhstan&#34;&gt;2019 Gender Profile of Sustainable Development Goals in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is available only Russian. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Publications about Kazakhstan are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/publications&#34;&gt;available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
