<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – advocacy</title>
    <link>/data_type/advocacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in advocacy on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/data_type/advocacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Antiuniversity of Feminism</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/antiuniversity_of_feminism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/antiuniversity_of_feminism/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/antiuniversity_of_feminism/&#34;&gt;Antiuniversity of Feminism&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project aimed at creating a safe space for women and people with all gender identities to learn about feminism and gender theory. Antiuniversity offers free online courses in Kyrgyz. The project was founded and created by Elvira Tilek.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Artif</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/artif/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artif.ication/&#34;&gt;Artif&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform connecting artists, human rights defenders, and activists from Eastern Europe and Central Asia. The platform&amp;rsquo;s mission is to voice social problems using art accessible to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ayol buyum emas</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ayol_buyum_emas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ayol_buyum_emas/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ayolbuyumemas/&#34;&gt;Ayol buyum emas&lt;/a&gt; is a nascent social project aimed at supporting Uzbek women and combating violence against them. It also has presence in &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/ayolbuyumemas&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Center of legal protection &#39;Zan Talaby&#39;</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/zan_talaby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/zan_talaby/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/NgoZanTalabyShymkent/&#34;&gt;Center of legal protection &amp;ldquo;Zan Talaby&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a Shymkent-based NGO dedicated to combating human trafficking in Kazakhstan. It offers hotline assistance to victims of human trafficking and actively engages in discussions, awareness campaigns, and educational trainings on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ECOM</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ecom/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecom.ngo/&#34;&gt;ECOM (Eurasian Coalition for Health, Rights, Gender and Sexual Diversity)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional NGO working the sphere of health of LGBTI communities in Eastern Europe and Central Asia. It is a membership association open to non-profit organizations and activists working in the field. ECOM publishes regular reports on violation of rights of the LGBTI people in various Central Asian countries, including Uzbekistan and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ILGA-Europe</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ilga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ilga/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ilga-europe.org/&#34;&gt;ILGA-Europe&lt;/a&gt; is an International NGO advocating for the protection of LGBTI people and uniting over 600 organizations from 54 countries across Europe and Central Asia. ILGA conducts its work through resourcing and connecting communities, driving political change, and amplifying voices. Its mission is to provide a solid foundation for activists and organizations. ILGA publishes reports on the protection of rights of LGBTI people in Central Asia, specifically related to violence and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qizlar Ovozi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qizlar_ovozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qizlar_ovozi/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qizlarovozi.uz/&#34;&gt;Qizlar Ovozi&lt;/a&gt; is a school aimed at motivating and helping girls and young women aged 14 to 30 years in their professional development. The school also intends to increase and strengthen women&amp;rsquo;s role in public life. Qizlar Ovozi was founded by Nilufar Kiyamova.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Sening mening haqqimiz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sening_mening_haqqimiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/sening_mening_haqqimiz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/sening_mening_haqqimiz/&#34;&gt;Sening mening haqqimiz&lt;/a&gt; is a social media account advocating for women&amp;rsquo;s rights, education, and development in Uzbekistan. On its Instagram page, sening mening haqqimiz shares relevant resources and news. The initiative is particularly focused on issues of violence against women.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Trans*Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transcoalition.net/&#34;&gt;Trans*Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a platform for trans- and non-binary activists from the countries of the Caucasus, Central Asia and Eastern Europe. It advocates for uniting, solidarizing, strengthening the voice of the trans-activist community in our region through the development of a sustainable, effective, authoritative, and resourceful organization. Key areas of Trans&lt;em&gt;Coalition&amp;rsquo;s work include response to the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, depathologizing, sex work, and legislation. In Central Asia, Trans&lt;/em&gt;Coalition offers a hot line, a map of resources and aid, and information for trans sex workers.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Uzbekistan with a Female Voice</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uzbekistan_with_a_female_voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/uzbekistan_with_a_female_voice/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/uzbekistanwithafemalevoice/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan with a Female Voice&lt;/a&gt; is a social media initiative that advocates for gender equality and women empowerment in Uzbekistan by spotlighting stories of Uzbek women and sharing relevant events and news. It has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Ozbekistonayollarkozibilan/&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.me/uzbekayol&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
