<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advocacy on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</title>
    <link>/data_type/advocacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advocacy on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 23:08:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/data_type/advocacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adil Qala</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adil_qala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/adil_qala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adilqala.kz/&#34;&gt;Adil Qala&lt;/a&gt; is a project on social justice in the field of urban planning and development. It aims to create a platform for a &amp;ldquo;broad public dialogue about the priority of the human dimension in urban policies and practices.&amp;rdquo; Adil Qala hosts public discussions and educational programs, including on the topic of LGBTQIA+ safe spaces and visibility and safety of women in urban settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Against Frotterizm</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/against_frotterizm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/against_frotterizm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/frotterizm.uz/&#34;&gt;Against Frotterizm&lt;/a&gt; is a social campaign project based on voluntary involved. It is combating frotteurism and harassment of women in Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s public transport. The project aims to increase public awareness of the issue, develop mechanisms to detect cases of harassment in public transport, and develop instructions on what to do and how to protect victims if they are harassed on public transport.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education Community</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/edu_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/edu_community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 in partnership with USAID and Eurasia Foundation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/edu.community.kz/&#34;&gt;Education Community&lt;/a&gt; is an activist project that aims to connect gender and sexuality minorities to provide them with opportunities for personal, psychological, and legal support and development. Education Community creates and shares projects and programs advocating for diversity, inclusivity, and tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European Sex Workers Rights Alliance</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eswra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/eswra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002 under the name of International Committee for Sex Workers in Europe (ICRSE), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eswalliance.org/&#34;&gt;European Sex Workers Rights Alliance&lt;/a&gt; is a sex worker-led network representing more than 100 organizations in 30 countries across Europe and Central Asia. One of its recent publication is &amp;ldquo;Sex work &amp;amp; racism: the impact of structural racism on racialized sex workers in Europe and Central Asia&amp;rdquo; report.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights Focus</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/human_rights_focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/human_rights_focus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by USAID and Kazakhstan Public Association &amp;ldquo;Dignity&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://humanrightsfocus.kz/&#34;&gt;Human Rights Focus&lt;/a&gt; is a project mobilizing and organizing various groups, including human rights defenders, NGOs, civil society leaders, and others, for empowering and encouraging women in Kazakhstan to participate more fully in public administration and decision-making and for prevention of bullying in Kazakhstani schools. Human Rights Focus offers trainings and workshops to Kazakhstani teachers, hosts conferences, and provides educational content on social media.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILGA-Europe</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ilga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/ilga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ilga-europe.org/&#34;&gt;ILGA-Europe&lt;/a&gt; is an International NGO advocating for the protection of LGBTI people and uniting over 600 organizations from 54 countries across Europe and Central Asia. ILGA conducts its work through resourcing and connecting communities, driving political change, and amplifying voices. Its mission is to provide a solid foundation for activists and organizations. ILGA publishes reports on the protection of rights of LGBTI people in Central Asia, specifically related to violence and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invisible Rainbow Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/invisible_rainbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/invisible_rainbow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/invisible_rainbow_union/&#34;&gt;Invisible Rainbow Union&lt;/a&gt; is a social media community of queer ethnic minorities from Central Asia and Russia. The media focuses on preserving oral histories of the LGBTQIA+ community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kibhr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/kibhr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bureau.kz/&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law (KIBHR)&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani bureau of human rights. It engages in human rights advocacy, shares relevant reports, and engages in human rights monitoring in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal Policy Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/lprc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/lprc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2008 by a group of Kazakhstani lawyers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lprc.kz/&#34;&gt;Legal Policy Research Center (LPRC)&lt;/a&gt; is a non-political, independent research institute promoting the principle of the rule of law and liberal values through the implementation of research, publishing and educational activities in the field of legal policy. Its mission is to strengthen democratic values through effective legal reforms. Its projects include promoting anti-discrimination agenda and combating sexual harassment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QAZAQUEER</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qazaqueer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/qazaqueer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qazaqueer/&#34;&gt;QAZAQUEER&lt;/a&gt; is a social media project on the lives of the LGBTQIA+ community in Kazakhstan. It primarily produces content in Kazakh and offers educational resources on queer identity, relationships, and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Right Now</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/right-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 in association with the US Embassy in Kazakhstan and the National Alumi Network of US programs graduates, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/rightnow.kz/&#34;&gt;Right Now&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform promoting awareness of legal rights in Kazakhstan. It offers online lectures on various topics, including violence against women and children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unit </title>
      <link>/sources/sources/unit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/unit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021 by n-ost, a Berlin-based media NGO, &lt;a href=&#34;https://unit.n-ost.org&#34;&gt;Unit&lt;/a&gt; is a crossborder community of journalists and activists from Central Asia, Eastern Europe, and South Caucasus who work on the LGBTQIA+ issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antiuniversity of Feminism</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/antiuniversity_of_feminism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/antiuniversity_of_feminism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/antiuniversity_of_feminism/&#34;&gt;Antiuniversity of Feminism&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project aimed at creating a safe space for women and people with all gender identities to learn about feminism and gender theory. Antiuniversity offers free online courses in Kyrgyz. The project was founded and created by Elvira Tilek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artif</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/artif/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artif.ication/&#34;&gt;Artif&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform connecting artists, human rights defenders, and activists from Eastern Europe and Central Asia. The platform&amp;rsquo;s mission is to voice social problems using art accessible to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ayol buyum emas</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ayol_buyum_emas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/ayol_buyum_emas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ayolbuyumemas/&#34;&gt;Ayol buyum emas&lt;/a&gt; is a nascent social project aimed at supporting Uzbek women and combating violence against them. It also has presence in &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/ayolbuyumemas&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Center of legal protection &#39;Zan Talaby&#39;</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/zan_talaby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/zan_talaby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/NgoZanTalabyShymkent/&#34;&gt;Center of legal protection &amp;ldquo;Zan Talaby&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a Shymkent-based NGO dedicated to combating human trafficking in Kazakhstan. It offers hotline assistance to victims of human trafficking and actively engages in discussions, awareness campaigns, and educational trainings on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECOM</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/ecom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecom.ngo/&#34;&gt;ECOM (Eurasian Coalition for Health, Rights, Gender and Sexual Diversity)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional NGO working the sphere of health of LGBTI communities in Eastern Europe and Central Asia. It is a membership association open to non-profit organizations and activists working in the field. ECOM publishes regular reports on violation of rights of the LGBTI people in various Central Asian countries, including Uzbekistan and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qizlar Ovozi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qizlar_ovozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/qizlar_ovozi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qizlarovozi.uz/&#34;&gt;Qizlar Ovozi&lt;/a&gt; is a school aimed at motivating and helping girls and young women aged 14 to 30 years in their professional development. The school also intends to increase and strengthen women&amp;rsquo;s role in public life. Qizlar Ovozi was founded by Nilufar Kiyamova.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sening mening haqqimiz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sening_mening_haqqimiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/sening_mening_haqqimiz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/sening_mening_haqqimiz/&#34;&gt;Sening mening haqqimiz&lt;/a&gt; is a social media account advocating for women&amp;rsquo;s rights, education, and development in Uzbekistan. On its Instagram page, sening mening haqqimiz shares relevant resources and news. The initiative is particularly focused on issues of violence against women.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trans*Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transcoalition.net/&#34;&gt;Trans*Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a platform for trans- and non-binary activists from the countries of the Caucasus, Central Asia and Eastern Europe. It advocates for uniting, solidarizing, strengthening the voice of the trans-activist community in our region through the development of a sustainable, effective, authoritative, and resourceful organization. Key areas of Trans&lt;em&gt;Coalition&amp;rsquo;s work include response to the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, depathologizing, sex work, and legislation. In Central Asia, Trans&lt;/em&gt;Coalition offers a hot line, a map of resources and aid, and information for trans sex workers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan with a Female Voice</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uzbekistan_with_a_female_voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uzbekistan_with_a_female_voice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/uzbekistanwithafemalevoice/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan with a Female Voice&lt;/a&gt; is a social media initiative that advocates for gender equality and women empowerment in Uzbekistan by spotlighting stories of Uzbek women and sharing relevant events and news. It has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Ozbekistonayollarkozibilan/&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.me/uzbekayol&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
