<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – dataset</title>
    <link>/data_type/dataset/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dataset on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/data_type/dataset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Bank</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_bank/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/&#34;&gt;World Bank Gender Data Portal&lt;/a&gt; covers &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/kyrgyz-republic/&#34;&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/mongolia/&#34;&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/tajikistan/&#34;&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/Turkmenistan/&#34;&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/uzbekistan/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;, and offers a breakdown of gender-related data in regards to adolescent fertility rates, education completion rates, literacy levels, labor force participation, vulnerable employment, unpaid domestic work, business and bank account ownership, internet usage, and parliament membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data sources annotation is available under all indicators. It includes development relevance, limitation and exceptions, and statistical concepts and methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datasets are available via CVS, API, and Databank formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wbl.worldbank.org/en/reports&#34;&gt;Women, Business, and the Law Reports&lt;/a&gt; Annual report measuring the laws and regulations that affect women’s economic opportunity in 190 economies, including Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports are available in English with executive summaries in French, Spanish, and Arabic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodology section is available on the website and is based on feedback of &amp;ldquo;more than 2,000 respondents&amp;rdquo; which includes local experts on family, labor, and criminal law, including lawyers, judges, academics, and civil society. It is unclear whether the questionnaires sent out to experts are in English, Russian, or Kazakh languages.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asia Barometer</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_asia_barometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_asia_barometer/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ca-barometer.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asia Barometer (CAB)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional independent NGO for applied social research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAB Survey Project is a multinational empirical survey on human beliefs and values first conducted in 2017. Questionnaires identify gender of the respondents with two options included, male or female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAB provides free access to databases of the CAB Survey Project available in SPSS, Excel, and Stata formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note &lt;a href=&#34;https://ca-barometer.org/en/what-we-do/methodology/research-methods&#34;&gt;is available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
