<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – Aizada Arystanbek</title>
    <link>/contributor/aizada-arystanbek/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aizada Arystanbek on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/contributor/aizada-arystanbek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: Kazakhstan Gender Research Guide</title>
      <link>/guides/kazakhstan/kazakhstan_gender_research_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/kazakhstan/kazakhstan_gender_research_guide/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Kazakhstan’s Gender Data Research Guide. This guide is designed to assist researchers, students, scholars, and activists in exploring the intricate landscape of gender and sexuality within the context of Kazakhstan. We recognize the importance of prioritizing locally produced knowledge and grassroots activism in understanding the complexities of this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan, as a diverse and rapidly evolving nation in Central Asia, presents a unique intersection of cultures, histories, and identities. This guide aims to provide a curated selection of resources, databases, and research strategies that will empower you to delve into the multifaceted dimensions of gender roles, sexual identities, and social dynamics in this region. Our commitment to highlighting locally produced knowledge and grassroots activism ensures that you have access to perspectives that are rooted in the lived experiences of individuals within Kazakhstan. These perspectives, often originating from community-based organizations, independent scholars, and advocacy groups, offer insights that traditional academic literature may not fully capture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have carefully assembled resources that span a wide spectrum of topics, from historical perspectives and cultural norms to contemporary issues and activism. By including voices from within the country, we hope to amplify the vital contributions of local activists and researchers who are driving conversations around gender equality and LGBTQIA+ rights. Navigating the complexities of gender and sexuality in any society requires an informed and empathetic approach. As you embark on your research journey, we encourage you to explore this guide&amp;rsquo;s recommendations, engage with diverse viewpoints, and critically analyze the intricate interplay between tradition, progress, and individual expression in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you are an academic researcher, a student, an activist, or simply curious about the evolving landscape of gender and sexuality in Kazakhstan, we hope that this guide, with its emphasis on locally produced knowledge and grassroots organizing, serves as a valuable compass, guiding you toward the resources and insights that will enrich your exploration of this important topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-background&#34;&gt;Historical background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan, a vast and diverse land located at the crossroads of Asia and Europe, boasts a complex historical tapestry shaped by various civilizations, empires, and nomadic cultures. The region&amp;rsquo;s history stretches back millennia, with evidence of human presence dating as far as the Paleolithic era. Over the centuries, Kazakhstan&amp;rsquo;s strategic location contributed to its role as a cross-cultural hub and a site of interactions between East and West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During antiquity, various nomadic societies, such as the Saka, Scythians, and Xiongnu, inhabited the steppes of what is now Kazakhstan. These nomadic cultures engaged in trade, herding, and seasonal migrations, leaving their mark on the region&amp;rsquo;s cultural and archaeological landscape. In the Sixth century, Turkic groups moving west from present-day Mongolia established dominance in the area, and various Turkic empires and peoples played a role over the following centuries. In the Middle Ages, the Silk Road traversed through Kazakhstan, connecting it to global trade routes and fostering cultural exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Islam reached the current region of Kazakhstan in the Eighth century. At the northernmost edge of Muslim expansion, the region’s inhabitants absorbed Islam to varying degrees, with southern and sedentary populations adopting more elements of “mainstream” Islam, while more northern and nomadic groups retained more of their original beliefs such as Tengrism.  These nomadic groups included those identified as the origin of the ethnic Kazakhs.  For a Kazakh perspective on this evolution, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://e-history.kz/en/e-resources/show/13455&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Islam in Kazakhstan&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 13th century, the Mongol Empire, led by Genghis Khan and his successors, exerted influence over the region, influencing its political dynamics and demographics, primarily through the longer-lived Khanate of the Golden Horde, a Muslim Turkic stateLater, the rise of the Kazakh Khanate in the 15th century led by Kerei Khan and Janibek Khan marked the emergence of a cohesive Kazakh identity. The Kazakh Khanate&amp;rsquo;s territory covered much of present-day Kazakhstan and parts of neighboring countries, and it played a crucial role in resisting external powers while also maintaining trade connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, the position and rights of women within Kazakh society and culture have evolved in response to a range of factors, including nomadic traditions, religious beliefs, external influences, and social changes. Traditionally, Kazakh society was characterized by a semi-nomadic lifestyle that necessitated shared responsibilities between men and women in various aspects of daily life, such as herding, household tasks, and child-rearing. Women held respected roles within their families and communities as caretakers, advisors, and contributors to the economic survival of their households.  The influence of Islam has led to conflict and compromise with traditional norms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 18th and 19th centuries saw the expansion of the Russian Empire into Central Asia, including Kazakhstan. Russian colonization led to significant demographic shifts, cultural assimilation, and land dispossession among the Kazakh population. Russian settlers were provided land, primarily in the north of the country, eventually forming up to 15% of the population. The region became a key source of raw materials and labor for the expanding empire.  As in other colonial polities, ethnic Kazakhs were in a subject position, with advancement tied to Russian assimilation and a sharp dichotomy between “modern”, Russian-dominated spheres and “traditional” spheres where Kazakh language and culture existed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan&amp;rsquo;s fate remained intertwined with larger geopolitical events, especially during the tumultuous early 20th century. It experienced revolutionary upheaval, including participation in the Russian Civil War and eventual incorporation into the Soviet Union in 1920. Soviet rule brought about significant changes to the region&amp;rsquo;s economy, society, and culture, with forced collectivization, industrialization, and state-imposed cultural policies, such as the conversion from the previous Arabic-derived script to one based on Cyrillic, shaping the lives of its inhabitants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the guise of promoting modernization and proletarian equality, the Soviet regime imposed its centralizing policies on Kazakhstan. These policies included forced collectivization of agriculture under Stalin, as in Ukraine leading to widespread famines (the larger of which is known as Asharshylyk/Ашаршылық or the Goloshchyokin genocide) and the displacement of nomadic communities. It is estimated that approximately 40 percent of ethnic Kazakhs died during this period. Additionally, the Soviet government conducted large-scale deportations, notably targeting Kazakh intellectuals and ethnic groups, to suppress dissent and further integrate the region into the Soviet framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soviet industrialization efforts exacerbated ecological degradation and disrupted local economies, reshaping the demographic fabric of the region. The establishment of nuclear test sites, including the infamous Semipalatinsk Polygon, left a lasting environmental and health crisis. Simultaneously, the Soviet narrative sought to homogenize cultures and languages, suppressing indigenous identities in favor of a Russian-centric ideology.  As a result of the aforementioned famines, Krushchev’s “Virgin Lands” program which brought more settlement to Kazakhstan’s north, and industrialization, ethnic Russians made up 42.8% of the population in 1970, with ethnic Kazakhs at 32.4%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Soviet Union&amp;rsquo;s reign over Kazakhstan, the landscape of women&amp;rsquo;s rights and societal roles underwent a multifaceted transformation. On one hand, Soviet policies sought to elevate women&amp;rsquo;s participation in education and the workforce, providing them with increased access to educational institutions and economic sectors. This engendered a notable surge in female employment and political involvement, often surpassing the levels seen in many Western countries at the time. However, this veneer of gender equality often concealed underlying issues, as women&amp;rsquo;s professional pursuits often carried the additional weight of maintaining domestic responsibilities, fostering a duality that impacted their overall well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soviet policies confronted deeply rooted cultural practices, often disregarding local customs and imposing a homogenized framework of gender relations. The Soviet regime, while ostensibly advocating for gender equality, often employed a top-down approach that failed to recognize the intricacies of local culture and history. The push for women&amp;rsquo;s participation in the workforce, education, and politics employed a “civilizing mission,&amp;quot; framing Soviet ideals as superior and traditional Kazakh values as primitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dissolution of the Soviet Union in 1991 marked a pivotal moment in Kazakhstan&amp;rsquo;s history, as it gained independence and embarked on the path of nation-building, including greater emphasis on Kazakh language and identity. Outmigration of ethnic Russians and Kazakh growth have led to ethnic Kazakhs being 70.4% of the population as of 2021, with ethnic Russians at 15.5% and other ethnicities also in decline. The complex relationship of Kazakh and Russian culture must be seen against this long and tangled historic background. Today, Kazakhstan continues to navigate its unique identity as a multicultural, multiethnic, and geopolitically significant nation, balancing its historical legacies with contemporary challenges and opportunities on the global stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;womens-rights-in-kazakhstan&#34;&gt;Women&amp;rsquo;s Rights in Kazakhstan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women in independent Kazakhstan have made notable strides in various fields, including education, employment, and political representation. The country has made significant gains in gender parity in education and has seen an increase in the number of women in the workforce, including leadership positions. However, traditional gender roles and societal expectations continue to influence many aspects of women&amp;rsquo;s lives, particularly in rural areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite legal provisions for gender equality, issues such as domestic violence, human trafficking, and child marriage persist. Activists and NGOs have been working to raise awareness and address these challenges, pushing for stronger legal enforcement and support systems for women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lgbtqia-rights-in-kazakhstan&#34;&gt;LGBTQIA+ Rights in Kazakhstan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LGBTQIA+ community in Kazakhstan has faced significant societal challenges due to prevailing conservative attitudes and limited legal protections. Same-sex relationships are not recognized, and there is no legal recognition of same-sex marriage or civil partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public LGBTQIA+ events and demonstrations have often faced opposition or been restricted by authorities. Discrimination, harassment, and violence against LGBTQIA+ individuals have been reported, and social stigma remains a barrier to open expression of one&amp;rsquo;s sexual orientation or gender identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efforts by LGBTQIA+ activists to promote awareness, education, and acceptance have met with resistance from some segments of society. However, despite these challenges, there have been pockets of progress as advocacy groups continue to work towards greater visibility, understanding, and protection for the LGBTQIA+ community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methodology-note&#34;&gt;Methodology note&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data gathering methodology employed a comprehensive and multifaceted approach, utilizing a diverse array of sources to compile gendered data pertaining to Kazakhstan. The process involved a systematic exploration of open-source information, encompassing data from state institutions, social media platforms, international and regional non-governmental organizations (INGOs), local NGOs, and a spectrum of media outlets, ranging from independent sources to those affiliated with the state. Each source underwent meticulous evaluation to ensure its relevance and reliability in terms of containing data related to gender and sexuality. This inclusive approach enabled a holistic view of Kazakhstan&amp;rsquo;s gender landscape, encompassing a broad range of perspectives and transcending official narratives. This methodological strategy facilitates a comprehensive understanding of gender dynamics within the country, leveraging the diversity of sources to enhance the collected data and contribute to a well-rounded analytical framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-social-media-and-digital-ethnographies&#34;&gt;Statement on social media and digital ethnographies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the realm of Central Asian studies, the emergence of social media has brought forth a dynamic and invaluable resource for researchers seeking to comprehend the region&amp;rsquo;s cultural, social, and political landscape. Social media platforms offer an unfiltered window into the lives, opinions, and interactions of individuals across Central Asia, transcending geographical boundaries and providing a real-time connection to the region&amp;rsquo;s contemporary realities. Through platforms like Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Telegram, and YouTube, researchers can gain access to a diverse array of voices, including local activists, artists, scholars, and ordinary citizens, who share their perspectives on everything from cultural traditions to current events. This digital ethnography enriches our understanding of regional identities, societal shifts, and emerging grassroots movements. By harnessing the power of social media as a research tool, researchers are empowered to capture the nuances and complexities of Central Asian societies in ways that traditional academic sources may struggle to capture, thus fostering a more comprehensive and authentic portrayal of the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-lgbtqia-issues-in-kazakhstan&#34;&gt;Statement on LGBTQIA+ issues in Kazakhstan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gathering data on LGBTQIA+ communities in Kazakhstan is a nuanced and intricate process, reflective of the challenges these communities face in a society where issues of sexuality and gender identity often remain sensitive or stigmatized. The compiled data, while providing valuable insights, may not capture the complete scope of LGBTQIA+ experiences due to the vulnerability and limited visibility that these communities navigate. Discrimination, social stigma, and legal barriers contribute to a hesitancy among LGBTQIA+ individuals to openly share their identities and experiences, leading to underrepresentation in many data sources. Consequently, the available data should be interpreted with the understanding that it might not fully reflect the diversity and complexities of LGBTQIA+ communities in Kazakhstan. Acknowledging these limitations is essential for a nuanced appreciation of the challenges and aspirations of these communities, fostering a more empathetic and informed discourse around LGBTQIA+ rights and well-being in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;archives&#34;&gt;Archives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/kz_national_archive/&#34;&gt;National Archive of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;: The National Archive is a central repository for historical documents in Kazakhstan. It likely contains a variety of materials related to women&amp;rsquo;s history, including official documents, photographs, and records of women&amp;rsquo;s organizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/kz_research_institute_of_culture/&#34;&gt;Kazakh Research Institute of Culture&lt;/a&gt;: This institute may have documents, publications, and research related to cultural aspects of women&amp;rsquo;s history in Kazakhstan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaznu.kz/en/&#34;&gt;Kazakh National University Libraries&lt;/a&gt;: University libraries, such as those at Al-Farabi Kazakh National University or other academic institutions, may hold collections related to women&amp;rsquo;s studies, gender studies, and social history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://csmrk.kz/index.php/en/&#34;&gt;Central State Museum of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;: This museum may house exhibits and archival materials related to the history of Kazakhstan, which could include information about women&amp;rsquo;s roles and contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academic-journals&#34;&gt;Academic journals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some notable journals that have published research on gender and sexuality in Central Asia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/journals/ccas20&#34;&gt;Central Asian Survey&lt;/a&gt;: This journal covers a wide range of topics related to Central Asia, including gender and social issues. It often features articles that explore gender dynamics, women&amp;rsquo;s roles, and cultural aspects of the region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brill.com/view/journals/caa/caa-overview.xml&#34;&gt;Central Asian Affairs&lt;/a&gt;: This journal covers political, economic, and social issues in Central Asia, including articles that touch on gender and social dynamics in the region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brill.com/view/journals/inas/inas-overview.xml&#34;&gt;Inner Asia&lt;/a&gt;: While broader in scope, this journal occasionally publishes articles that delve into gender and sexuality issues in Inner Asia, which includes parts of Central Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/journals/cgpc&#34;&gt;Gender, Place &amp;amp; Culture: A Journal of Feminist Geography&lt;/a&gt;: Although not exclusive to Central Asia, this journal publishes research on gender, place, and culture from a feminist perspective, and some articles may address gender issues in the region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/journals/cdeb20&#34;&gt;Journal of Contemporary Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/a&gt;: This journal covers a range of topics related to the region, including gender and sexuality. It might feature articles that discuss gender dynamics and societal changes in Central Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Created 2023-10-15, updated 2023-11-02&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: Uzbekistan Gender Research Guide</title>
      <link>/guides/uzbekistan/uzbekistan_gender_research_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/uzbekistan/uzbekistan_gender_research_guide/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to  Uzbekistan’s Gender Data Research Guide, a resource designed to illuminate the multifaceted dimensions of this crucial topic within the unique cultural and historical context of Uzbekistan. As a nation embedded in the heart of Central Asia, Uzbekistan has a rich tapestry of traditions, customs, and sociopolitical influences that have shaped the experiences of its people in relation to gender and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide has been carefully curated to serve as a valuable tool for scholars, students, researchers, activists, and anyone keen to explore the intricate dynamics of gender and sexuality within Uzbekistan. We hope to enable users of this guide to develop a deeper and more nuanced understanding of how these constructs are created, perceived, and navigated in this diverse and rapidly evolving society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our guide not only provides access to a wide array of academic sources, official databases, articles, books, and multimedia materials, but it also contextualizes the historical, social, and contemporary forces that have shaped the discourse around gender and sexuality in Uzbekistan. We invite you to explore topics such as the historical roles of women in Uzbek society, the evolving legal landscape concerning gender rights and sexual orientation, the challenges faced by LGBTQ+ individuals, and the intersectionality of gender with other identity markers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this guide, we aim to facilitate critical inquiry, promote cross-cultural awareness, and foster informed dialogue on these vital issues. Whether you are embarking on an academic research project, seeking to expand your knowledge, or simply curious about the diverse experiences of Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s people, this resource will empower you to begin the process of navigating the complex terrain of gender and sexuality in Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-background&#34;&gt;Historical background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uzbekistan’s central location, surrounded by landlocked countries and serving as a crossroads, boasts a rich and complex history that has been shaped by a diverse array of empires, cultures, and influences over the centuries. Throughout its history, the position and rights of women in Uzbekistan have been influenced by its societal norms, religious traditions, and the ruling powers of different eras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The region that is now Uzbekistan has been inhabited for thousands of years, with evidence of ancient civilizations dating back to the Bronze Age. One of the most notable ancient cultures in the region was the Sogdian civilization, known for its trade along the Silk Road. While the roles of women in these ancient societies varied, women often played important roles in trade, agriculture, and even religious practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 8th century, the region came under Arab control and was subsequently influenced by Islamic culture and religion. Islamic teachings granted women certain rights, such as the right to inherit property and engage in economic activities. However, the interpretation and application of these rights varied across different regions and communities within Uzbekistan. In the 13th century, the Mongol Empire, under the leadership of Genghis Khan and his successors, swept through Central Asia, including Uzbekistan, bringing it under Mongol rule. This period saw a blending of cultures and the development of trade along the Silk Road. Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s strategic location on the Silk Road made it a vibrant hub for trade and cultural exchange for centuries, with caravanserais and cities like Samarkand, Bukhara, and Khiva prospering.  The ancient trade cities of Samarkand and Bukhara have a large Tajik minority reflecting the Persian dominance of trade, while the Ozbek khans who rose to political power in the early 1500s and give their name to country are of nomadic Turkic origin.  The Karakalpaks, living in the Western region, remain a distinct ethnic group, speaking a language closer to Kazakh than standard Uzbek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian imperialism made its significant incursions into Central Asia in the late 19th century, gradually expanding its control over the region. Although the khanates and emirates in what is now Uzbekistan were among the last to cede control (Bukhara 1866, Kokhand 1868, Khiva 1873), Russian domination was soon complete.. The conquest was marked by a combination of military force, political maneuvering, and economic exploitation.  The city of Tashkent, as the terminus of the only rail connection from Russia into the region until the completion of the Turkestan-Siberia (Turksib) railway in 1930, and as the provincial capital, grew rapidly to outpace other cities.  Its growth reinforced by deportations and the transfer of Soviet industry to the city far from front lines during World War II, it remains the largest city in Central Asia to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian colonial rule in Uzbekistan ushered in a period of profound change and upheaval. The indigenous social, economic, and political structures were disrupted, and the local population faced widespread discrimination and subjugation under Russian rule. The imposition of colonial governance, coupled with the extraction of resources, such as the emphasis on cotton production to replace American imports interrupted by the US Civil War, disrupted traditional ways of life and led to economic exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation evolved with the establishment of the Soviet Union in 1922. Uzbekistan, like other Central Asian republics, became part of the Soviet sphere of influence. While the Soviet regime introduced modernization and industrialization, it did so under a coercive and centralized system, including the forced unveiling of women. This often meant that the interests of the indigenous population were secondary to Moscow&amp;rsquo;s priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soviet colonialism in Uzbekistan can be characterized by several key aspects. First, it entailed the forced collectivization of agriculture, which disrupted traditional farming practices and caused severe social and economic dislocation. In particular the emphasis on the water-intensive and labor-intensive crop of cotton ultimately led to both the drying up of the Aral Sea and environmental pollution in Karakalpakstan and the ongoing use of periodic forced labor (corvée) to pick cotton, particularly impacting women and children. Second, the Soviet authorities implemented a policy of Russification, which aimed to undermine local cultures and languages in favor of Russian dominance. The traditional Arabic script used to write the Uzbek language since around 1000 AD was transitioned to the Cyrillic alphabet by 1940. Furthermore, Uzbekistan, like other Soviet republics, experienced repression, censorship, and human rights abuses under the Soviet regime. Dissent was met with harsh penalties, and the local population had limited autonomy over their political and economic affairs.  The interaction of the Soviet economic system and distorted political regime with the coercive economic sector based on cotton led to notable corruption and scandal that by the 1980s revealed major problems with the Soviet state more generally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the period of Soviet colonization, Uzbekistan experienced significant changes in women&amp;rsquo;s rights as a result of the policies and ideologies of the Soviet government. Positive developments included increased access to education for women, enabling them to pursue careers in fields such as medicine and engineering. Legal reforms theoretically granted women equal rights with men, including the right to vote and work in various professions, while also aiming to eliminate discriminatory practices. Additionally, economic opportunities for women expanded, contributing to their financial independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there were negative aspects to these changes. Traditional societal norms often resisted the shift toward gender equality, with many families continuing to expect women to fulfill traditional roles as homemakers and mothers. This divergence between legal rights and societal expectations created a complex dynamic. Moreover, the so-called &amp;ldquo;double burden&amp;rdquo; emerged as women were required to balance professional careers with domestic responsibilities. Despite legal equality, women&amp;rsquo;s representation in higher political positions remained limited, reflecting the predominantly male-dominated political landscape. The promotion of Soviet values sometimes clashed with Uzbek cultural traditions, leading to perceptions of cultural disruption and the potential erosion of traditional gender roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uzbekistan gained independence from the Soviet Union in 1991 following its dissolution.Islam Karimov, who had been the First Secretary of the Communist Party, became the country&amp;rsquo;s first president and ruled until his death in 2016.   While remaining a centralized authoritarian state with major crises (for example, the Andijan massacre where hundreds of protesters were killed), Uzbekistan has evolved culturally.  The Cyrillic script has been transitioned to Latin, and a cultural identity is being built around the Uzbek language and the grand historical relics of the Timurid era (Amir Timur, who was Turkic, but not strictly speaking an Uzbek ruler).  Uzbekistan is the most populous of the countries covered here, with more of a farming and agricultural population than most, and remains relatively low income.  Its size and central position mean that it will continue to have a complex relationship with other countries in the region, politically and culturally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;womens-rights-in-uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Women’s rights in Uzbekistan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uzbek women have made notable advancements in education and workforce participation over recent years. Many women are actively involved in various professions, including healthcare, education, and government. However, traditional gender roles continue to exert significant influence over many aspects of Uzbek society. These roles often translate into disparities in political representation and access to high-ranking decision-making positions. While women have made significant inroads in some sectors, they remain underrepresented in key leadership roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domestic violence remains a critical issue in Uzbekistan. Cultural norms, coupled with limited awareness and resources, create hurdles in effectively combating this problem. While the Uzbek government has taken steps to promote gender equality and address violence against women through legislative measures, the consistent enforcement and implementation of these laws remain a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these challenges, there are active women&amp;rsquo;s rights activists and organizations in Uzbekistan working diligently to raise awareness about gender issues, empower women, and advocate for meaningful change. Their efforts are crucial in promoting gender equality and challenging deeply ingrained societal norms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lgbtqia-rights-in-uzbekistan&#34;&gt;LGBTQIA+ Rights in Uzbekistan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uzbekistan maintains a conservative stance on LGBTQIA+ rights, making the situation for LGBTQIA+ individuals particularly challenging. Homosexuality is illegal in Uzbekistan and is punishable by imprisonment. Thus, the country lacks legal recognition or protection for same-sex relationships, leaving LGBTQIA+ individuals vulnerable to discrimination and harassment. They face societal stigmatization and often keep their sexual orientation concealed to avoid discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LGBTQIA+ community in Uzbekistan operates in a climate where open advocacy or activism for LGBTQIA+ rights is risky due to societal and legal constraints. Authorities have at times taken repressive measures against LGBTQIA+ individuals and organizations, and there is limited room for public discourse on LGBTQIA+ rights. While there may be pockets of support and underground LGBTQIA+ networks, the overall environment for LGBTQIA+ individuals in Uzbekistan remains challenging, emphasizing the need for greater recognition, protection, and understanding of their rights and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methodology-note&#34;&gt;Methodology note&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data gathering methodology employed a comprehensive and multifaceted approach, utilizing a diverse array of sources to compile gendered data pertaining to Uzbekistan. The process involved a systematic exploration of open-source information, encompassing data from state institutions, social media platforms, international and regional non-governmental organizations (INGOs), local NGOs, and a spectrum of media outlets, ranging from independent sources to those affiliated with the state. Each source underwent careful evaluation to ensure its relevance and reliability in terms of containing data related to gender and sexuality. This inclusive approach enabled a holistic view of Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s gender landscape, encompassing a broad range of perspectives and transcending official narratives. This methodological strategy facilitates a comprehensive understanding of gender dynamics within the country, leveraging the diversity of sources to enhance the collected data and contribute to a well-rounded analytical framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-social-media-and-digital-ethnographies&#34;&gt;Statement on social media and digital ethnographies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the realm of Central Asian studies, the emergence of social media has brought forth a dynamic and invaluable resource for researchers seeking to comprehend the region&amp;rsquo;s cultural, social, and political landscape. Social media platforms offer an unfiltered window into the lives, opinions, and interactions of individuals across Central Asia, transcending geographical boundaries and providing a real-time connection to the region&amp;rsquo;s contemporary realities. Through platforms like Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Telegram, and YouTube, researchers can gain access to a diverse array of voices, including local activists, artists, scholars, and ordinary citizens, who share their perspectives on everything from cultural traditions to current events. This digital ethnography enriches our understanding of regional identities, societal shifts, and emerging grassroots movements. By harnessing the power of social media as a research tool, researchers are empowered to capture the nuances and complexities of Central Asian societies in ways that traditional academic sources may struggle to capture, thus fostering a more comprehensive and authentic portrayal of the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statement-on-lgbtqia-issues-in-uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Statement on LGBTQIA+ issues in Uzbekistan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of gathering data on LGBTQIA+ communities in Uzbekistan is inherently complex and challenging. Uzbekistan, like many countries in the region, maintains conservative social norms and legal restrictions on LGBTQIA+ rights, which create a climate of fear and secrecy for this community. Consequently, the compiled data may not fully reflect the true extent of LGBTQIA+ issues and experiences in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary factors contributing to this complexity include the vulnerability and low visibility of LGBTQIA+ individuals in Uzbekistan. Many LGBTQIA+ individuals fear discrimination, violence, and legal repercussions, which forces them to conceal their sexual orientation and gender identity. This fear of exposure often deters individuals from participating in surveys, interviews, or any form of data collection that could potentially reveal their LGBTQIA+ identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, societal stigma and discrimination further contribute to the invisibility of LGBTQIA+ communities, as they are often excluded from mainstream discourse, health services, and legal protections. This isolation makes it difficult for researchers and organizations to reach out to LGBTQIA+ individuals and gather accurate information about their needs, experiences, and challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;archives&#34;&gt;Archives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the availability and accessibility of archival materials may vary, and it&amp;rsquo;s advisable to contact these institutions directly or check their websites for the most up-to-date information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/national_library_uz/&#34;&gt;National Library of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;: The National Library of Uzbekistan, located in Tashkent, may hold historical documents and manuscripts related to women&amp;rsquo;s history in Uzbekistan. They have a substantial collection of books, manuscripts, and archival materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/institute_of_oriental_studies/&#34;&gt;Institute of Oriental Studies of the Academy of Sciences of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;: This research institute may have historical research and publications related to the role of women in Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s history, culture, and society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/family_and_womens_committee/&#34;&gt;Family and Women&amp;rsquo;s Committee of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;: The Women&amp;rsquo;s Committee of Uzbekistan may have archives or resources related to women&amp;rsquo;s issues, achievements, and contributions in Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://library.nuu.uz/&#34;&gt;University Libraries&lt;/a&gt;: Universities in Uzbekistan, such as the National University of Uzbekistan, may have specialized collections and archives related to women&amp;rsquo;s history and gender studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academic-journals&#34;&gt;Academic journals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some notable journals that have published research on gender and sexuality in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/journals/ccas20&#34;&gt;Central Asian Survey&lt;/a&gt;: This journal covers a wide range of topics related to Central Asia, including gender and social issues. It often features articles that explore gender dynamics, women&amp;rsquo;s roles, and cultural aspects of the region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brill.com/view/journals/caa/caa-overview.xml&#34;&gt;Central Asian Affairs&lt;/a&gt;: This journal covers political, economic, and social issues in Central Asia, including articles that touch on gender and social dynamics in the region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brill.com/view/journals/inas/inas-overview.xml&#34;&gt;Inner Asia&lt;/a&gt;: While broader in scope, this journal occasionally publishes articles that delve into gender and sexuality issues in Inner Asia, which includes parts of Central Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/journals/cgpc&#34;&gt;Gender, Place &amp;amp; Culture: A Journal of Feminist Geography&lt;/a&gt;: Although not exclusive to Central Asia, this journal publishes research on gender, place, and culture from a feminist perspective, and some articles may address gender issues in the region.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/journals/cdeb20&#34;&gt;Journal of Contemporary Central and Eastern Europe&lt;/a&gt;: This journal covers a range of topics related to the region, including gender and sexuality. It might feature articles that discuss gender dynamics and societal changes in Central Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Created 2023-10-15, updated 2023-11-02&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Values Survey (KZ)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_values_survey_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_values_survey_kz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSOnline.jsp&#34;&gt;World Values Survey&lt;/a&gt; studies social, political, economic, religious and cultural values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is included in waves 6 (2010-2014) and 7 (2017-2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some relevant questions include questions about women’s leadership skills, women’s rights, familial fiscal responsibilities, acceptance of homosexuality, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sample size is 1,500 and 1,276 in waves 6 and 7 respectively. A lot of questions are missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Values Survey (UZ)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_values_survey_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_values_survey_uz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSOnline.jsp&#34;&gt;World Values Survey&lt;/a&gt; studies social, political, economic, religious and cultural values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some relevant questions include questions about women&amp;rsquo;s leadership skills, women&amp;rsquo;s rights, familial fiscal responsibilities, acceptance of homosexuality, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uzbekistan is included in wave 6 (2010-2014). Sample size for Uzbekistan is 1487.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Akimat of the city of Astana</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/astana/about?lang=en&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Astana&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the akimat (regional administration) of the capital city Astana. Contains official documents, press releases, and statistical data of the city. Offers latest news about the capital’s governance. The information is divided into several directions, including familial and demographic policies, culture, civil society, youth, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Family and Women&#39;s Committee of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/family_and_womens_committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/family_and_womens_committee/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wcu.uz/ru/&#34;&gt;Family and Women&amp;rsquo;s Committee of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is a state institution aimed at protecting women&amp;rsquo;s civil, labor, and human rights. It publishes reports and shares other updates on issues of women and family in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Institute of Oriental Studies of the Academy of Sciences</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/institute_of_oriental_studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/institute_of_oriental_studies/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1943, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://beruni.uz/ru/glavnaya/struktura-instituta/item/329-o/&#39;92zr-fa.html&#34;&gt;Institute of Oriental Studies of the Academy of Sciences&lt;/a&gt; is a Tashkent-based research institution that specializes on collection of manuscripts. At the present time, its manuscript collection contains about 26,000 volumes and includes works written in Uzbek, Arabic, Persian, Tajik, Urdu, Azeri, Ottoman Turkish, Tatar, Turkmen, Uighur and other languages.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: National Archive of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kz_national_archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kz_national_archive/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Opened in 2006, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ulttykarhiv.kz/en/&#34;&gt;National Archive of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is a central repository for historical documents in Kazakhstan. It is located in Astana.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kazakh Research Institute of Culture</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kz_research_institute_of_culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kz_research_institute_of_culture/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;First founded in 1934, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cultural.kz/en/&#34;&gt;Kazakh Research Institute of Culture&lt;/a&gt; is a research center for art, culture, history, and archaeology. Its mission is to &amp;ldquo;conduct an in-depth systemic analysis in the sphere of culture in accordance with the Conception of cultural policy of the Republic of Kazakhstan, integration into world cultural space and effective international cooperation.&amp;rdquo; The institute is located in Almaty.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: National Library of Uzbekistan named after Alisher Navoi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/national_library_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/national_library_uz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Originally founded in 1870, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.natlib.uz/&#34;&gt;National Library of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; received its current name in 2002. It is the main state book depository for national and foreign press, information and research institution, and a methodological center for all libraries of the country. The National Library is located in Tashkent.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Museum of Contemporary Women&#39;s and Queer Art of Central Asia (MoFA&#43;)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mofa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/mofa/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://femmuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA+)&lt;/a&gt; is a museum spotlighting feminist and queer artists from Central Asia and advocating for the rights and freedoms of women and LGBTQIA+ community. MoFA+ hosts solo and group exhibits, workshops, and events. The museum also grants art fellowships and is involved in documentary filmmaking.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Adil Qala</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adil_qala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/adil_qala/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adilqala.kz/&#34;&gt;Adil Qala&lt;/a&gt; is a project on social justice in the field of urban planning and development. It aims to create a platform for a &amp;ldquo;broad public dialogue about the priority of the human dimension in urban policies and practices.&amp;rdquo; Adil Qala hosts public discussions and educational programs, including on the topic of LGBTQIA+ safe spaces and visibility and safety of women in urban settings.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Against Frotterizm</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/against_frotterizm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/against_frotterizm/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/frotterizm.uz/&#34;&gt;Against Frotterizm&lt;/a&gt; is a social campaign project based on voluntary involved. It is combating frotteurism and harassment of women in Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s public transport. The project aims to increase public awareness of the issue, develop mechanisms to detect cases of harassment in public transport, and develop instructions on what to do and how to protect victims if they are harassed on public transport.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Amerika Ovozi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/amerika_ovozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/amerika_ovozi/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amerikaovozi.com/&#34;&gt;Amerika Ovozi (Voice of America)&lt;/a&gt; is an international multimedia agency launched in 1942 and funded by the US Congress. Its charter was founded in 1976. Since 2016, Amerika Ovozi legally established itself as an independent media with a neutral coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ariadna</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ariadna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ariadna/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ariadna.media&#34;&gt;Ariadna&lt;/a&gt; is a Central Asia media dedicated to covering the art scene of the region using accessible language. It provides reviews, editorials, and audioguides.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bashtan Bashta</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bashtan_bashta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bashtan_bashta/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@bashtanbashta/&#34;&gt;Bashtan Bashta&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bashtan_bashta/&#34;&gt;a social media project&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to raising civil consciousness in Kyrgyzstan. It also covers news and politics of other Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bulbul Podcasts</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bulbul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bulbul/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bulbulpodcasts/&#34;&gt;Bulbul Podcasts&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast studio that produces shows about Kazakhstani women&amp;rsquo;s histories and stories, as well as culture and music.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Crossroads Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/crossroads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/crossroads/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crossroads-ca.org/&#34;&gt;Crossroads Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; is a Bishkek-based non-profit research institute with an aim to &amp;ldquo;promote better understanding of political, economic and security affairs of Central Asia and its wider Eurasian neighborhood.&amp;rdquo; It publishes analytical commentary and research reports.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Daryo</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/daryo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/daryo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://daryo.uz&#34;&gt;Daryo&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news media offering coverage of politics, economics, sport, and culture in Uzbekistan and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Dope Soz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@DOPESOZ/&#34;&gt;Dope Soz&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series offering discussions and conversations about social, historical, political, and cultural events and discourses.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Education Community</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/edu_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/edu_community/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 in partnership with USAID and Eurasia Foundation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/edu.community.kz/&#34;&gt;Education Community&lt;/a&gt; is an activist project that aims to connect gender and sexuality minorities to provide them with opportunities for personal, psychological, and legal support and development. Education Community creates and shares projects and programs advocating for diversity, inclusivity, and tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: European Sex Workers Rights Alliance</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eswra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eswra/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002 under the name of International Committee for Sex Workers in Europe (ICRSE), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eswalliance.org/&#34;&gt;European Sex Workers Rights Alliance&lt;/a&gt; is a sex worker-led network representing more than 100 organizations in 30 countries across Europe and Central Asia. One of its recent publication is &amp;ldquo;Sex work &amp;amp; racism: the impact of structural racism on racialized sex workers in Europe and Central Asia&amp;rdquo; report.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: FemAgora</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/femagora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/femagora/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://femagora.org/&#34;&gt;FemAgora&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to fostering transnational feminist solidarity in Central Asia. The organization is involved in organization of Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march and the issue of employment of transgender people. FemAgora hosts annual FemAgora Central Asian festival for those involved in feminist, gender-sensitive, and/or women-led work.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminist Translocalities</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminisms.co/&#34;&gt;Feminist Translocalities&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots transnational feminist organization aiming to bring together and support feminist and LGBTQ+ activists from Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia. The organization publishes magazine articles and zines, hosts events, and engages in other various projects. Although the website describes the organization as primarily focused on Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia, it frequently publishes works by Central Asian authors.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminita</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminita/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminita.kz/&#34;&gt;Feminita&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots queer feminist collective. Feminita aims to create and strengthen the rights of women and activist communities and empower the most oppressed groups of Kazakhstani population (lesbian, bisexual, queer, women with disabilities, women in sex work). Currently, the organization works on three research projects: assessment of needs of LBQ women; health conditions of LBQT women and transgender men; and sexual wellness of LBQ women. Methodology and research design sections are included in the first two project reports. The reports are available in Russian with occasional translation to Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Human Rights Focus</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/human_rights_focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/human_rights_focus/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by USAID and Kazakhstan Public Association &amp;ldquo;Dignity&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://humanrightsfocus.kz/&#34;&gt;Human Rights Focus&lt;/a&gt; is a project mobilizing and organizing various groups, including human rights defenders, NGOs, civil society leaders, and others, for empowering and encouraging women in Kazakhstan to participate more fully in public administration and decision-making and for prevention of bullying in Kazakhstani schools. Human Rights Focus offers trainings and workshops to Kazakhstani teachers, hosts conferences, and provides educational content on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ILGA-Europe</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ilga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ilga/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ilga-europe.org/&#34;&gt;ILGA-Europe&lt;/a&gt; is an International NGO advocating for the protection of LGBTI people and uniting over 600 organizations from 54 countries across Europe and Central Asia. ILGA conducts its work through resourcing and connecting communities, driving political change, and amplifying voices. Its mission is to provide a solid foundation for activists and organizations. ILGA publishes reports on the protection of rights of LGBTI people in Central Asia, specifically related to violence and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Invisible Rainbow Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/invisible_rainbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/invisible_rainbow/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/invisible_rainbow_union/&#34;&gt;Invisible Rainbow Union&lt;/a&gt; is a social media community of queer ethnic minorities from Central Asia and Russia. The media focuses on preserving oral histories of the LGBTQIA+ community.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kaz Fem</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kazfem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kazfem/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/kaz_fem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots feminist organization dedicated to research and development of feminist theory in Kazakhstan. One of the leading organizations behind Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march. Available mostly in Russian with occasional material in Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kibhr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kibhr/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bureau.kz/&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law (KIBHR)&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani bureau of human rights. It engages in human rights advocacy, shares relevant reports, and engages in human rights monitoring in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kok.team</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kok.team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kok.team/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017 and dissolved in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kok.team/&#34;&gt;Kok.team&lt;/a&gt; was a grassroots LGBT organization dedicated to providing information on the LGBT issues in Kazakh. Digital archive contains articles, podcasts and videos of Kazakhstani LGBT  community. Available in Kazakh and Russian with occasional translation to English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Legal Policy Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/lprc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/lprc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2008 by a group of Kazakhstani lawyers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lprc.kz/&#34;&gt;Legal Policy Research Center (LPRC)&lt;/a&gt; is a non-political, independent research institute promoting the principle of the rule of law and liberal values through the implementation of research, publishing and educational activities in the field of legal policy. Its mission is to strengthen democratic values through effective legal reforms. Its projects include promoting anti-discrimination agenda and combating sexual harassment.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Loyiha</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/loyiha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/loyiha/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@loyiha_project/&#34;&gt;Loyiha&lt;/a&gt; is a video podcast platform designed to &amp;ldquo;inspire and motivate women.&amp;rdquo; It platforms several women-centered podcast series that provide educational content on various career fields, from marketing to education, as well as information on such topics as misogyny, infertility, ecology, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Official Website of the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/president_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/president_website/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://president.uz/&#34;&gt;Official Website of the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; publishes updates, media, infographics, and legislative documents.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qalampir</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qalampir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qalampir/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://qalampir.uz/&#34;&gt;Qalampir&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news and analytics publication with an aim to achieve transparent and quality informational space in the media sector of Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qara Magan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qara.magan/&#34;&gt;Qara Magan&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project is dedicated to visibility and storytelling of the LGBTQ+ community of Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: QAZAQUEER</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qazaqueer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qazaqueer/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qazaqueer/&#34;&gt;QAZAQUEER&lt;/a&gt; is a social media project on the lives of the LGBTQIA+ community in Kazakhstan. It primarily produces content in Kazakh and offers educational resources on queer identity, relationships, and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Queernyi squirt</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mira Ungarova and Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://podcast.kz/1657513218/info&#34;&gt;Queernyi Squirt&lt;/a&gt; is an 18+ podcast dedicated to inclusive LGBTQIA+ sex education in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Repost</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/repost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/repost/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://repost.uz/&#34;&gt;Repost&lt;/a&gt; is a Russian-language news media in Uzbekistan. It covers local and world affairs, as well as lifestyle and cultural events.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Right Now</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/right-now/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 in association with the US Embassy in Kazakhstan and the National Alumi Network of US programs graduates, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/rightnow.kz/&#34;&gt;Right Now&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform promoting awareness of legal rights in Kazakhstan. It offers online lectures on various topics, including violence against women and children.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ruyo Journal</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ruyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ruyo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruyojournal.com&#34;&gt;Ruyo Journal&lt;/a&gt; is an artist-led digital media focused on critical discourse on art, film, and theory in Central Asia. Its goal is to &amp;ldquo;support the development of a flourishing cultural scene in Central Asia by providing a platform for thoughtful and engaging discussions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Sof.uz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/sof/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2016, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sof.uz/&#34;&gt;Sof.uz&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news publication designed to deliver news to a wider audience using accessible language.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Spot</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/spot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/spot/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2017 as a part of the Afisha Media company, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spot.uz/&#34;&gt;Spot&lt;/a&gt; is a news media primarily covering business and economic news in Uzbekistan. It also offers editorial pieces on the same topics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Statistics Agency under the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/statistics_agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/statistics_agency/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz/&#34;&gt;Statistics Agency under the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; publishes official statistical reports and the state&amp;rsquo;s analysis of social and economic processes.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Stop Harass</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/stop-harass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/stop-harass/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stopharass.kz/&#34;&gt;Stop Harass&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani harassment prevention and tracking website. Its mission is to &amp;ldquo;engage all residents of Kazakhstan in creating an environment that is intolerant of sexual assault, harassment, stalking, catcalling, etc.&amp;rdquo; The platform allows anyone to report harassment instances either via Telegram bot or website.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: TEDxAbayStWomen</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;First held in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tedxabaystwomen/&#34;&gt;TEDxAbayStWomen&lt;/a&gt; is a noncommercial conference on gender equality usually held in Almaty, Kazakhstan. Next conference is expected to be held in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: The Fish that changed gender (Рыба, которая сменила пол)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fish/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://beacons.ai/rybaipol&#34;&gt;the Fish that changed gender&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast project in conversation with transgender people living in Kazakhstan. It brings forward stories and experiences of transpeople. The podcast also has a presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/rybaipol/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: The Government Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uz_gov_portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/uz_gov_portal/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/&#34;&gt;The Government Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is an official website of all thing related to the government of Uzbekistan. It includes information on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/ru/&#34;&gt;gender statistics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/en/pages/government_sites&#34;&gt;a list of government bodies&amp;rsquo; websites&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/en/organizations/kind/local&#34;&gt;a list of local authorities&amp;rsquo; websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Tolk</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tolk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tolk/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@tolkkz/&#34;&gt;Tolk&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast studio and an audio-hub dedicated to researching contemporary Kazakhstani through interpersonal conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Unit </title>
      <link>/sources/sources/unit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/unit/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021 by n-ost, a Berlin-based media NGO, &lt;a href=&#34;https://unit.n-ost.org&#34;&gt;Unit&lt;/a&gt; is a crossborder community of journalists and activists from Central Asia, Eastern Europe, and South Caucasus who work on the LGBTQIA+ issues.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
