<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – civil society</title>
    <link>/tags/civil-society/</link>
    <description>Recent content in civil society on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/civil-society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Eurasia Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2004 and based in Washington, DC, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/where-we-work/asia/&#34;&gt;Eurasia Foundation&lt;/a&gt; works with international, national, and local partners for community action. The foundation has a variety of international and local donors. Areas of expertise include civil society, youth and leadership, media, governance, and [gender and marginalized communities] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&#34;&gt;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminist Translocalities</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminisms.co/&#34;&gt;Feminist Translocalities&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots transnational feminist organization aiming to bring together and support feminist and LGBTQ+ activists from Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia. The organization publishes magazine articles and zines, hosts events, and engages in other various projects. Although the website describes the organization as primarily focused on Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia, it frequently publishes works by Central Asian authors.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: OCCRP</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/occrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/occrp/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005 in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.occrp.org/&#34;&gt;Organized Crime and Corruption Reporting Project&lt;/a&gt; aims to develop and equip a global network of investigative journalists, as well as publish stories exposing crime and corruption. The project regularly covers post-Soviet and Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Prague Civil Society Centre</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2014 and based in Prague, the Czech Republic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.praguecivilsociety.org/&#34;&gt;Prague Civil Society Centre&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to enabling civic groups and journalists to connect with their communities through grant making, capacity building, and learning. The Centre is funded by governments of Sweden, the Czech Republic, the UK, and the US, as well as the European Commission, the Oak Foundation, and the Wellspring Philanthropic Fund. Focuses on Eastern Europe and Central Asia. In addition to civil society programs, the Centre publishes media and publications on various topics related to the civic groups in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Aiman Umarova School of Rights</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/aiman_umratova_school_of_rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/aiman_umratova_school_of_rights/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://womenrights.kz/&#34;&gt;Aiman Umarova School of Rights&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots informational platform focusing on the problems of women and girls from socially vulnerable background, including gender-based violence. The portal provides brief information on legislative contexts and statistical summaries on the issues of sexual violence, domestic violence, violence against children, LGBTQ rights, etc. Information is available in Kazakh and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Aiman Umarova’s Rights School</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/aiman_umarova_school_of_rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/aiman_umarova_school_of_rights/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://womenrights.kz/&#34;&gt;Aiman Umarova’s Rights School&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots informational platform focusing on the problems of women and girls from socially vulnerable background, including gender-based violence. The portal provides brief information on legislative contexts and statistical summaries on the issues of sexual violence, domestic violence, violence against children, LGBTQ rights, etc. Information is available in Kazakh and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Human Rights KZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/human_rights_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/human_rights_kz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/humanrightskz/&#34;&gt;Human Rights KZ&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to sharing domestic and international human rights information and news in Kazakh. Available on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kaz Fem</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kazfem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kazfem/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/kaz_fem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots feminist organization dedicated to research and development of feminist theory in Kazakhstan. One of the leading organizations behind Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march. Available mostly in Russian with occasional material in Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: MISK</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/misk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/misk/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1998 &lt;a href=&#34;https://misk.org.kz/&#34;&gt;MISK (Kazakhstani Informational Youth Service)&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to research on youth, monitoring youth policy legislation, and human rights training. Key projects of the organization include School of Human Rights and School of Civil Education. MISK also regularly published surveys on various social issues. Summary of survey findings include brief information on sample sizes of each survey. Available in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Oyan, Qazaqstan!</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/oyanqazaqstankz/&#34;&gt;Oyan, Qazaqstan!&lt;/a&gt; is a social movement advocating for political reforms in Kazakhstan. The organization shares news about political events, activist campaigns, organizing efforts, as well as prosecution of activists by the state authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: PaperLab</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/paperlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/paperlab/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015 and supported by the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://paperlab.kz/&#34;&gt;PaperLab&lt;/a&gt; is a public policy research organization in Kazakhstan. PaperLab publishes research, organizes public discussions, and offers training and networking opportunities to Central Asian experts. Most publications are in Kazakh and Russian and sometimes in English. PaperLab has done extensive research on sex education in Kazakhstan and frequently collaborates with other NGOs and INGOs on the topic of violence against women. Methodology note and description of sources are not always included in the publications.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Soros Kazakhstan Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1995 by the Open Society Institute, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soros.kz&#34;&gt;Soros Kazakhstan Foundation&lt;/a&gt; funds multiple scholarship programs, educational courses, and research and activist initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundation publishes research works of various organizations and authors produced with the foundation’s support and/or collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available primarily in Russian with translations into Kazakh and English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
