<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – Central Asian media</title>
    <link>/tags/central-asian-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Central Asian media on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/central-asian-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Orda</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/orda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/orda/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://orda.kz/&#34;&gt;Orda&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan, as well as journalistic investigations.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Adamdar/CA</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adamdar.ca/&#34;&gt;Adamdar/CA&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage and storytelling narratives from Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Uzbekistan, and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: CABAR</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/cabar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/cabar/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2016 and based under the Institute’s for War and Peace Reporting (IWPR) Central Asian Office, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cabar.asia/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Bureau for Analytical Reporting (CABAR)&lt;/a&gt; offers regional analytical, informational, and educational material on Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asian Analytical Network</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_asian_analytical_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_asian_analytical_network/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded on the basis of the George Washington University’s Institute for European, Russian, and Eurasian Studies (IERES), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.caa-network.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Analytical Network&lt;/a&gt; offers editorial and opinion pieces, interviews, book and publication reviews, and expert projects on politics, society, and economics of Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Current Time Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/current_time_asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/current_time_asia/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Based in Prague, Czech Republic, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.currenttime.tv/asia/&#34;&gt;Current Time Asia&lt;/a&gt; was created by the Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, a US Congress-funded broadcasting organization, with participation of Voice of America. Offers news, reports, investigations, and interviews covering Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Mediazona Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mediazona/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/mediazona/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2014 in Russia, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mediazona.ca/&#34;&gt;Mediazona Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; covers current events in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, and Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Novastan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/novastan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/novastan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2011 in Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan and based in Paris and Berlin, &lt;a href=&#34;https://novastan.org/&#34;&gt;Novastan&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, Uzbekistan, and the Uyghur region.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Voices on Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/voices_on_central_asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/voices_on_central_asia/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in collaboration with the Central Asia Program and the Central Asian Analytical Network on the basis of the George Washington University’s Institute for European, Russian, and Eurasian Studies (IERES), &lt;a href=&#34;https://voicesoncentralasia.org/&#34;&gt;Voices on Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; offers analytical pieces, research insights, policy discussions, fieldwork recollections, photos, charts, and data on Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: TAG news</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tag_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tag_news/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded first in 2008 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kaztag.kz/ru/&#34;&gt;TAG news agency&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Afghanistan, Iran, and the Silk Road region. Available in English, Kazakh, and Russian in Kazakhstan; Kyrgyz and Russian in Kyrgyzstan; Uzbek and Russian in Uzbekistan; and Tajik and Russian in Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
