<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</title>
    <link>/date_start/2018/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2018 on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 20:55:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/date_start/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FemAgora</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/femagora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/femagora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://femagora.org/&#34;&gt;FemAgora&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to fostering transnational feminist solidarity in Central Asia. The organization is involved in organization of Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march and the issue of employment of transgender people. FemAgora hosts annual FemAgora Central Asian festival for those involved in feminist, gender-sensitive, and/or women-led work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kibhr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/kibhr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bureau.kz/&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law (KIBHR)&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani bureau of human rights. It engages in human rights advocacy, shares relevant reports, and engages in human rights monitoring in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hook Report</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/hook_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/hook_report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hook.report/&#34;&gt;Hook Report&lt;/a&gt; is an independent Uzbek media offering coverage of political, economic, art, and cultural news in the country. According to its mission, Hook Report aims to bring quality news coverage using a less traditional and formal approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FemPoint</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fempoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/fempoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/fempoint_kz/&#34;&gt;FemPoint&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots organization for LBT women providing support resources and engaged in advocacy and activism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gender Economics Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/gerc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/gerc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 with the assistance of the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.narxoz.kz/research/institutes/gerc&#34;&gt;Gender Economics Research Center (GERC)&lt;/a&gt; is a research center at Narxoz University, Almaty. GERC is dedicated to development and coordination of research on gender and economy. The center publishes research articles and reports on the topics of labor market, education, COVID-19 impact, and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SVET</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/svet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/svet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://svetpf.org/&#34;&gt;SVET&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani foundation dedicated to helping survivors of gender-based violence and sharing relevant news.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tselinny Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tselinny_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/tselinny_center/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 by Kairat Boranbayev, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tselinny.org/&#34;&gt;Tselinny Center&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to studying and developing cultural scene in Kazakhstan. The center publishes educational books, hosts art exhibitions, and organizes events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uyat Emes</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uyat_emes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uyat_emes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uyatemes.kz/&#34;&gt;Uyat Emes&lt;/a&gt; is an educational site about sex and relationships for Kazakhstani teenagers and their parents. The mission of the initiative is to help young people become more literate about reproductive health and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
