<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Government on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</title>
    <link>/tags/government/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 16:22:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>National Statistics Committee of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/stat_gov_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/stat_gov_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz&#34;&gt;National Statistics Committee of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; provides fundamental economic, social, and other demographic statistics about Uzbekistan. Education, healthcare, economy, population, employment, and living standards are among the many categories of data available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statistics are available as downloadable tables in Excel format and as publications, including a special section on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/&#34;&gt;Gender Statistics&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/gender_stat_uz/&#34;&gt;also described on CAMGDP&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz/en/publications&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; include &lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/en/2020-11-09-06-11-08/women-var-men-in-uzbekistan-facts-and-figures&#34;&gt;Women and Men in Uzbekistan: Facts and Figures&lt;/a&gt;.  The &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz/en/publications/3627-statistical-yearbook-of-the-republic-of-uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Statistical Yearbook of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; and other publications are available for purchase, with only their tables of contents freely viewable. Quarterly reports and other frequently updated releases are typically freely downloadable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Data Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/data_egov_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/data_egov_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.egov.uz&#34;&gt;Open Data Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; provides over 10,000 freely downloadable datasets from more than 150 organizations on various aspects of life in Uzbekistan, including education, health, economy, population, culture, justice, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Datasets are typically available in CSV, Excel, XML, JSON, and RDF formats. Before downloading, a brief pop-up will ask the user to identify the intended use of the data (research, personal, application development, media, or other), but no registration is required.  In addition to keyword search, data can be browsed by topic or organization, and the most recent and most highly rated datasets are highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIAT Integrated Information System (Uzbekistan)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/siat_stat_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/siat_stat_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://siat.stat.uz&#34;&gt;SIAT Integrated Information System&lt;/a&gt; provides detailed statistical tables for economic and social indicators for the Republic of Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After selecting the desired indicator, data may be downloaded in Excel, CSV, PDF, JSON, or XML formats, and may also be graphed online, with downloadable images.  Either time series line charts or cartograms can be selected. Detailed metadata describes the provenance of the data and contacts for further information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The site is navigable in Uzbek, Russian, and English. Most downloads of publications and tables are in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Gender Statistics of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/gender_stat_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/gender_stat_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/&#34;&gt;Gender Statistics&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz&#34;&gt;National Statistics Committee of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; provides highlighted gender indicators on education, fertility, health, labor and employment, and more. These are downloadable in multiple formats (Excel,CSV, PDF, JSON, XML), with dates of coverage typically from the 2000s to the present. The publication &lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/en/2020-11-09-06-11-08/women-var-men-in-uzbekistan-facts-and-figures&#34;&gt;Women and Men in Uzbekistan: Facts and Figures&lt;/a&gt; is also available here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the words of the site, &amp;ldquo;Gender statistics are statistics that adequately reflect the real situation of women and men in all strategic areas in order to identify gender differences and study them systematically.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Statistical Committee of the Kyrgyz Republic</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/stat_gov_kg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/stat_gov_kg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg&#34;&gt;National Statistical Committee of the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt; provides fundamental economic, social, and other demographic statistics about Kyrgyzstan. Education, healthcare, economy, population, employment, and living standards are among the many categories of data available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statistics are available as downloadable tables in Excel format and as publications, including a special section on &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/gendernaya-statistika/&#34;&gt;Gender Statistics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Publications include the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/publications/statisticheskij-ezhegodnik-kyrgyzskoj-respubliki/&#34;&gt;Statistical Yearbook of the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/publications/publikaciya-socialnye-tendencii-kyrgyzskoj-respubliki/&#34;&gt;Social Trends of the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/publications/sbornik-zhenshiny-i-muzhchiny-kyrgyzskoj-respubliki/&#34;&gt;Women and Men in the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt;, and many other regular and special publications available for download.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caspiana</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/caspiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/caspiana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/&#34;&gt;Caspiana&lt;/a&gt;: A Digital Toolbox for Students and Scholars of Central Asia and the South Caucasus is a website created to facilitate research on the fascinating regions spreading east and west of the Caspian Sea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notably the site contains sections on &lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/exhibits/show/governance&#34;&gt;Governance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/exhibits/show/media&#34;&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/exhibits/show/statistics&#34;&gt;Statistics&lt;/a&gt; that link to major government offices and information providers. Additional material includes academic resources such as conferences and language learning links.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akimat of the city of Astana</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/astana/about?lang=en&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Astana&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the akimat (regional administration) of the capital city Astana. Contains official documents, press releases, and statistical data of the city. Offers latest news about the capital’s governance. The information is divided into several directions, including familial and demographic policies, culture, civil society, youth, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family and Women&#39;s Committee of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/family_and_womens_committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/family_and_womens_committee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wcu.uz/ru/&#34;&gt;Family and Women&amp;rsquo;s Committee of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is a state institution aimed at protecting women&amp;rsquo;s civil, labor, and human rights. It publishes reports and shares other updates on issues of women and family in the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Official Website of the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/president_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/president_website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://president.uz/&#34;&gt;Official Website of the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; publishes updates, media, infographics, and legislative documents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Agency under the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/statistics_agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/statistics_agency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz/&#34;&gt;Statistics Agency under the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; publishes official statistical reports and the state&amp;rsquo;s analysis of social and economic processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Government Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uz_gov_portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uz_gov_portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/&#34;&gt;The Government Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is an official website of all thing related to the government of Uzbekistan. It includes information on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/ru/&#34;&gt;gender statistics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/en/pages/government_sites&#34;&gt;a list of government bodies&amp;rsquo; websites&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/en/organizations/kind/local&#34;&gt;a list of local authorities&amp;rsquo; websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ministry of Employment and Poverty Reduction of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ministry_of_employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/ministry_of_employment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mehnat.uz/&#34;&gt;Ministry of Employment and Poverty Reduction of the Republic of Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; main activity areas include labor and renumeration, employment, labor protection and migration, and anti-corruption legislature. The ministry has &lt;a href=&#34;https://mehnat.uz/ru/pages/gendernoe-ravenstvo&#34;&gt;a page dedicated to gender equality&lt;/a&gt; that details the status of women in the constitution of the Republic of Uzbekistan, as well as details of latest state events related to gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan Art and Culture Development Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/acdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/acdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.acdf.uz/&#34;&gt;The Art and Culture Development Foundation of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; fosters international cooperation&#xA;and promotes the culture of Uzbekistan on the international arena. Its mission is to create an &amp;ldquo;inclusive and accessible environment in the country&amp;rsquo;s cultural institutions, contribute to renovation of museums, and to develop cultural patronage and professional training for the arts and culture sector.&amp;rdquo; It appears to be a state-affiliated organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adilet.Zan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adilet_zan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/adilet_zan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/&#34;&gt;Adilet.Zan&lt;/a&gt; is a legal information system of Regulatory Legal Acts under the Ministry of Justice Institute of Legislation and Legal Information. The database contains more than 330 thousand legal documents, including Kazakhstan’s Concept of Family and Gender Policies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ak Orda</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ak_orda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/ak_orda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.akorda.kz/&#34;&gt;Ak Orda&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, such as the constitution, state strategies and programs, and constitutional laws, as well as an archive of the documents. The website is not search friendly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akimat of the city of Almaty</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_almaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_almaty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/almaty?lang=en&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Almaty&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the akimat (regional administration) of Almaty, the largest city in Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, press releases, and statistical data of the city. Offers latest news about Almaty’s governance. The information is divided into several directions, including social sphere, culture, society, youth policies, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bureau of National Statistics / Gender</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.gov.kz/en&#34;&gt;Bureau of National Statistics / Gender&lt;/a&gt; is the official government resource representing a collection of gendered data on population, family, healthcare, education and communication, employment, human rights, and politics. The Bureau has received criticism of its data from a feminist organization &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CUmGoyNsJPu/&#34;&gt;Kaz Fem&lt;/a&gt;. Kaz Fem created &lt;a href=&#34;https://schitaetsya.kz/&#34;&gt;its own alternative platform&lt;/a&gt; about the domestic violence situation in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Communication Service under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_communication_service_under_the_president_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_communication_service_under_the_president_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ortcom.kz/en/&#34;&gt;Central Communication Service under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is the official communication service for presidential and state affairs aimed at fostering communication between the government bodies and media. Contains latest news (including regional news), press releases, infographics, video announcements, and expert discussions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Commission for Women Affairs and Familial Demographic Policies</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/national_commission_for_women_affairs_and_familial_demographic_policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/national_commission_for_women_affairs_and_familial_demographic_policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Established in 2006 by the first president Nursultan Nazarbayev, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.akorda.kz/ru/executive_office/presidential_commissions/commission_for_women&#34;&gt;National Commission for Women Affairs and Familial Demographic Policies&lt;/a&gt; serves as a consultative and advisory body under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan. One of the main goals of the commission is the development of recommendations for setting priorities and forming and implementing a comprehensive state policy regarding the family, equality of women and men in the context of the &amp;ldquo;Strategy &amp;ldquo;Kazakhstan - 2050: a new political course of an established state.&amp;rdquo; The text of the original 2006 decree could be found in Russian &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/rus/docs/U060000056_&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. As of May 2022, the composition of the commission can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.akorda.kz/ru/o-vnesenii-izmeneniy-i-dopolneniya-v-ukaz-prezidenta-respubliki-kazahstan-ot-1-fevralya-2006-goda-56-o-nacionalnoy-komissii-po-delam-zhenshchin-i-semeyno-demograficheskoy-politike-pri-prezidente-respubliki-kazahstan-1842638&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Current president of the commission, Karakat Abden, Kazakhstani author, politician, and public figure, &lt;a href=&#34;https://esquire.kz/t-v-kazashka-smirisy/&#34;&gt;received public criticism&lt;/a&gt; after the release of her controversial book titled &amp;ldquo;You are a Kazakh Girl. Be Proud!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Official Information Source of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/official_information_source_of_the_prime_minister_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/official_information_source_of_the_prime_minister_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://primeminister.kz/&#34;&gt;Official Information Source of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, such as the state addresses, policies breakdown of the state and advisory bodies, government composition, as well as an archive of the documents. The website is not search friendly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PaperLab</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/paperlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/paperlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015 and supported by the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://paperlab.kz/&#34;&gt;PaperLab&lt;/a&gt; is a public policy research organization in Kazakhstan. PaperLab publishes research, organizes public discussions, and offers training and networking opportunities to Central Asian experts. Most publications are in Kazakh and Russian and sometimes in English. PaperLab has done extensive research on sex education in Kazakhstan and frequently collaborates with other NGOs and INGOs on the topic of violence against women. Methodology note and description of sources are not always included in the publications.   &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Units to Guard Women against Violence</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/units_to_guard_women_against_violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/units_to_guard_women_against_violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1998, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/rus/docs/V1500012948&#34;&gt;Republic of Kazakhstan Administrations of Internal Affairs’ Units to Guard Women against Violence&lt;/a&gt; is a domestic body on the basis of police work force designed to protect constitutional rights of women, coordinate detention and prosecution processes in the case of the detention of women, and organize work to prevent domestic violence against women. The official text of the establishment of the units &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/rus/docs/V1500012948&#34;&gt;could be found here&lt;/a&gt;. In 2021, Kaz Fem feminist organization &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CXtA7T6MbAM/&#34;&gt;criticized&lt;/a&gt; the compensation policy of the Units’ workers stating that on average its female workers earn less than workers of other internal affairs’ units.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
