<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – human rights</title>
    <link>/tags/human-rights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in human rights on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/human-rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Aiman Umarova’s Rights School</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/aiman_umratova_rights_school/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/aiman_umratova_rights_school/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://womenrights.kz/&#34;&gt;Aiman Umarova’s Rights School&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots informational platform focusing on the problems of women and girls from socially vulnerable background, including gender-based violence. The portal provides brief information on legislative contexts and statistical summaries on the issues of sexual violence, domestic violence, violence against children, LGBTQ rights, etc. Information is available in Kazakh and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Human Rights KZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/human_rights_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/human_rights_kz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/humanrightskz/&#34;&gt;Human Rights KZ&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to sharing domestic and international human rights information and news in Kazakh. Available on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: MISK</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/misk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/misk/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1998 &lt;a href=&#34;https://misk.org.kz/&#34;&gt;MISK (Kazakhstani Informational Youth Service)&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to research on youth, monitoring youth policy legislation, and human rights training. Key projects of the organization include School of Human Rights and School of Civil Education. MISK also regularly published surveys on various social issues. Summary of survey findings include brief information on sample sizes of each survey. Available in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nghrdc.kz/&#34;&gt;New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a coalition of Kazakhstani human rights defenders including practicing experts in the field of international human rights law, human rights researchers, leaders, and members of NGOs. The Coalition is engaged in informational campaigns, educational training, and other public events organization.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Soros Kazakhstan Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1995 by the Open Society Institute, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soros.kz&#34;&gt;Soros Kazakhstan Foundation&lt;/a&gt; funds multiple scholarship programs, educational courses, and research and activist initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundation publishes research works of various organizations and authors produced with the foundation’s support and/or collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available primarily in Russian with translations into Kazakh and English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
