<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – gender-based` violence</title>
    <link>/tags/gender-based-violence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gender-based` violence on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/gender-based-violence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: NeMolchiKZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.kz/&#34;&gt;#NeMolchiKZ&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots public fund dedicated to protection of victims of gender-based violence. The fund defines its activities along the three components, including legal protection, promotion of awareness, and legislative.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: NeMolchi.UZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchi_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchi_uz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.uz&#34;&gt;NeMolchi.UZ&lt;/a&gt; is an independent information project against gender-based violence in Uzbekistan. Its mission is to draw attention to violence against women and challenge societal attitudes towards the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Oydin Nur</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oydin_nur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oydin_nur/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1999, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/oydinnur.uz/&#34;&gt;Regional Center for Social Protection of the Family &amp;ldquo;Oydin Nur&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a shelter in the the Bukhara Region of Uzbekistan that offers long term shelter to female victims of gender-based violence, as well as legal and medical services and resources for personal development. The center organizes seminars and trainings concerning issues of women in the country. State departments of internal affairs, education, and health are listed as partners of Oydin Nur.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/central-asia&#34;&gt;Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt; is a research and advocacy campaign dedicated to eliminating sexual and gender-based violence and harmful practices in Central Asia. The program involves UN Women, UNDP, and UNFPA with funding from the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan 2020 report is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/publications/spotlight-initiative-central-asia-and-afghanistan-programme-report-2020&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt; in English. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/projects/spotlight-initiative-regional-programme-central-asia-and-afghanistan&#34;&gt;UNDP project page for the Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Data Hub</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_data_hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_data_hub/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Publications on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/publications&#34;&gt;UN Women Data Hub&lt;/a&gt; have an option to filter by region.
Eurasia and Central Asia region primarily focuses on Eastern European and Balkan countries with occasional inclusion of Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themes of publications include data use, disabilities, economic empowerment, ending violence against women, environment, gender and COVID-19, HIV and AIDS, migration, sustainable development, and peace and security.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UNDP</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_uz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;UN Development Program&lt;/a&gt; became active in Uzbekistan in 1993 and works on projects related to the national government, business, civil society and academic affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UNDP regularly published press releases on the topic of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/uzbekistan/gender-equality&#34;&gt;gender equality development&lt;/a&gt; in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://evaw-global-database.unwomen.org/en/countries/asia/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Global database on violence against women&lt;/a&gt; assembles UN data on different forms of violence against women, including all UN-issued reports and updates on Gender Equality Indexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://uzbekistan.unfpa.org&#34;&gt;UN Population Fund&lt;/a&gt; produces country-specific landing pages. The work of the Fund includes data on sexual and reproductive health, gender equality, young people, and population matters. Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unfpa.org/data/UZ&#34;&gt;Data Portal for Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; gender-related data across six main components: population, sexual and reproductive health, family planning, education, gender, rights, and human capital, and harmful practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://uzbekistan.un.org/en/resources/publications&#34;&gt;The UN publications on Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; include annual reports, analysis of the education sector, and reports on activism against gender-based violence. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Aiman Umarova School of Rights</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/aiman_umratova_school_of_rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/aiman_umratova_school_of_rights/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://womenrights.kz/&#34;&gt;Aiman Umarova School of Rights&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots informational platform focusing on the problems of women and girls from socially vulnerable background, including gender-based violence. The portal provides brief information on legislative contexts and statistical summaries on the issues of sexual violence, domestic violence, violence against children, LGBTQ rights, etc. Information is available in Kazakh and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Aiman Umarova’s Rights School</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/aiman_umarova_school_of_rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/aiman_umarova_school_of_rights/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://womenrights.kz/&#34;&gt;Aiman Umarova’s Rights School&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots informational platform focusing on the problems of women and girls from socially vulnerable background, including gender-based violence. The portal provides brief information on legislative contexts and statistical summaries on the issues of sexual violence, domestic violence, violence against children, LGBTQ rights, etc. Information is available in Kazakh and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bureau of National Statistics / Gender</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.gov.kz/en&#34;&gt;Bureau of National Statistics / Gender&lt;/a&gt; is the official government resource representing a collection of gendered data on population, family, healthcare, education and communication, employment, human rights, and politics. The Bureau has received criticism of its data from a feminist organization &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CUmGoyNsJPu/&#34;&gt;Kaz Fem&lt;/a&gt;. Kaz Fem created &lt;a href=&#34;https://schitaetsya.kz/&#34;&gt;its own alternative platform&lt;/a&gt; about the domestic violence situation in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Crisis Centers Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telefon150.kz/&#34;&gt;Crisis Centers Union&lt;/a&gt; unites 18 organizations from 12 regions of Kazakhstan. The Union is aimed at prevention and eradication of all forms of gender-based violence, formation of a non-violent culture in Kazakhstani society. The website offers news articles, photo and video materials, informational materials, webinars, and infographics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminita</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminita/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminita/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminita.kz/&#34;&gt;Feminita&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots queer feminist collective. Feminita aims to create and strengthen the rights of women and activist communities and empower the most oppressed groups of Kazakhstani population (lesbian, bisexual, queer, women with disabilities, women in sex work). Currently, the organization works on three research projects: assessment of needs of LBQ women; health conditions of LBQT women and transgender men; and sexual wellness of LBQ women. Methodology and research design sections are included in the first two project reports. The reports are available in Russian with occasional translation to Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Schitaetsya</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/schitaetsya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/schitaetsya/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://schitaetsya.kz/&#34;&gt;Schitaetsya&lt;/a&gt; is a collaborative project by the Kaz Fem feminist organization and other experts and organization to collect accurate information about domestic violence in Kazakhstan and provide informational resources for victims of domestic abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: SVET</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/svet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/svet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://svetpf.org/&#34;&gt;SVET&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani foundation dedicated to helping survivors of gender-based violence and sharing relevant news.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women: Europe and Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_europe_and_central_asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_europe_and_central_asia/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://eca.unwomen.org/en/where-we-are/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UN Women: Europe and Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; provides an overview of the UN initiatives in Kazakhstan, including a list of major international treaties ratified by the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overview includes four main themes: women’s economic empowerment, ending violence against women, national planning and budgeting, and sustainable development agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Units to Guard Women against Violence</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/units_to_guard_women_against_violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/units_to_guard_women_against_violence/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1998, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/rus/docs/V1500012948&#34;&gt;Republic of Kazakhstan Administrations of Internal Affairs’ Units to Guard Women against Violence&lt;/a&gt; is a domestic body on the basis of police work force designed to protect constitutional rights of women, coordinate detention and prosecution processes in the case of the detention of women, and organize work to prevent domestic violence against women. The official text of the establishment of the units &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/rus/docs/V1500012948&#34;&gt;could be found here&lt;/a&gt;. In 2021, Kaz Fem feminist organization &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CXtA7T6MbAM/&#34;&gt;criticized&lt;/a&gt; the compensation policy of the Units’ workers stating that on average its female workers earn less than workers of other internal affairs’ units.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
