<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – culture</title>
    <link>/tags/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in culture on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA&#43;)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mofa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/mofa/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/femmuseum/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA+)&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots media spotlighting feminist and queer artists from Central Asia. MoFA+ also shares art exhibits, events, and publications on feminist and queer art in Central Asia. It appears to be primarily based at the Kyrgyz National Museum of Fine Arts named after Gapar Aitiev and located in Bishkek.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Dope Soz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@DOPESOZ/&#34;&gt;Dope Soz&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series offering discussions and conversations about social, historical, political, and cultural events and discourses.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Tolk</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tolk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tolk/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@tolkkz/&#34;&gt;Tolk&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast studio and an audio-hub dedicated to researching contemporary Kazakhstani through interpersonal conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Art - Review</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/art_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/art_review/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artreviewuz/&#34;&gt;Art - Review&lt;/a&gt; is local media about art and culture in Uzbekistan. It has presence on Instagram, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/artreviewuz&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.facebook.com/artreview.uz&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bahor/Vesna</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bahor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bahor/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;facebook.com/people/Bahor-%D0%92%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BD%D0%B0/&#34;&gt;Bahor/Vesna&lt;/a&gt; is a self-organized group of cultural immigrant-workers from Russia, Belarus, and Ukraine who have migrated to Uzbekistan following the escalation of Russia&amp;rsquo;s invasion of Ukraine. The initiative covers educational and cultural events in Uzbekistan. Bahor/Vesna is described as a project born out of necessity to &amp;ldquo;find connections during the tragic events affecting millions of residents in Ukraine, Russia, and other countries.&amp;rdquo; The initiative mostly focuses on music and contemporary art, as well as cinematography, literature, and research. It has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bahorvesnaa/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/bahorvesna&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8YmBSTfITo0VZ9zZkG6ShQ&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Exponaut</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/exponaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/exponaut/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/exponautz/&#34;&gt;Exponaut&lt;/a&gt; is an independent media geared toward a younger audience. It covers art and culture, as well as creating projects meant to spotlight women and LGBTQIA+ community of Uzbekistan. Exponaut also has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/exponautz/729&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Moc Creative Org</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/moc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/moc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.facebook.com/org.moc&#34;&gt;Moc Creative Org&lt;/a&gt; is a collective of creators, producers, artists, designers, musicians, and photographers. The initiative is focused on organization of events in Uzbekistan, including music festivals, educational and professional trainings, and art exhibits. It is present on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/moc__org/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/moc24&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qizlar</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qizlar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qizlar/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qizlarqizlarqizlar/&#34;&gt;Qizlar&lt;/a&gt; is an independent collective of women-creators from Uzbekistan. The collective&amp;rsquo;s mission is described as spotlighting projects and products created by women and non-binary people, as well as fostering safe and friendly space for minorities. Qizlar also works on projects with a decolonial agenda aimed at &amp;ldquo;understanding and working out identities as a product of complex post-colonial processes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Uzbekistan Art and Culture Development Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/acdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/acdf/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.acdf.uz/&#34;&gt;The Art and Culture Development Foundation of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; fosters international cooperation
and promotes the culture of Uzbekistan on the international arena. Its mission is to create an &amp;ldquo;inclusive and accessible environment in the country&amp;rsquo;s cultural institutions, contribute to renovation of museums, and to develop cultural patronage and professional training for the arts and culture sector.&amp;rdquo; It appears to be a state-affiliated organization.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Hook Report</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/hook_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/hook_report/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hook.report/&#34;&gt;Hook Report&lt;/a&gt; is an independent Uzbek media offering coverage of political, economic, art, and cultural news in the country. According to its mission, Hook Report aims to bring quality news coverage using a less traditional and formal approach.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Calvert Journal (The)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/calvert_journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/calvert_journal/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013 and owned by a UK-based non-profit Calvert 22 Foundation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.calvertjournal.com/&#34;&gt;The Calvert Journal&lt;/a&gt; offers publications on culture, innovation, photography, and travel in Central Asia, Caucasus, Russia, the Balkans, and Eastern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Eurasian Cultural Alliance</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasian_cultural_alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasian_cultural_alliance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2011, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.cultura.kz/&#34;&gt;Eurasian Cultural Alliance&lt;/a&gt; is a NGO dedicated to cultivating the contemporary art scene of Kazakhstan. The mission of the Alliance is to stimulate the creative economy, improve social and economic standing of the region&amp;rsquo;s key cultural players, and advance the integration of the Kazakhstani identity into a larger global context.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Fading.TSE</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/fading.tse/&#34;&gt;Fading.TSE&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project documenting urban history of Kazakhstan and its capital. Primary focused on photography, oral histories, and cultural heritage. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram, Facebook, TikTok, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Tselinny Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tselinny_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tselinny_center/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 by Kairat Boranbayev, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tselinny.org/&#34;&gt;Tselinny Center&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to studying and developing cultural scene in Kazakhstan. The center publishes educational books, hosts art exhibitions, and organizes events.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
