<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – politics</title>
    <link>/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in politics on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Dope Soz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@DOPESOZ/&#34;&gt;Dope Soz&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series offering discussions and conversations about social, historical, political, and cultural events and discourses.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Country Data Sheet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/&#34;&gt;UN Women Country Data Sheet&lt;/a&gt; offers country specific gender-related data across four main components: economic, social, political, and environmental. Data sheets are available for &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kyrgyzstan&#34;&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/mongolia&#34;&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/tajikistan&#34;&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/turkmenistan&#34;&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;,. Some of the economic data is missing, while environmental data does not include a gender-based breakdown. Gender-specific indicators have at least 50% of data missing across the 17 indicators listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection is &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/modules/custom/country_fact_sheet/pdf/MethodologicalNote.pdf&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asia Barometer</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_asia_barometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_asia_barometer/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ca-barometer.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asia Barometer (CAB)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional independent NGO for applied social research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAB Survey Project is a multinational empirical survey on human beliefs and values first conducted in 2017. Questionnaires identify gender of the respondents with two options included, male or female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAB provides free access to databases of the CAB Survey Project available in SPSS, Excel, and Stata formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note &lt;a href=&#34;https://ca-barometer.org/en/what-we-do/methodology/research-methods&#34;&gt;is available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oxus_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oxus_society/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oxussociety.org/&#34;&gt;The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs&lt;/a&gt; is a Washington, DC-based NGO aimed at fostering academic exchange between Central Asia and the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Oxus Society publishes datasets on articles and books on Central Asia, as well as a directory of researchers studying Central Asia. The NGO also publishes reports on various topic, particularly pertaining to international relations, religion, and domestic politics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bureau of National Statistics / Gender</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.gov.kz/en&#34;&gt;Bureau of National Statistics / Gender&lt;/a&gt; is the official government resource representing a collection of gendered data on population, family, healthcare, education and communication, employment, human rights, and politics. The Bureau has received criticism of its data from a feminist organization &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CUmGoyNsJPu/&#34;&gt;Kaz Fem&lt;/a&gt;. Kaz Fem created &lt;a href=&#34;https://schitaetsya.kz/&#34;&gt;its own alternative platform&lt;/a&gt; about the domestic violence situation in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Oyan, Qazaqstan!</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/oyanqazaqstankz/&#34;&gt;Oyan, Qazaqstan!&lt;/a&gt; is a social movement advocating for political reforms in Kazakhstan. The organization shares news about political events, activist campaigns, organizing efforts, as well as prosecution of activists by the state authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Policy Solutions Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://policysolutions.kz/&#34;&gt;Policy Solutions Center&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots organizations of Kazakhstani researchers involved in the study of socio-political and socio-economic problems in Kazakhstan, as well as the development of policy and management recommendations. The Center publishes analytical pieces and develops projects on political, economic, and social issues.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Schitaetsya</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/schitaetsya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/schitaetsya/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://schitaetsya.kz/&#34;&gt;Schitaetsya&lt;/a&gt; is a collaborative project by the Kaz Fem feminist organization and other experts and organization to collect accurate information about domestic violence in Kazakhstan and provide informational resources for victims of domestic abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Economic Forum’s Global Gender Gap Report</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weforum.org/reports/global-gender-gap-report-2022&#34;&gt;World Economic Forum’s Global Gender Gap Report&lt;/a&gt; includes countries’ score cards summarizing key gendered data findings broken down into 11 categories: economic participation and opportunity, educational attainment, health and survival, political empowerment, general indicators, work participation and leadership, access to finance, civil and political freedom, family and care, education and skills, and health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available. User’s guide how to read the economy profiles &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weforum.org/reports/global-gender-gap-report-2022/in-full/user-s-guide-how-to-read-the-economy-profiles&#34;&gt;is provided&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
