<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1993 on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</title>
    <link>/date_start/1993/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1993 on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 22:24:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/date_start/1993/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Living Standards Measurement Study (LSMS) - World Bank - Kyrgyzstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/living_standards_measurement_survey_kyrgyzstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/living_standards_measurement_survey_kyrgyzstan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbank.org/en/programs/lsms&#34;&gt;Living Standards Measurement Study (LSMS)&lt;/a&gt; is the World Bank&amp;rsquo;s flagship household survey program focused on strengthening household survey systems in client countries and on improving the quality of microdata to better inform development policies. The LSMS is housed in the Data Production and Methods Unit of the World Bank’s Development Data Group.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://microdata.worldbank.org/index.php/catalog/lsms/?page=1&amp;amp;country%5B%5D=118&amp;amp;ps=15&amp;amp;repo=lsms&#34;&gt;Data on Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt; is available from 1993 to 1998 through the &lt;strong&gt;Poverty Monitoring Survey&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scope of the study includes household and family, jobs and employment, education, health, and other variables.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNDP</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;UN Development Program&lt;/a&gt; became active in Uzbekistan in 1993 and works on projects related to the national government, business, civil society and academic affairs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UNDP regularly published press releases on the topic of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/uzbekistan/gender-equality&#34;&gt;gender equality development&lt;/a&gt; in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://evaw-global-database.unwomen.org/en/countries/asia/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Global database on violence against women&lt;/a&gt; assembles UN data on different forms of violence against women, including all UN-issued reports and updates on Gender Equality Indexes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://uzbekistan.unfpa.org&#34;&gt;UN Population Fund&lt;/a&gt; produces country-specific landing pages. The work of the Fund includes data on sexual and reproductive health, gender equality, young people, and population matters. Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unfpa.org/data/UZ&#34;&gt;Data Portal for Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; gender-related data across six main components: population, sexual and reproductive health, family planning, education, gender, rights, and human capital, and harmful practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friedrich Ebert Stiftung</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/fes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1925 in Germany with a Kazakhstani office opened in 1993, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.fes.de/&#34;&gt;Friedrich Ebert Stiftung&lt;/a&gt; is a foundation funded by the German government. The INGO focuses on social and gender justice issues, as well as political participation and youth leadership.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Publications on Kazakhstan include population surveys, particularly focused on youth, and are available in English, Kazakh, and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Published surveys include &amp;ldquo;Youth and Education,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Values,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Social Justice.&amp;rdquo; Gendered breakdown of data is included for some survey questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
