<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kyrgyz on CAMGDP</title>
    <link>https://camgdp.org/language/kyrgyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kyrgyz on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:36:55 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://camgdp.org/language/kyrgyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>National Statistical Committee of the Kyrgyz Republic</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/stat_gov_kg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/stat_gov_kg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg&#34;&gt;National Statistical Committee of the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt; provides fundamental economic, social, and other demographic statistics about Kyrgyzstan. Education, healthcare, economy, population, employment, and living standards are among the many categories of data available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statistics are available as downloadable tables in Excel format and as publications, including a special section on &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/gendernaya-statistika/&#34;&gt;Gender Statistics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Publications include the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/publications/statisticheskij-ezhegodnik-kyrgyzskoj-respubliki/&#34;&gt;Statistical Yearbook of the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/publications/publikaciya-socialnye-tendencii-kyrgyzskoj-respubliki/&#34;&gt;Social Trends of the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/publications/sbornik-zhenshiny-i-muzhchiny-kyrgyzskoj-respubliki/&#34;&gt;Women and Men in the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt;, and many other regular and special publications available for download.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Museum of Contemporary Women&#39;s and Queer Art of Central Asia (MoFA&#43;)</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/mofa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/mofa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://femmuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA+)&lt;/a&gt; is a museum spotlighting feminist and queer artists from Central Asia and advocating for the rights and freedoms of women and LGBTQIA+ community. MoFA+ hosts solo and group exhibits, workshops, and events. The museum also grants art fellowships and is involved in documentary filmmaking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bashtan Bashta</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/bashtan_bashta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/bashtan_bashta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@bashtanbashta/&#34;&gt;Bashtan Bashta&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bashtan_bashta/&#34;&gt;a social media project&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to raising civil consciousness in Kyrgyzstan. It also covers news and politics of other Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antiuniversity of Feminism</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/antiuniversity_of_feminism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/antiuniversity_of_feminism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/antiuniversity_of_feminism/&#34;&gt;Antiuniversity of Feminism&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project aimed at creating a safe space for women and people with all gender identities to learn about feminism and gender theory. Antiuniversity offers free online courses in Kyrgyz. The project was founded and created by Elvira Tilek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/oxus_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/oxus_society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oxussociety.org/&#34;&gt;The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs&lt;/a&gt; is a Washington, DC-based NGO aimed at fostering academic exchange between Central Asia and the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Oxus Society publishes datasets on articles and books on Central Asia, as well as a directory of researchers studying Central Asia. The NGO also publishes reports on various topic, particularly pertaining to international relations, religion, and domestic politics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TAG news</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/tag_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/tag_news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded first in 2008 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kaztag.kz/ru/&#34;&gt;TAG news agency&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Afghanistan, Iran, and the Silk Road region. Available in English, Kazakh, and Russian in Kazakhstan; Kyrgyz and Russian in Kyrgyzstan; Uzbek and Russian in Uzbekistan; and Tajik and Russian in Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
