<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – Kazakhstan</title>
    <link>/countries/kazakhstan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kazakhstan on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/countries/kazakhstan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides: Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/guides/kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide will be expanded during summer 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;international-non-governmental-organizations-ingos&#34;&gt;International non-governmental organizations (INGOs)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official international sources (&lt;a href=&#34;/category/ingo&#34;&gt;INGOs&lt;/a&gt;) cover gender issues in Kazakhstan using a comparative perspective that applies standardized reporting methods to Kazakhstan.  These can be good sources of numeric data at the country-level.  For example, see the
&lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/un_population_fund_kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;UN Population Fund in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/&#34;&gt;World Economic Forum&amp;rsquo;s Global Gender Gap Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other INGOs take a more focused, activist perspective, such as the &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative&#34;&gt;Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-non-governmental-organizations-local-ngos&#34;&gt;Local non-governmental organizations (Local NGOs)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For information on issues that often go unrecognized in official state media and governmental sources, such as feminist activism and LGBTQ topics, &lt;a href=&#34;/category/local-ngo&#34;&gt;local NGOs&lt;/a&gt; can fill in the gaps.  For example, see &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/feminita/&#34;&gt;Feminita&lt;/a&gt;, a grassroots queer feminist collective, and the grassroots feminist organization &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/kazfem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;government&#34;&gt;Government&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazakh &lt;a href=&#34;/category/government&#34;&gt;Government&lt;/a&gt; resources provide many official data series (such as the &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/&#34;&gt;Bureau of National Statistics Gender Statistics&lt;/a&gt;) and sources of official government laws and pronouncements (such as &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/ak_orda/&#34;&gt;Ak Orda&lt;/a&gt;), but may lack in coverage of underrepresented groups or controversial issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;media&#34;&gt;Media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&#34;/category/state-affiliated-media/&#34;&gt;state-affiliated media&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/zakon_kz/&#34;&gt;Zakon.kz&lt;/a&gt; offer mainstream perspectives, &lt;a href=&#34;/category/independent-media/&#34;&gt;independent media&lt;/a&gt; can deliver alternative viewpoints.  For example,  &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/batyr_jamal/&#34;&gt;Batyr Jamal&lt;/a&gt; takes a women-oriented perspective, while &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/human_rights_kz/&#34;&gt;Human Rights KZ&lt;/a&gt; highlights human rights concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-information&#34;&gt;Local information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional and information on areas within Kazakhstan is sparser, but local government offices represent one source of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nur-sultan-astana&#34;&gt;Nur-Sultan (Astana)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information and data on the capital, now renamed Nur-Sultan from Astana, is available from the &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_nur_sultan/&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Nur-Sultan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;almaty&#34;&gt;Almaty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_almaty/&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Almaty&lt;/a&gt; provides information on the largest city in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/guides/lgbtq&#34;&gt;LGBTQ&lt;/a&gt;: guide to LGBTQ material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/guides/media&#34;&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt;: guide to news and media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/guides/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;: guide to resources on Uzbekistan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Adil Qala</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adil_qala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/adil_qala/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adilqala.kz/&#34;&gt;Adil Qala&lt;/a&gt; is a project on social justice in the field of urban planning and development. It aims to create a platform for a &amp;ldquo;broad public dialogue about the priority of the human dimension in urban policies and practices.&amp;rdquo; Adil Qala hosts public discussions and educational programs, including on the topic of LGBTQIA+ safe spaces and visibility and safety of women in urban settings.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA&#43;)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mofa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/mofa/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/femmuseum/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA+)&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots media spotlighting feminist and queer artists from Central Asia. MoFA+ also shares art exhibits, events, and publications on feminist and queer art in Central Asia. It appears to be primarily based at the Kyrgyz National Museum of Fine Arts named after Gapar Aitiev and located in Bishkek.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Dope Soz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@DOPESOZ/&#34;&gt;Dope Soz&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series offering discussions and conversations about social, historical, political, and cultural events and discourses.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Education Community</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/edu_community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/edu_community/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 in partnership with USAID and Eurasia Foundation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/edu.community.kz/&#34;&gt;Education Community&lt;/a&gt; is an activist project that aims to connect gender and sexuality minorities to provide them with opportunities for personal, psychological, and legal support and development. Education Community creates and shares projects and programs advocating for diversity, inclusivity, and tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: FemAgora</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/femagora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/femagora/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://femagora.org/&#34;&gt;FemAgora&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to fostering transnational feminist solidarity in Central Asia. The organization is involved in organization of Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march and the issue of employment of transgender people. FemAgora hosts annual FemAgora Central Asian festival for those involved in feminist, gender-sensitive, and/or women-led work.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminist Translocalities</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminisms.co/&#34;&gt;Feminist Translocalities&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots transnational feminist organization aiming to bring together and support feminist and LGBTQ+ activists from Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia. The organization publishes magazine articles and zines, hosts events, and engages in other various projects. Although the website describes the organization as primarily focused on Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia, it frequently publishes works by Central Asian authors.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminita</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminita/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminita.kz/&#34;&gt;Feminita&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots queer feminist collective. Feminita aims to create and strengthen the rights of women and activist communities and empower the most oppressed groups of Kazakhstani population (lesbian, bisexual, queer, women with disabilities, women in sex work). Currently, the organization works on three research projects: assessment of needs of LBQ women; health conditions of LBQT women and transgender men; and sexual wellness of LBQ women. Methodology and research design sections are included in the first two project reports. The reports are available in Russian with occasional translation to Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Human Rights Focus</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/human_rights_focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/human_rights_focus/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by USAID and Kazakhstan Public Association &amp;ldquo;Dignity&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://humanrightsfocus.kz/&#34;&gt;Human Rights Focus&lt;/a&gt; is a project mobilizing and organizing various groups, including human rights defenders, NGOs, civil society leaders, and others, for empowering and encouraging women in Kazakhstan to participate more fully in public administration and decision-making and for prevention of bullying in Kazakhstani schools. Human Rights Focus offers trainings and workshops to Kazakhstani teachers, hosts conferences, and provides educational content on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ILGA-Europe</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ilga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ilga/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ilga-europe.org/&#34;&gt;ILGA-Europe&lt;/a&gt; is an International NGO advocating for the protection of LGBTI people and uniting over 600 organizations from 54 countries across Europe and Central Asia. ILGA conducts its work through resourcing and connecting communities, driving political change, and amplifying voices. Its mission is to provide a solid foundation for activists and organizations. ILGA publishes reports on the protection of rights of LGBTI people in Central Asia, specifically related to violence and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Invisible Rainbow Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/invisible_rainbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/invisible_rainbow/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/invisible_rainbow_union/&#34;&gt;Invisible Rainbow Union&lt;/a&gt; is a social media community of queer ethnic minorities from Central Asia and Russia. The media focuses on preserving oral histories of the LGBTQIA+ community.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kaz Fem</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kazfem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kazfem/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/kaz_fem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots feminist organization dedicated to research and development of feminist theory in Kazakhstan. One of the leading organizations behind Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march. Available mostly in Russian with occasional material in Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kibhr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kibhr/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bureau.kz/&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law (KIBHR)&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani bureau of human rights. It engages in human rights advocacy, shares relevant reports, and engages in human rights monitoring in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kok.team</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kok.team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kok.team/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017 and dissolved in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kok.team/&#34;&gt;Kok.team&lt;/a&gt; was a grassroots LGBT organization dedicated to providing information on the LGBT issues in Kazakh. Digital archive contains articles, podcasts and videos of Kazakhstani LGBT  community. Available in Kazakh and Russian with occasional translation to English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Legal Policy Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/lprc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/lprc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2008 by a group of Kazakhstani lawyers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lprc.kz/&#34;&gt;Legal Policy Research Center (LPRC)&lt;/a&gt; is a non-political, independent research institute promoting the principle of the rule of law and liberal values through the implementation of research, publishing and educational activities in the field of legal policy. Its mission is to strengthen democratic values through effective legal reforms. Its projects include promoting anti-discrimination agenda and combating sexual harassment.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qara Magan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qara.magan/&#34;&gt;Qara Magan&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project is dedicated to visibility and storytelling of the LGBTQ+ community of Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: QAZAQUEER</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qazaqueer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qazaqueer/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qazaqueer/&#34;&gt;QAZAQUEER&lt;/a&gt; is a social media project on the lives of the LGBTQIA+ community in Kazakhstan. It primarily produces content in Kazakh and offers educational resources on queer identity, relationships, and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Queernyi squirt</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mira Ungarova and Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://podcast.kz/1657513218/info&#34;&gt;Queernyi Squirt&lt;/a&gt; is an 18+ podcast dedicated to inclusive LGBTQIA+ sex education in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Right Now</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/right-now/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 in association with the US Embassy in Kazakhstan and the National Alumi Network of US programs graduates, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/rightnow.kz/&#34;&gt;Right Now&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform promoting awareness of legal rights in Kazakhstan. It offers online lectures on various topics, including violence against women and children.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Stop Harass</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/stop-harass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/stop-harass/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stopharass.kz/&#34;&gt;Stop Harass&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani harassment prevention and tracking website. Its mission is to &amp;ldquo;engage all residents of Kazakhstan in creating an environment that is intolerant of sexual assault, harassment, stalking, catcalling, etc.&amp;rdquo; The platform allows anyone to report harassment instances either via Telegram bot or website.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: TEDxAbayStWomen</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;First held in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tedxabaystwomen/&#34;&gt;TEDxAbayStWomen&lt;/a&gt; is a noncommercial conference on gender equality usually held in Almaty, Kazakhstan. Next conference is expected to be held in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: The Fish that changed gender (Рыба, которая сменила пол)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fish/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://beacons.ai/rybaipol&#34;&gt;the Fish that changed gender&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast project in conversation with transgender people living in Kazakhstan. It brings forward stories and experiences of transpeople. The podcast also has a presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/rybaipol/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Tolk</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tolk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tolk/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@tolkkz/&#34;&gt;Tolk&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast studio and an audio-hub dedicated to researching contemporary Kazakhstani through interpersonal conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Unit </title>
      <link>/sources/sources/unit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/unit/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021 by n-ost, a Berlin-based media NGO, &lt;a href=&#34;https://unit.n-ost.org&#34;&gt;Unit&lt;/a&gt; is a crossborder community of journalists and activists from Central Asia, Eastern Europe, and South Caucasus who work on the LGBTQIA+ issues.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Womxn of Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/womxn_of_ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/womxn_of_ca/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/womxnofcentralasia/&#34;&gt;Womxn of Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; is a social media project sharing stories and success of Central Asian women in various professional fields. It also has a Spotify-based podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: NeMolchiKZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchikz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.kz/&#34;&gt;#NeMolchiKZ&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots public fund dedicated to protection of victims of gender-based violence. The fund defines its activities along the three components, including legal protection, promotion of awareness, and legislative.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Artif</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/artif/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artif.ication/&#34;&gt;Artif&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform connecting artists, human rights defenders, and activists from Eastern Europe and Central Asia. The platform&amp;rsquo;s mission is to voice social problems using art accessible to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Center of legal protection &#39;Zan Talaby&#39;</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/zan_talaby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/zan_talaby/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/NgoZanTalabyShymkent/&#34;&gt;Center of legal protection &amp;ldquo;Zan Talaby&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a Shymkent-based NGO dedicated to combating human trafficking in Kazakhstan. It offers hotline assistance to victims of human trafficking and actively engages in discussions, awareness campaigns, and educational trainings on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ECOM</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ecom/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecom.ngo/&#34;&gt;ECOM (Eurasian Coalition for Health, Rights, Gender and Sexual Diversity)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional NGO working the sphere of health of LGBTI communities in Eastern Europe and Central Asia. It is a membership association open to non-profit organizations and activists working in the field. ECOM publishes regular reports on violation of rights of the LGBTI people in various Central Asian countries, including Uzbekistan and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Orda</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/orda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/orda/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://orda.kz/&#34;&gt;Orda&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan, as well as journalistic investigations.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Trans*Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transcoalition.net/&#34;&gt;Trans*Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a platform for trans- and non-binary activists from the countries of the Caucasus, Central Asia and Eastern Europe. It advocates for uniting, solidarizing, strengthening the voice of the trans-activist community in our region through the development of a sustainable, effective, authoritative, and resourceful organization. Key areas of Trans&lt;em&gt;Coalition&amp;rsquo;s work include response to the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, depathologizing, sex work, and legislation. In Central Asia, Trans&lt;/em&gt;Coalition offers a hot line, a map of resources and aid, and information for trans sex workers.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Country Data Sheet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/&#34;&gt;UN Women Country Data Sheet&lt;/a&gt; offers country specific gender-related data across four main components: economic, social, political, and environmental. Data sheets are available for &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kyrgyzstan&#34;&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/mongolia&#34;&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/tajikistan&#34;&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/turkmenistan&#34;&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;,. Some of the economic data is missing, while environmental data does not include a gender-based breakdown. Gender-specific indicators have at least 50% of data missing across the 17 indicators listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection is &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/modules/custom/country_fact_sheet/pdf/MethodologicalNote.pdf&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Bank</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_bank/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/&#34;&gt;World Bank Gender Data Portal&lt;/a&gt; covers &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/kyrgyz-republic/&#34;&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/mongolia/&#34;&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/tajikistan/&#34;&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/Turkmenistan/&#34;&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/uzbekistan/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;, and offers a breakdown of gender-related data in regards to adolescent fertility rates, education completion rates, literacy levels, labor force participation, vulnerable employment, unpaid domestic work, business and bank account ownership, internet usage, and parliament membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data sources annotation is available under all indicators. It includes development relevance, limitation and exceptions, and statistical concepts and methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datasets are available via CVS, API, and Databank formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wbl.worldbank.org/en/reports&#34;&gt;Women, Business, and the Law Reports&lt;/a&gt; Annual report measuring the laws and regulations that affect women’s economic opportunity in 190 economies, including Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports are available in English with executive summaries in French, Spanish, and Arabic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodology section is available on the website and is based on feedback of &amp;ldquo;more than 2,000 respondents&amp;rdquo; which includes local experts on family, labor, and criminal law, including lawyers, judges, academics, and civil society. It is unclear whether the questionnaires sent out to experts are in English, Russian, or Kazakh languages.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Adamdar/CA</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adamdar.ca/&#34;&gt;Adamdar/CA&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage and storytelling narratives from Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Uzbekistan, and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: CABAR</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/cabar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/cabar/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2016 and based under the Institute’s for War and Peace Reporting (IWPR) Central Asian Office, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cabar.asia/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Bureau for Analytical Reporting (CABAR)&lt;/a&gt; offers regional analytical, informational, and educational material on Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Calvert Journal (The)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/calvert_journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/calvert_journal/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013 and owned by a UK-based non-profit Calvert 22 Foundation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.calvertjournal.com/&#34;&gt;The Calvert Journal&lt;/a&gt; offers publications on culture, innovation, photography, and travel in Central Asia, Caucasus, Russia, the Balkans, and Eastern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asia Barometer</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_asia_barometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_asia_barometer/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ca-barometer.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asia Barometer (CAB)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional independent NGO for applied social research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAB Survey Project is a multinational empirical survey on human beliefs and values first conducted in 2017. Questionnaires identify gender of the respondents with two options included, male or female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAB provides free access to databases of the CAB Survey Project available in SPSS, Excel, and Stata formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note &lt;a href=&#34;https://ca-barometer.org/en/what-we-do/methodology/research-methods&#34;&gt;is available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asian Analytical Network</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_asian_analytical_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_asian_analytical_network/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded on the basis of the George Washington University’s Institute for European, Russian, and Eurasian Studies (IERES), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.caa-network.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Analytical Network&lt;/a&gt; offers editorial and opinion pieces, interviews, book and publication reviews, and expert projects on politics, society, and economics of Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Current Time Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/current_time_asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/current_time_asia/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Based in Prague, Czech Republic, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.currenttime.tv/asia/&#34;&gt;Current Time Asia&lt;/a&gt; was created by the Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, a US Congress-funded broadcasting organization, with participation of Voice of America. Offers news, reports, investigations, and interviews covering Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Diplomat (The)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/diplomat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/diplomat/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002 and based in Arlington, Virginia, &lt;a href=&#34;https://thediplomat.com/&#34;&gt;The Diplomat&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Eurasia Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2004 and based in Washington, DC, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/where-we-work/asia/&#34;&gt;Eurasia Foundation&lt;/a&gt; works with international, national, and local partners for community action. The foundation has a variety of international and local donors. Areas of expertise include civil society, youth and leadership, media, governance, and [gender and marginalized communities] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&#34;&gt;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Eurasianet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasianet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasianet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1999 and based at Columbia University’s Harriman Institute, &lt;a href=&#34;https://eurasianet.org/&#34;&gt;Eurasianet.org&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Central Asia and South Caucasus.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Foreign Policy Research Institute</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/foreign_policy_research_institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/foreign_policy_research_institute/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002, based in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fpri.org/central-asia-initiative/&#34;&gt;Foreign Policy Research Institute&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to producing research and policy analysis with the focus on foreign policy and national security challenges facing the US. Its Central Asia Initiative produces analyses of trends in the region concerning the US national security.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Mediazona Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mediazona/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/mediazona/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2014 in Russia, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mediazona.ca/&#34;&gt;Mediazona Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; covers current events in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, and Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Novastan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/novastan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/novastan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2011 in Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan and based in Paris and Berlin, &lt;a href=&#34;https://novastan.org/&#34;&gt;Novastan&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, Uzbekistan, and the Uyghur region.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: OCCRP</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/occrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/occrp/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005 in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.occrp.org/&#34;&gt;Organized Crime and Corruption Reporting Project&lt;/a&gt; aims to develop and equip a global network of investigative journalists, as well as publish stories exposing crime and corruption. The project regularly covers post-Soviet and Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: PONARS Eurasia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ponars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ponars/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in the late 1990s and currently based at the George Washington University’s Institute for European, Russian, and Eurasian Studies (IERES), the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ponarseurasia.org/&#34;&gt;Program on New Approaches to Research and Security in Eurasia (PONARS Eurasia)&lt;/a&gt; offers policy analysis and dialogue. The program aims to advance new approaches in research on security, politics, economics, and society in Russia and Eurasia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Prague Civil Society Centre</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2014 and based in Prague, the Czech Republic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.praguecivilsociety.org/&#34;&gt;Prague Civil Society Centre&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to enabling civic groups and journalists to connect with their communities through grant making, capacity building, and learning. The Centre is funded by governments of Sweden, the Czech Republic, the UK, and the US, as well as the European Commission, the Oak Foundation, and the Wellspring Philanthropic Fund. Focuses on Eastern Europe and Central Asia. In addition to civil society programs, the Centre publishes media and publications on various topics related to the civic groups in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/central-asia&#34;&gt;Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt; is a research and advocacy campaign dedicated to eliminating sexual and gender-based violence and harmful practices in Central Asia. The program involves UN Women, UNDP, and UNFPA with funding from the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan 2020 report is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/publications/spotlight-initiative-central-asia-and-afghanistan-programme-report-2020&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt; in English. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/projects/spotlight-initiative-regional-programme-central-asia-and-afghanistan&#34;&gt;UNDP project page for the Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oxus_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oxus_society/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oxussociety.org/&#34;&gt;The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs&lt;/a&gt; is a Washington, DC-based NGO aimed at fostering academic exchange between Central Asia and the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Oxus Society publishes datasets on articles and books on Central Asia, as well as a directory of researchers studying Central Asia. The NGO also publishes reports on various topic, particularly pertaining to international relations, religion, and domestic politics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
