<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – activism</title>
    <link>/tags/activism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in activism on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/activism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Artyq Emes</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artyqemes&#34;&gt;Artyq Emes&lt;/a&gt; is a human rights project that researches fat phobia and fat-shaming in Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram and YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: FemAgora</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/femagora/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/femagora/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://femagora.org/&#34;&gt;FemAgora&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to fostering transnational feminist solidarity in Central Asia. The organization is involved in organization of Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march and the issue of employment of transgender people. FemAgora hosts annual FemAgora Central Asian festival for those involved in feminist, gender-sensitive, and/or women-led work.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: FemPoint</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fempoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fempoint/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/fempoint_kz/&#34;&gt;FemPoint&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots organization for LBT women providing support resources and engaged in advocacy and activism.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kaz Fem</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kazfem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kazfem/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/kaz_fem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots feminist organization dedicated to research and development of feminist theory in Kazakhstan. One of the leading organizations behind Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march. Available mostly in Russian with occasional material in Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: MISK</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/misk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/misk/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1998 &lt;a href=&#34;https://misk.org.kz/&#34;&gt;MISK (Kazakhstani Informational Youth Service)&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to research on youth, monitoring youth policy legislation, and human rights training. Key projects of the organization include School of Human Rights and School of Civil Education. MISK also regularly published surveys on various social issues. Summary of survey findings include brief information on sample sizes of each survey. Available in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Oyan, Qazaqstan!</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/oyanqazaqstankz/&#34;&gt;Oyan, Qazaqstan!&lt;/a&gt; is a social movement advocating for political reforms in Kazakhstan. The organization shares news about political events, activist campaigns, organizing efforts, as well as prosecution of activists by the state authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Soros Kazakhstan Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/soros_foundation-kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1995 by the Open Society Institute, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soros.kz&#34;&gt;Soros Kazakhstan Foundation&lt;/a&gt; funds multiple scholarship programs, educational courses, and research and activist initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundation publishes research works of various organizations and authors produced with the foundation’s support and/or collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available primarily in Russian with translations into Kazakh and English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: SVET</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/svet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/svet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://svetpf.org/&#34;&gt;SVET&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani foundation dedicated to helping survivors of gender-based violence and sharing relevant news.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
