<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Local Ngo on CAMGDP</title>
    <link>https://camgdp.org/tags/local-ngo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Local Ngo on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 21:15:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://camgdp.org/tags/local-ngo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bahor/Vesna</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/bahor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/bahor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;facebook.com/people/Bahor-%D0%92%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BD%D0%B0/&#34;&gt;Bahor/Vesna&lt;/a&gt; is a self-organized group of cultural immigrant-workers from Russia, Belarus, and Ukraine who have migrated to Uzbekistan following the escalation of Russia&amp;rsquo;s invasion of Ukraine. The initiative covers educational and cultural events in Uzbekistan. Bahor/Vesna is described as a project born out of necessity to &amp;ldquo;find connections during the tragic events affecting millions of residents in Ukraine, Russia, and other countries.&amp;rdquo; The initiative mostly focuses on music and contemporary art, as well as cinematography, literature, and research. It has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bahorvesnaa/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/bahorvesna&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8YmBSTfITo0VZ9zZkG6ShQ&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moc Creative Org</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/moc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/moc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.facebook.com/org.moc&#34;&gt;Moc Creative Org&lt;/a&gt; is a collective of creators, producers, artists, designers, musicians, and photographers. The initiative is focused on organization of events in Uzbekistan, including music festivals, educational and professional trainings, and art exhibits. It is present on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/moc__org/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/moc24&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qizlar</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/qizlar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/qizlar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qizlarqizlarqizlar/&#34;&gt;Qizlar&lt;/a&gt; is an independent collective of women-creators from Uzbekistan. The collective&amp;rsquo;s mission is described as spotlighting projects and products created by women and non-binary people, as well as fostering safe and friendly space for minorities. Qizlar also works on projects with a decolonial agenda aimed at &amp;ldquo;understanding and working out identities as a product of complex post-colonial processes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qizlar Ovozi</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/qizlar_ovozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/qizlar_ovozi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qizlarovozi.uz/&#34;&gt;Qizlar Ovozi&lt;/a&gt; is a school aimed at motivating and helping girls and young women aged 14 to 30 years in their professional development. The school also intends to increase and strengthen women&amp;rsquo;s role in public life. Qizlar Ovozi was founded by Nilufar Kiyamova.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
