<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – Turkmenistan</title>
    <link>/countries/turkmenistan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Turkmenistan on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/countries/turkmenistan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Artif</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/artif/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artif.ication/&#34;&gt;Artif&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform connecting artists, human rights defenders, and activists from Eastern Europe and Central Asia. The platform&amp;rsquo;s mission is to voice social problems using art accessible to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ECOM</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ecom/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecom.ngo/&#34;&gt;ECOM (Eurasian Coalition for Health, Rights, Gender and Sexual Diversity)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional NGO working the sphere of health of LGBTI communities in Eastern Europe and Central Asia. It is a membership association open to non-profit organizations and activists working in the field. ECOM publishes regular reports on violation of rights of the LGBTI people in various Central Asian countries, including Uzbekistan and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: ILGA-Europe</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ilga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ilga/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ilga-europe.org/&#34;&gt;ILGA-Europe&lt;/a&gt; is an International NGO advocating for the protection of LGBTI people and uniting over 600 organizations from 54 countries across Europe and Central Asia. ILGA conducts its work through resourcing and connecting communities, driving political change, and amplifying voices. Its mission is to provide a solid foundation for activists and organizations. ILGA publishes reports on the protection of rights of LGBTI people in Central Asia, specifically related to violence and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Trans*Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transcoalition.net/&#34;&gt;Trans*Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a platform for trans- and non-binary activists from the countries of the Caucasus, Central Asia and Eastern Europe. It advocates for uniting, solidarizing, strengthening the voice of the trans-activist community in our region through the development of a sustainable, effective, authoritative, and resourceful organization. Key areas of Trans&lt;em&gt;Coalition&amp;rsquo;s work include response to the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, depathologizing, sex work, and legislation. In Central Asia, Trans&lt;/em&gt;Coalition offers a hot line, a map of resources and aid, and information for trans sex workers.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
