<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – regional media</title>
    <link>/category/regional-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in regional media on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/category/regional-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ariadna</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ariadna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ariadna/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ariadna.media&#34;&gt;Ariadna&lt;/a&gt; is a Central Asia media dedicated to covering the art scene of the region using accessible language. It provides reviews, editorials, and audioguides.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA&#43;)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mofa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/mofa/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/femmuseum/&#34;&gt;Central Asian Museum of Feminist and Queer Art (MoFA+)&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots media spotlighting feminist and queer artists from Central Asia. MoFA+ also shares art exhibits, events, and publications on feminist and queer art in Central Asia. It appears to be primarily based at the Kyrgyz National Museum of Fine Arts named after Gapar Aitiev and located in Bishkek.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ruyo Journal</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ruyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ruyo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruyojournal.com&#34;&gt;Ruyo Journal&lt;/a&gt; is an artist-led digital media focused on critical discourse on art, film, and theory in Central Asia. Its goal is to &amp;ldquo;support the development of a flourishing cultural scene in Central Asia by providing a platform for thoughtful and engaging discussions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Artif</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/artif/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artif.ication/&#34;&gt;Artif&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform connecting artists, human rights defenders, and activists from Eastern Europe and Central Asia. The platform&amp;rsquo;s mission is to voice social problems using art accessible to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
