<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – 2020</title>
    <link>/date_end/2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2020 on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/date_end/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Caspiana</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/caspiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/caspiana/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/&#34;&gt;Caspiana&lt;/a&gt;: A Digital Toolbox for Students and Scholars of Central Asia and the South Caucasus is a website created to facilitate research on the fascinating regions spreading east and west of the Caspian Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notably the site contains sections on &lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/exhibits/show/governance&#34;&gt;Governance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/exhibits/show/media&#34;&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/exhibits/show/statistics&#34;&gt;Statistics&lt;/a&gt; that link to major government offices and information providers. Additional material includes academic resources such as conferences and language learning links.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Generations and Gender Survey - Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/generations_and_gender_survey_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/generations_and_gender_survey_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ggp.colectica.org/item/int.ggp/009e728f-77f1-4c45-88be-e3bc1acb5bfa/1&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan data&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ggp-i.org/&#34;&gt;Generations and Gender Survey&lt;/a&gt; for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data covers the non-institutionalized, resident population aged 18-79 in Kazakhstan on 2nd April 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Generations and Gender Survey (GGS) data provides micro-level data that can be used to investigate partnership dynamics, transition to adulthood, fertility, care and support networks, division of household tasks, and contraception, among other topics. These data are an essential resource in the understanding of fundamental societal challenges across Europe and beyond and form a substantial basis for the formulation of evidence-based policies. Key features of the survey are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cross-national comparability: The comparative focus allows analyses of the ways in which policies, culture and economic circumstances influence dependencies between men and women and between the young and the old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A longitudinal design: The GGP survey applies a panel design - collecting information on the same persons at three-year intervals - to allow the examination of causes and consequences of inequalities between genders and generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large sample size: The GGP survey has an average of 10,000 respondents per country, making it possible to study numerical minorities and uncommon events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A broad age range: The GGP collects data on the whole life course by interviewing respondents aged 18-79. It also enables analysis of multiple generations by asking extensive questions about intergenerational exchange and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combination of micro and macro data: Alongside the micro data collected via surveys, the GGP has a contextual database with over 100 indicators which cover not only the year of the survey but also retrospective indicators covering the past 40 years to be used alongside the retrospective data in the surveys. A theory-driven and multidisciplinary questionnaire: The GGS questionnaire is developed and maintained by a team of leading social scientists from demography, sociology and economics. The questionnaire seeks to bring together a wide range of subjects that examine the causes and consequences of family change.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Values Survey (Kazakhstan)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_values_survey_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_values_survey_kz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldvaluessurvey.org/WVSOnline.jsp&#34;&gt;World Values Survey&lt;/a&gt; studies social, political, economic, religious and cultural values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is included in waves 6 (2010-2014) and 7 (2017-2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some relevant questions include questions about women’s leadership skills, women’s rights, familial fiscal responsibilities, acceptance of homosexuality, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sample size is 1,500 and 1,276 in waves 6 and 7 respectively. A lot of questions are missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Country Data Sheet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/&#34;&gt;UN Women Country Data Sheet&lt;/a&gt; offers country specific gender-related data across four main components: economic, social, political, and environmental. Data sheets are available for &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kyrgyzstan&#34;&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/mongolia&#34;&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/tajikistan&#34;&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/turkmenistan&#34;&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;,. Some of the economic data is missing, while environmental data does not include a gender-based breakdown. Gender-specific indicators have at least 50% of data missing across the 17 indicators listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection is &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/modules/custom/country_fact_sheet/pdf/MethodologicalNote.pdf&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
