<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feminism on CAMGDP</title>
    <link>https://camgdp.org/tags/feminism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feminism on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 23:08:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://camgdp.org/tags/feminism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bulbul Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/bulbul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/bulbul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bulbulpodcasts/&#34;&gt;Bulbul Podcasts&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast studio that produces shows about Kazakhstani women&amp;rsquo;s histories and stories, as well as culture and music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FemAgora</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/femagora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/femagora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://femagora.org/&#34;&gt;FemAgora&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to fostering transnational feminist solidarity in Central Asia. The organization is involved in organization of Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march and the issue of employment of transgender people. FemAgora hosts annual FemAgora Central Asian festival for those involved in feminist, gender-sensitive, and/or women-led work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feminist Translocalities</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/feminist_translocalities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminisms.co/&#34;&gt;Feminist Translocalities&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots transnational feminist organization aiming to bring together and support feminist and LGBTQ+ activists from Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia. The organization publishes magazine articles and zines, hosts events, and engages in other various projects. Although the website describes the organization as primarily focused on Ukraine, Belarus, and Russia, it frequently publishes works by Central Asian authors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feminita</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/feminita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/feminita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminita.kz/&#34;&gt;Feminita&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots queer feminist collective. Feminita aims to create and strengthen the rights of women and activist communities and empower the most oppressed groups of Kazakhstani population (lesbian, bisexual, queer, women with disabilities, women in sex work). Currently, the organization works on three research projects: assessment of needs of LBQ women; health conditions of LBQT women and transgender men; and sexual wellness of LBQ women. Methodology and research design sections are included in the first two project reports. The reports are available in Russian with occasional translation to Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaz Fem</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/kazfem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/kazfem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/kaz_fem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots feminist organization dedicated to research and development of feminist theory in Kazakhstan. One of the leading organizations behind Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march. Available mostly in Russian with occasional material in Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruyo Journal</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ruyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ruyo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruyojournal.com&#34;&gt;Ruyo Journal&lt;/a&gt; is an artist-led digital media focused on critical discourse on art, film, and theory in Central Asia. Its goal is to &amp;ldquo;support the development of a flourishing cultural scene in Central Asia by providing a platform for thoughtful and engaging discussions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antiuniversity of Feminism</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/antiuniversity_of_feminism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/antiuniversity_of_feminism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/antiuniversity_of_feminism/&#34;&gt;Antiuniversity of Feminism&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project aimed at creating a safe space for women and people with all gender identities to learn about feminism and gender theory. Antiuniversity offers free online courses in Kyrgyz. The project was founded and created by Elvira Tilek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exponaut</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/exponaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/exponaut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/exponautz/&#34;&gt;Exponaut&lt;/a&gt; is an independent media geared toward a younger audience. It covers art and culture, as well as creating projects meant to spotlight women and LGBTQIA+ community of Uzbekistan. Exponaut also has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/exponautz/729&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trans*Coalition</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/trans_coalition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transcoalition.net/&#34;&gt;Trans*Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a platform for trans- and non-binary activists from the countries of the Caucasus, Central Asia and Eastern Europe. It advocates for uniting, solidarizing, strengthening the voice of the trans-activist community in our region through the development of a sustainable, effective, authoritative, and resourceful organization. Key areas of Trans&lt;em&gt;Coalition&amp;rsquo;s work include response to the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, depathologizing, sex work, and legislation. In Central Asia, Trans&lt;/em&gt;Coalition offers a hot line, a map of resources and aid, and information for trans sex workers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artyq Emes</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artyqemes&#34;&gt;Artyq Emes&lt;/a&gt; is a human rights project that researches fat phobia and fat-shaming in Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram and YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FemPoint</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/fempoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/fempoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/fempoint_kz/&#34;&gt;FemPoint&lt;/a&gt; is grassroots organization for LBT women providing support resources and engaged in advocacy and activism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SVET</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/svet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/svet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://svetpf.org/&#34;&gt;SVET&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani foundation dedicated to helping survivors of gender-based violence and sharing relevant news.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/women_of_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/women_of_kz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/womenofkz/&#34;&gt;Women of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is a first online museum of documenting the past and present of Kazakhstani women with a focus on historical research. Available in English, Kazakh, and Russian on Instagram, Twitter, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
