<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2019 on CAMGDP</title>
    <link>https://camgdp.org/date_start/2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019 on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 20:55:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://camgdp.org/date_start/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dope Soz</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/dope_soz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/dope_soz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@DOPESOZ/&#34;&gt;Dope Soz&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series offering discussions and conversations about social, historical, political, and cultural events and discourses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILGA-Europe</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ilga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ilga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ilga-europe.org/&#34;&gt;ILGA-Europe&lt;/a&gt; is an International NGO advocating for the protection of LGBTI people and uniting over 600 organizations from 54 countries across Europe and Central Asia. ILGA conducts its work through resourcing and connecting communities, driving political change, and amplifying voices. Its mission is to provide a solid foundation for activists and organizations. ILGA publishes reports on the protection of rights of LGBTI people in Central Asia, specifically related to violence and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEDxAbayStWomen</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First held in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tedxabaystwomen/&#34;&gt;TEDxAbayStWomen&lt;/a&gt; is a noncommercial conference on gender equality usually held in Almaty, Kazakhstan. Next conference is expected to be held in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECOM</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ecom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecom.ngo/&#34;&gt;ECOM (Eurasian Coalition for Health, Rights, Gender and Sexual Diversity)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional NGO working the sphere of health of LGBTI communities in Eastern Europe and Central Asia. It is a membership association open to non-profit organizations and activists working in the field. ECOM publishes regular reports on violation of rights of the LGBTI people in various Central Asian countries, including Uzbekistan and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exponaut</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/exponaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/exponaut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/exponautz/&#34;&gt;Exponaut&lt;/a&gt; is an independent media geared toward a younger audience. It covers art and culture, as well as creating projects meant to spotlight women and LGBTQIA+ community of Uzbekistan. Exponaut also has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/exponautz/729&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Women Country Data Sheet</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/&#34;&gt;UN Women Country Data Sheet&lt;/a&gt; offers country specific gender-related data across four main components: economic, social, political, and environmental. Data sheets are available for &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kyrgyzstan&#34;&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/mongolia&#34;&gt;Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/tajikistan&#34;&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/turkmenistan&#34;&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt;,. Some of the economic data is missing, while environmental data does not include a gender-based breakdown. Gender-specific indicators have at least 50% of data missing across the 17 indicators listed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection is &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/modules/custom/country_fact_sheet/pdf/MethodologicalNote.pdf&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nghrdc.kz/&#34;&gt;New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a coalition of Kazakhstani human rights defenders including practicing experts in the field of international human rights law, human rights researchers, leaders, and members of NGOs. The Coalition is engaged in informational campaigns, educational training, and other public events organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oyan, Qazaqstan!</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/oyanqazaqstankz/&#34;&gt;Oyan, Qazaqstan!&lt;/a&gt; is a social movement advocating for political reforms in Kazakhstan. The organization shares news about political events, activist campaigns, organizing efforts, as well as prosecution of activists by the state authorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
