<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – 2019</title>
    <link>/date_start/2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019 on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/date_start/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/new_generation_of_human_rights_defenders_coalition/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nghrdc.kz/&#34;&gt;New Generation of Human Rights Defenders Coalition&lt;/a&gt; is a coalition of Kazakhstani human rights defenders including practicing experts in the field of international human rights law, human rights researchers, leaders, and members of NGOs. The Coalition is engaged in informational campaigns, educational training, and other public events organization.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Oyan, Qazaqstan!</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/oyanqazaqstankz/&#34;&gt;Oyan, Qazaqstan!&lt;/a&gt; is a social movement advocating for political reforms in Kazakhstan. The organization shares news about political events, activist campaigns, organizing efforts, as well as prosecution of activists by the state authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Country Data Sheet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UN Women Country Data Sheet&lt;/a&gt; offers country specific gender-related data across four main components: economic, social, political, and environmental. Some of the economic data is missing, while environmental data does not include a gender-based breakdown. Gender-specific indicators have at least 50% of data missing across the 17 indicators listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection is &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/modules/custom/country_fact_sheet/pdf/MethodologicalNote.pdf&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
