<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uzbek on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</title>
    <link>/language/uzbek/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uzbek on CAMGDP: Central Asia and Mongolia Gender Data Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 16:22:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/language/uzbek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>National Statistics Committee of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/stat_gov_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/stat_gov_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz&#34;&gt;National Statistics Committee of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; provides fundamental economic, social, and other demographic statistics about Uzbekistan. Education, healthcare, economy, population, employment, and living standards are among the many categories of data available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statistics are available as downloadable tables in Excel format and as publications, including a special section on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/&#34;&gt;Gender Statistics&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/gender_stat_uz/&#34;&gt;also described on CAMGDP&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz/en/publications&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; include &lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/en/2020-11-09-06-11-08/women-var-men-in-uzbekistan-facts-and-figures&#34;&gt;Women and Men in Uzbekistan: Facts and Figures&lt;/a&gt;.  The &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz/en/publications/3627-statistical-yearbook-of-the-republic-of-uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Statistical Yearbook of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; and other publications are available for purchase, with only their tables of contents freely viewable. Quarterly reports and other frequently updated releases are typically freely downloadable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Data Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/data_egov_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/data_egov_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.egov.uz&#34;&gt;Open Data Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; provides over 10,000 freely downloadable datasets from more than 150 organizations on various aspects of life in Uzbekistan, including education, health, economy, population, culture, justice, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Datasets are typically available in CSV, Excel, XML, JSON, and RDF formats. Before downloading, a brief pop-up will ask the user to identify the intended use of the data (research, personal, application development, media, or other), but no registration is required.  In addition to keyword search, data can be browsed by topic or organization, and the most recent and most highly rated datasets are highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIAT Integrated Information System (Uzbekistan)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/siat_stat_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/siat_stat_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://siat.stat.uz&#34;&gt;SIAT Integrated Information System&lt;/a&gt; provides detailed statistical tables for economic and social indicators for the Republic of Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After selecting the desired indicator, data may be downloaded in Excel, CSV, PDF, JSON, or XML formats, and may also be graphed online, with downloadable images.  Either time series line charts or cartograms can be selected. Detailed metadata describes the provenance of the data and contacts for further information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The site is navigable in Uzbek, Russian, and English. Most downloads of publications and tables are in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Gender Statistics of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/gender_stat_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/gender_stat_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/&#34;&gt;Gender Statistics&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz&#34;&gt;National Statistics Committee of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; provides highlighted gender indicators on education, fertility, health, labor and employment, and more. These are downloadable in multiple formats (Excel,CSV, PDF, JSON, XML), with dates of coverage typically from the 2000s to the present. The publication &lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/en/2020-11-09-06-11-08/women-var-men-in-uzbekistan-facts-and-figures&#34;&gt;Women and Men in Uzbekistan: Facts and Figures&lt;/a&gt; is also available here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the words of the site, &amp;ldquo;Gender statistics are statistics that adequately reflect the real situation of women and men in all strategic areas in order to identify gender differences and study them systematically.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loyiha</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/loyiha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/loyiha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@loyiha_project/&#34;&gt;Loyiha&lt;/a&gt; is a video podcast platform designed to &amp;ldquo;inspire and motivate women.&amp;rdquo; It platforms several women-centered podcast series that provide educational content on various career fields, from marketing to education, as well as information on such topics as misogyny, infertility, ecology, and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family and Women&#39;s Committee of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/family_and_womens_committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/family_and_womens_committee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wcu.uz/ru/&#34;&gt;Family and Women&amp;rsquo;s Committee of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is a state institution aimed at protecting women&amp;rsquo;s civil, labor, and human rights. It publishes reports and shares other updates on issues of women and family in the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Institute of Oriental Studies of the Academy of Sciences</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/institute_of_oriental_studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/institute_of_oriental_studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1943, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://beruni.uz/ru/glavnaya/struktura-instituta/item/329-o/%2792zr-fa.html&#34;&gt;Institute of Oriental Studies of the Academy of Sciences&lt;/a&gt; is a Tashkent-based research institution that specializes on collection of manuscripts. At the present time, its manuscript collection contains about 26,000 volumes and includes works written in Uzbek, Arabic, Persian, Tajik, Urdu, Azeri, Ottoman Turkish, Tatar, Turkmen, Uighur and other languages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Library of Uzbekistan named after Alisher Navoi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/national_library_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/national_library_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally founded in 1870, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.natlib.uz/&#34;&gt;National Library of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; received its current name in 2002. It is the main state book depository for national and foreign press, information and research institution, and a methodological center for all libraries of the country. The National Library is located in Tashkent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Against Frotterizm</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/against_frotterizm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/against_frotterizm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/frotterizm.uz/&#34;&gt;Against Frotterizm&lt;/a&gt; is a social campaign project based on voluntary involved. It is combating frotteurism and harassment of women in Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s public transport. The project aims to increase public awareness of the issue, develop mechanisms to detect cases of harassment in public transport, and develop instructions on what to do and how to protect victims if they are harassed on public transport.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amerika Ovozi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/amerika_ovozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/amerika_ovozi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amerikaovozi.com/&#34;&gt;Amerika Ovozi (Voice of America)&lt;/a&gt; is an international multimedia agency launched in 1942 and funded by the US Congress. Its charter was founded in 1976. Since 2016, Amerika Ovozi legally established itself as an independent media with a neutral coverage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daryo</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/daryo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/daryo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://daryo.uz&#34;&gt;Daryo&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news media offering coverage of politics, economics, sport, and culture in Uzbekistan and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Official Website of the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/president_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/president_website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://president.uz/&#34;&gt;Official Website of the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; publishes updates, media, infographics, and legislative documents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qalampir</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qalampir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/qalampir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://qalampir.uz/&#34;&gt;Qalampir&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news and analytics publication with an aim to achieve transparent and quality informational space in the media sector of Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sof.uz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/sof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2016, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sof.uz/&#34;&gt;Sof.uz&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news publication designed to deliver news to a wider audience using accessible language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Agency under the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/statistics_agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/statistics_agency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.uz/&#34;&gt;Statistics Agency under the President of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; publishes official statistical reports and the state&amp;rsquo;s analysis of social and economic processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Government Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uz_gov_portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uz_gov_portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/&#34;&gt;The Government Portal of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is an official website of all thing related to the government of Uzbekistan. It includes information on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.uz/ru/&#34;&gt;gender statistics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/en/pages/government_sites&#34;&gt;a list of government bodies&amp;rsquo; websites&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.uz/en/organizations/kind/local&#34;&gt;a list of local authorities&amp;rsquo; websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan Daily</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uzdaily/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uzdaily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2009, &lt;a href=&#34;http://uzdaily.uz/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan Daily (UzDaily)&lt;/a&gt; is a digital news media with a focus on business and occasional coverage of other Central Asian countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan National News Agency</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 1992, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uza.uz/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan National News Agency (UzA)&lt;/a&gt; is a state-affiliated news media and one of &amp;ldquo;the leading information agency of the country. UzA covers activities of the government agencies in the country, as well as socio-political events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UzReport</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uzreport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uzreport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 1999, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uzreport.news/&#34;&gt;UzReport&lt;/a&gt; is one of the largest news portals in Uzbekistan. It offers coverage of politics, economics, culture, and sports, as well as analytical and interview pieces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Womxn of Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/womxn_of_ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/womxn_of_ca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/womxnofcentralasia/&#34;&gt;Womxn of Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; is a social media project sharing stories and success of Central Asian women in various professional fields. It also has a Spotify-based podcast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xabar</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/xabar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/xabar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 1992 by what is currently Ministry of Digital Technologies of the Republic of Uzbekistan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://xabar.uz/&#34;&gt;Xabar&lt;/a&gt; is a state-affiliated news media covering local and world affairs, technology, and sports.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anhor</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/anhor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/anhor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anhor.uz/&#34;&gt;Anhor&lt;/a&gt; is an independent media that positions itself as a platform for &amp;ldquo;analytics, investigations, and news.&amp;rdquo; The publication&amp;rsquo;s mission is to contribute to effective governing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art - Review</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/art_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/art_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artreviewuz/&#34;&gt;Art - Review&lt;/a&gt; is local media about art and culture in Uzbekistan. It has presence on Instagram, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/artreviewuz&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.facebook.com/artreview.uz&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ayol buyum emas</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ayol_buyum_emas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/ayol_buyum_emas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ayolbuyumemas/&#34;&gt;Ayol buyum emas&lt;/a&gt; is a nascent social project aimed at supporting Uzbek women and combating violence against them. It also has presence in &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/ayolbuyumemas&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bahor/Vesna</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bahor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/bahor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;facebook.com/people/Bahor-%D0%92%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BD%D0%B0/&#34;&gt;Bahor/Vesna&lt;/a&gt; is a self-organized group of cultural immigrant-workers from Russia, Belarus, and Ukraine who have migrated to Uzbekistan following the escalation of Russia&amp;rsquo;s invasion of Ukraine. The initiative covers educational and cultural events in Uzbekistan. Bahor/Vesna is described as a project born out of necessity to &amp;ldquo;find connections during the tragic events affecting millions of residents in Ukraine, Russia, and other countries.&amp;rdquo; The initiative mostly focuses on music and contemporary art, as well as cinematography, literature, and research. It has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bahorvesnaa/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/bahorvesna&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8YmBSTfITo0VZ9zZkG6ShQ&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Center for the Development of Contemporary Journalism in the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/mjdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/mjdc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mjdc.uz/&#34;&gt;Center for the Development of Contemporary Journalism in the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; is an nongovernmental and noncommercial media institution aimed at improving the quality of journalism in Uzbekistan through &amp;ldquo;identifying problem areas, education, creating quality content that meets the highest standards of truthfulness and objectivity.&amp;rdquo; The center offers trainings for journalists, bloggers, and mass communication professionals, as well as workshops for a wider audience on media literacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exponaut</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/exponaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/exponaut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/exponautz/&#34;&gt;Exponaut&lt;/a&gt; is an independent media geared toward a younger audience. It covers art and culture, as well as creating projects meant to spotlight women and LGBTQIA+ community of Uzbekistan. Exponaut also has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/exponautz/729&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kun.Uz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kun_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/kun_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2012, Kun.Uz is an online publication platform with a wide presence across social media platforms. It offers coverage of news events in Uzbekistan and across the world. The publication works in cooperation with the state and public organizations operating on the territory of Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manarifat</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/manarifat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/manarifat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/manarifat/&#34;&gt;Manarifat&lt;/a&gt; is a social media initiative dedicated to matters of sexual and reproductive health of women. It offers educational content on often stigmatized topics related to sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ministry of Employment and Poverty Reduction of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ministry_of_employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/ministry_of_employment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mehnat.uz/&#34;&gt;Ministry of Employment and Poverty Reduction of the Republic of Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; main activity areas include labor and renumeration, employment, labor protection and migration, and anti-corruption legislature. The ministry has &lt;a href=&#34;https://mehnat.uz/ru/pages/gendernoe-ravenstvo&#34;&gt;a page dedicated to gender equality&lt;/a&gt; that details the status of women in the constitution of the Republic of Uzbekistan, as well as details of latest state events related to gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moc Creative Org</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/moc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/moc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.facebook.com/org.moc&#34;&gt;Moc Creative Org&lt;/a&gt; is a collective of creators, producers, artists, designers, musicians, and photographers. The initiative is focused on organization of events in Uzbekistan, including music festivals, educational and professional trainings, and art exhibits. It is present on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/moc__org/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/moc24&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeMolchi.UZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/nemolchi_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/nemolchi_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nemolchi.uz&#34;&gt;NeMolchi.UZ&lt;/a&gt; is an independent information project against gender-based violence in Uzbekistan. Its mission is to draw attention to violence against women and challenge societal attitudes towards the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orda</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/orda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/orda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://orda.kz/&#34;&gt;Orda&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan, as well as journalistic investigations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oydin Nur</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oydin_nur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/oydin_nur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1999, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/oydinnur.uz/&#34;&gt;Regional Center for Social Protection of the Family &amp;ldquo;Oydin Nur&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a shelter in the the Bukhara Region of Uzbekistan that offers long term shelter to female victims of gender-based violence, as well as legal and medical services and resources for personal development. The center organizes seminars and trainings concerning issues of women in the country. State departments of internal affairs, education, and health are listed as partners of Oydin Nur.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qizlar</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qizlar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/qizlar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qizlarqizlarqizlar/&#34;&gt;Qizlar&lt;/a&gt; is an independent collective of women-creators from Uzbekistan. The collective&amp;rsquo;s mission is described as spotlighting projects and products created by women and non-binary people, as well as fostering safe and friendly space for minorities. Qizlar also works on projects with a decolonial agenda aimed at &amp;ldquo;understanding and working out identities as a product of complex post-colonial processes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qizlar Ovozi</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qizlar_ovozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/qizlar_ovozi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qizlarovozi.uz/&#34;&gt;Qizlar Ovozi&lt;/a&gt; is a school aimed at motivating and helping girls and young women aged 14 to 30 years in their professional development. The school also intends to increase and strengthen women&amp;rsquo;s role in public life. Qizlar Ovozi was founded by Nilufar Kiyamova.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sarpa</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sarpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/sarpa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sarpa.media&#34;&gt;Sarpa&lt;/a&gt; is independent Uzbek media with a focus on human rights, democracy, and gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sening mening haqqimiz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/sening_mening_haqqimiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/sening_mening_haqqimiz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/sening_mening_haqqimiz/&#34;&gt;Sening mening haqqimiz&lt;/a&gt; is a social media account advocating for women&amp;rsquo;s rights, education, and development in Uzbekistan. On its Instagram page, sening mening haqqimiz shares relevant resources and news. The initiative is particularly focused on issues of violence against women.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan Art and Culture Development Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/acdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/acdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.acdf.uz/&#34;&gt;The Art and Culture Development Foundation of the Republic of Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; fosters international cooperation&#xA;and promotes the culture of Uzbekistan on the international arena. Its mission is to create an &amp;ldquo;inclusive and accessible environment in the country&amp;rsquo;s cultural institutions, contribute to renovation of museums, and to develop cultural patronage and professional training for the arts and culture sector.&amp;rdquo; It appears to be a state-affiliated organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan with a Female Voice</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uzbekistan_with_a_female_voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/uzbekistan_with_a_female_voice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/uzbekistanwithafemalevoice/&#34;&gt;Uzbekistan with a Female Voice&lt;/a&gt; is a social media initiative that advocates for gender equality and women empowerment in Uzbekistan by spotlighting stories of Uzbek women and sharing relevant events and news. It has presence on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Ozbekistonayollarkozibilan/&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.me/uzbekayol&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friedrich Ebert Stiftung</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fes_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/fes_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/fesuzbekistan/&#34;&gt;FES Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; was founded in 1997. The foundation&amp;rsquo;s mission in the country is stated as promoting ideas of inclusive society and contributing to the development of just economic and social politics, as well as supporting civil society, labor unions, and gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Organization for Migration</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/iom_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/iom_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iom.int/countries/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;IOM&lt;/a&gt; presence in Uzbekistan began in 2003. In 2019, Uzbekistan officially became a member-state of the IOM. The organization was officially accredited in April 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are currently no reports or country-specific research conducted by the IOM in Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oxus_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/oxus_society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oxussociety.org/&#34;&gt;The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs&lt;/a&gt; is a Washington, DC-based NGO aimed at fostering academic exchange between Central Asia and the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Oxus Society publishes datasets on articles and books on Central Asia, as well as a directory of researchers studying Central Asia. The NGO also publishes reports on various topic, particularly pertaining to international relations, religion, and domestic politics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TAG news</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tag_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sources/sources/tag_news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded first in 2008 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kaztag.kz/ru/&#34;&gt;TAG news agency&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Afghanistan, Iran, and the Silk Road region. Available in English, Kazakh, and Russian in Kazakhstan; Kyrgyz and Russian in Kyrgyzstan; Uzbek and Russian in Uzbekistan; and Tajik and Russian in Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
