<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Policy on CAMGDP</title>
    <link>https://camgdp.org/data_type/policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Policy on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 21:15:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://camgdp.org/data_type/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Akimat of the city of Astana</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/astana/about?lang=en&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Astana&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the akimat (regional administration) of the capital city Astana. Contains official documents, press releases, and statistical data of the city. Offers latest news about the capital’s governance. The information is divided into several directions, including familial and demographic policies, culture, civil society, youth, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ministry of Employment and Poverty Reduction of the Republic of Uzbekistan</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ministry_of_employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ministry_of_employment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mehnat.uz/&#34;&gt;Ministry of Employment and Poverty Reduction of the Republic of Uzbekistan&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; main activity areas include labor and renumeration, employment, labor protection and migration, and anti-corruption legislature. The ministry has &lt;a href=&#34;https://mehnat.uz/ru/pages/gendernoe-ravenstvo&#34;&gt;a page dedicated to gender equality&lt;/a&gt; that details the status of women in the constitution of the Republic of Uzbekistan, as well as details of latest state events related to gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Policy Research Institute</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/foreign_policy_research_institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/foreign_policy_research_institute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002, based in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fpri.org/central-asia-initiative/&#34;&gt;Foreign Policy Research Institute&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to producing research and policy analysis with the focus on foreign policy and national security challenges facing the US. Its Central Asia Initiative produces analyses of trends in the region concerning the US national security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adilet.Zan</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/adilet_zan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/adilet_zan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/&#34;&gt;Adilet.Zan&lt;/a&gt; is a legal information system of Regulatory Legal Acts under the Ministry of Justice Institute of Legislation and Legal Information. The database contains more than 330 thousand legal documents, including Kazakhstan’s Concept of Family and Gender Policies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ak Orda</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ak_orda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ak_orda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.akorda.kz/&#34;&gt;Ak Orda&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, such as the constitution, state strategies and programs, and constitutional laws, as well as an archive of the documents. The website is not search friendly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akimat of the city of Almaty</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_almaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_almaty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/almaty?lang=en&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Almaty&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the akimat (regional administration) of Almaty, the largest city in Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, press releases, and statistical data of the city. Offers latest news about Almaty’s governance. The information is divided into several directions, including social sphere, culture, society, youth policies, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Communication Service under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/central_communication_service_under_the_president_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/central_communication_service_under_the_president_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ortcom.kz/en/&#34;&gt;Central Communication Service under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is the official communication service for presidential and state affairs aimed at fostering communication between the government bodies and media. Contains latest news (including regional news), press releases, infographics, video announcements, and expert discussions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Commission for Women Affairs and Familial Demographic Policies</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/national_commission_for_women_affairs_and_familial_demographic_policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/national_commission_for_women_affairs_and_familial_demographic_policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Established in 2006 by the first president Nursultan Nazarbayev, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.akorda.kz/ru/executive_office/presidential_commissions/commission_for_women&#34;&gt;National Commission for Women Affairs and Familial Demographic Policies&lt;/a&gt; serves as a consultative and advisory body under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan. One of the main goals of the commission is the development of recommendations for setting priorities and forming and implementing a comprehensive state policy regarding the family, equality of women and men in the context of the &amp;ldquo;Strategy &amp;ldquo;Kazakhstan - 2050: a new political course of an established state.&amp;rdquo; The text of the original 2006 decree could be found in Russian &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/rus/docs/U060000056_&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. As of May 2022, the composition of the commission can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.akorda.kz/ru/o-vnesenii-izmeneniy-i-dopolneniya-v-ukaz-prezidenta-respubliki-kazahstan-ot-1-fevralya-2006-goda-56-o-nacionalnoy-komissii-po-delam-zhenshchin-i-semeyno-demograficheskoy-politike-pri-prezidente-respubliki-kazahstan-1842638&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Current president of the commission, Karakat Abden, Kazakhstani author, politician, and public figure, &lt;a href=&#34;https://esquire.kz/t-v-kazashka-smirisy/&#34;&gt;received public criticism&lt;/a&gt; after the release of her controversial book titled &amp;ldquo;You are a Kazakh Girl. Be Proud!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Official Information Source of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/official_information_source_of_the_prime_minister_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/official_information_source_of_the_prime_minister_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://primeminister.kz/&#34;&gt;Official Information Source of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, such as the state addresses, policies breakdown of the state and advisory bodies, government composition, as well as an archive of the documents. The website is not search friendly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Policy Solutions Center</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://policysolutions.kz/&#34;&gt;Policy Solutions Center&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots organizations of Kazakhstani researchers involved in the study of socio-political and socio-economic problems in Kazakhstan, as well as the development of policy and management recommendations. The Center publishes analytical pieces and develops projects on political, economic, and social issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TengriNews</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/tengrinews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/tengrinews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2016, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tengrinews.kz/&#34;&gt;TengriNews&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage of current events in Kazakhstan and the world and a database of legislative documents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Units to Guard Women against Violence</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/units_to_guard_women_against_violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/units_to_guard_women_against_violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1998, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/rus/docs/V1500012948&#34;&gt;Republic of Kazakhstan Administrations of Internal Affairs’ Units to Guard Women against Violence&lt;/a&gt; is a domestic body on the basis of police work force designed to protect constitutional rights of women, coordinate detention and prosecution processes in the case of the detention of women, and organize work to prevent domestic violence against women. The official text of the establishment of the units &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/rus/docs/V1500012948&#34;&gt;could be found here&lt;/a&gt;. In 2021, Kaz Fem feminist organization &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CXtA7T6MbAM/&#34;&gt;criticized&lt;/a&gt; the compensation policy of the Units’ workers stating that on average its female workers earn less than workers of other internal affairs’ units.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
