<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – economics</title>
    <link>/tags/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in economics on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Asia Barometer</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_asia_barometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_asia_barometer/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ca-barometer.org/&#34;&gt;Central Asia Barometer (CAB)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional independent NGO for applied social research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CAB Survey Project is a multinational empirical survey on human beliefs and values first conducted in 2017. Questionnaires identify gender of the respondents with two options included, male or female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAB provides free access to databases of the CAB Survey Project available in SPSS, Excel, and Stata formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note &lt;a href=&#34;https://ca-barometer.org/en/what-we-do/methodology/research-methods&#34;&gt;is available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: OECD</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oecd_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oecd_uz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Uzbekistan is not a member of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/uzbekistan/&#34;&gt;OECD&lt;/a&gt;. It has recently joined the OECD/G20 Inclusive Framework on BEPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No gender-sensitive data appears to be available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Data Hub</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_data_hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_data_hub/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Publications on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/publications&#34;&gt;UN Women Data Hub&lt;/a&gt; have an option to filter by region.
Eurasia and Central Asia region primarily focuses on Eastern European and Balkan countries with occasional inclusion of Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Themes of publications include data use, disabilities, economic empowerment, ending violence against women, environment, gender and COVID-19, HIV and AIDS, migration, sustainable development, and peace and security.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Gender Economics Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/gerc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/gerc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 with the assistance of the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.narxoz.kz/research/institutes/gerc&#34;&gt;Gender Economics Research Center (GERC)&lt;/a&gt; is a research center at Narxoz University, Almaty. GERC is dedicated to development and coordination of research on gender and economy. The center publishes research articles and reports on the topics of labor market, education, COVID-19 impact, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oecd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oecd/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is not a member of the OECD and acts as its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;partner for the Eurasian region&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of available data on Kazakhstan found on the OECD portal, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/gender-policy-delivery-in-kazakhstan-9789264280359-en.htm&#34;&gt;2017 Gender Policy Delivery in Kazakhstan review&lt;/a&gt; is so far the only gender-related publication on Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The review contains policy assessment and recommendation. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Policy Solutions Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/policy_solutions_center/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://policysolutions.kz/&#34;&gt;Policy Solutions Center&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots organizations of Kazakhstani researchers involved in the study of socio-political and socio-economic problems in Kazakhstan, as well as the development of policy and management recommendations. The Center publishes analytical pieces and develops projects on political, economic, and social issues.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women Country Data Sheet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_country_data_sheet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/country/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UN Women Country Data Sheet&lt;/a&gt; offers country specific gender-related data across four main components: economic, social, political, and environmental. Some of the economic data is missing, while environmental data does not include a gender-based breakdown. Gender-specific indicators have at least 50% of data missing across the 17 indicators listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection is &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.unwomen.org/modules/custom/country_fact_sheet/pdf/MethodologicalNote.pdf&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UN Women: Europe and Central Asia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/un_women_europe_and_central_asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/un_women_europe_and_central_asia/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://eca.unwomen.org/en/where-we-are/kazakhstan&#34;&gt;UN Women: Europe and Central Asia&lt;/a&gt; provides an overview of the UN initiatives in Kazakhstan, including a list of major international treaties ratified by the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overview includes four main themes: women’s economic empowerment, ending violence against women, national planning and budgeting, and sustainable development agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Bank</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/world_bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/world_bank/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://genderdata.worldbank.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;World Bank Gender Data Portal&lt;/a&gt; offers a breakdown of gender-related data in regards to adolescent fertility rates, education completion rates, literacy levels, labor force participation, vulnerable employment, unpaid domestic work, business and bank account ownership, internet usage, and parliament membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data sources annotation is available under all indicators. It includes development relevance, limitation and exceptions, and statistical concepts and methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datasets are available via CVS, API, and Databank formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wbl.worldbank.org/en/reports&#34;&gt;Women, Business, and the Law Reports&lt;/a&gt; Annual report measuring the laws and regulations that affect women’s economic opportunity in 190 economies, including Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports are available in English with executive summaries in French, Spanish, and Arabic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodology section is available on the website and is based on feedback of &amp;ldquo;more than 2,000 respondents&amp;rdquo; which includes local experts on family, labor, and criminal law, including lawyers, judges, academics, and civil society. It is unclear whether the questionnaires sent out to experts are in English, Russian, or Kazakh languages.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
