<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – 1999</title>
    <link>/date_start/1999/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1999 on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/date_start/1999/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: UzReport</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uzreport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/uzreport/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 1999, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uzreport.news/&#34;&gt;UzReport&lt;/a&gt; is one of the largest news portals in Uzbekistan. It offers coverage of politics, economics, culture, and sports, as well as analytical and interview pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Oydin Nur</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oydin_nur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oydin_nur/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1999, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/oydinnur.uz/&#34;&gt;Regional Center for Social Protection of the Family &amp;ldquo;Oydin Nur&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a shelter in the the Bukhara Region of Uzbekistan that offers long term shelter to female victims of gender-based violence, as well as legal and medical services and resources for personal development. The center organizes seminars and trainings concerning issues of women in the country. State departments of internal affairs, education, and health are listed as partners of Oydin Nur.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Eurasianet</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasianet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasianet/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1999 and based at Columbia University’s Harriman Institute, &lt;a href=&#34;https://eurasianet.org/&#34;&gt;Eurasianet.org&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Central Asia and South Caucasus.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: PONARS Eurasia</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ponars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ponars/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in the late 1990s and currently based at the George Washington University’s Institute for European, Russian, and Eurasian Studies (IERES), the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ponarseurasia.org/&#34;&gt;Program on New Approaches to Research and Security in Eurasia (PONARS Eurasia)&lt;/a&gt; offers policy analysis and dialogue. The program aims to advance new approaches in research on security, politics, economics, and society in Russia and Eurasia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Zakon.kz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/zakon_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/zakon_kz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1999, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zakon.kz/&#34;&gt;Zakon.kz&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, Central Asia, Russia, and the US, as well as analytical materials and interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
