<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – Kazakh</title>
    <link>/language/kazakh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kazakh on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/language/kazakh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Akimat of the city of Astana</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_astana/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/astana/about?lang=en&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Astana&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the akimat (regional administration) of the capital city Astana. Contains official documents, press releases, and statistical data of the city. Offers latest news about the capital’s governance. The information is divided into several directions, including familial and demographic policies, culture, civil society, youth, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: National Archive of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kz_national_archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kz_national_archive/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Opened in 2006, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ulttykarhiv.kz/en/&#34;&gt;National Archive of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is a central repository for historical documents in Kazakhstan. It is located in Astana.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kazakh Research Institute of Culture</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kz_research_institute_of_culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kz_research_institute_of_culture/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;First founded in 1934, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cultural.kz/en/&#34;&gt;Kazakh Research Institute of Culture&lt;/a&gt; is a research center for art, culture, history, and archaeology. Its mission is to &amp;ldquo;conduct an in-depth systemic analysis in the sphere of culture in accordance with the Conception of cultural policy of the Republic of Kazakhstan, integration into world cultural space and effective international cooperation.&amp;rdquo; The institute is located in Almaty.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Adil Qala</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adil_qala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/adil_qala/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adilqala.kz/&#34;&gt;Adil Qala&lt;/a&gt; is a project on social justice in the field of urban planning and development. It aims to create a platform for a &amp;ldquo;broad public dialogue about the priority of the human dimension in urban policies and practices.&amp;rdquo; Adil Qala hosts public discussions and educational programs, including on the topic of LGBTQIA+ safe spaces and visibility and safety of women in urban settings.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ariadna</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ariadna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ariadna/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Launched in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ariadna.media&#34;&gt;Ariadna&lt;/a&gt; is a Central Asia media dedicated to covering the art scene of the region using accessible language. It provides reviews, editorials, and audioguides.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bulbul Podcasts</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bulbul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bulbul/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/bulbulpodcasts/&#34;&gt;Bulbul Podcasts&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast studio that produces shows about Kazakhstani women&amp;rsquo;s histories and stories, as well as culture and music.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Dope Soz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/dope_soz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@DOPESOZ/&#34;&gt;Dope Soz&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast series offering discussions and conversations about social, historical, political, and cultural events and discourses.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: FemAgora</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/femagora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/femagora/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 in Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://femagora.org/&#34;&gt;FemAgora&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to fostering transnational feminist solidarity in Central Asia. The organization is involved in organization of Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march and the issue of employment of transgender people. FemAgora hosts annual FemAgora Central Asian festival for those involved in feminist, gender-sensitive, and/or women-led work.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Feminita</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/feminita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/feminita/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feminita.kz/&#34;&gt;Feminita&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots queer feminist collective. Feminita aims to create and strengthen the rights of women and activist communities and empower the most oppressed groups of Kazakhstani population (lesbian, bisexual, queer, women with disabilities, women in sex work). Currently, the organization works on three research projects: assessment of needs of LBQ women; health conditions of LBQT women and transgender men; and sexual wellness of LBQ women. Methodology and research design sections are included in the first two project reports. The reports are available in Russian with occasional translation to Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kaz Fem</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kazfem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kazfem/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/kaz_fem/&#34;&gt;KazFem&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots feminist organization dedicated to research and development of feminist theory in Kazakhstan. One of the leading organizations behind Kazakhstan’s annual women rights march. Available mostly in Russian with occasional material in Kazakh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kibhr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kibhr/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bureau.kz/&#34;&gt;Kazakhstan International Bureau for Human Rights and Rule of Law (KIBHR)&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani bureau of human rights. It engages in human rights advocacy, shares relevant reports, and engages in human rights monitoring in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Kok.team</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/kok.team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/kok.team/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017 and dissolved in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kok.team/&#34;&gt;Kok.team&lt;/a&gt; was a grassroots LGBT organization dedicated to providing information on the LGBT issues in Kazakh. Digital archive contains articles, podcasts and videos of Kazakhstani LGBT  community. Available in Kazakh and Russian with occasional translation to English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Legal Policy Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/lprc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/lprc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2008 by a group of Kazakhstani lawyers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lprc.kz/&#34;&gt;Legal Policy Research Center (LPRC)&lt;/a&gt; is a non-political, independent research institute promoting the principle of the rule of law and liberal values through the implementation of research, publishing and educational activities in the field of legal policy. Its mission is to strengthen democratic values through effective legal reforms. Its projects include promoting anti-discrimination agenda and combating sexual harassment.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Qara Magan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qara_magan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qara.magan/&#34;&gt;Qara Magan&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project is dedicated to visibility and storytelling of the LGBTQ+ community of Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: QAZAQUEER</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/qazaqueer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/qazaqueer/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/qazaqueer/&#34;&gt;QAZAQUEER&lt;/a&gt; is a social media project on the lives of the LGBTQIA+ community in Kazakhstan. It primarily produces content in Kazakh and offers educational resources on queer identity, relationships, and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Queernyi squirt</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mira Ungarova and Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://podcast.kz/1657513218/info&#34;&gt;Queernyi Squirt&lt;/a&gt; is an 18+ podcast dedicated to inclusive LGBTQIA+ sex education in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Right Now</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/right-now/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 in association with the US Embassy in Kazakhstan and the National Alumi Network of US programs graduates, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/rightnow.kz/&#34;&gt;Right Now&lt;/a&gt; is a social media platform promoting awareness of legal rights in Kazakhstan. It offers online lectures on various topics, including violence against women and children.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Stop Harass</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/stop-harass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/stop-harass/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stopharass.kz/&#34;&gt;Stop Harass&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani harassment prevention and tracking website. Its mission is to &amp;ldquo;engage all residents of Kazakhstan in creating an environment that is intolerant of sexual assault, harassment, stalking, catcalling, etc.&amp;rdquo; The platform allows anyone to report harassment instances either via Telegram bot or website.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: TEDxAbayStWomen</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tedxabaystwomen/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;First held in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tedxabaystwomen/&#34;&gt;TEDxAbayStWomen&lt;/a&gt; is a noncommercial conference on gender equality usually held in Almaty, Kazakhstan. Next conference is expected to be held in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Tolk</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/tolk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/tolk/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2023, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@tolkkz/&#34;&gt;Tolk&lt;/a&gt; is a podcast studio and an audio-hub dedicated to researching contemporary Kazakhstani through interpersonal conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Center of legal protection &#39;Zan Talaby&#39;</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/zan_talaby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/zan_talaby/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/NgoZanTalabyShymkent/&#34;&gt;Center of legal protection &amp;ldquo;Zan Talaby&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a Shymkent-based NGO dedicated to combating human trafficking in Kazakhstan. It offers hotline assistance to victims of human trafficking and actively engages in discussions, awareness campaigns, and educational trainings on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Orda</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/orda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/orda/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://orda.kz/&#34;&gt;Orda&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan, as well as journalistic investigations.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Adamdar/CA</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/adamdar_ca/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adamdar.ca/&#34;&gt;Adamdar/CA&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage and storytelling narratives from Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Uzbekistan, and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oxus_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oxus_society/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oxussociety.org/&#34;&gt;The Oxus Society for Central Asian Affairs&lt;/a&gt; is a Washington, DC-based NGO aimed at fostering academic exchange between Central Asia and the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Oxus Society publishes datasets on articles and books on Central Asia, as well as a directory of researchers studying Central Asia. The NGO also publishes reports on various topic, particularly pertaining to international relations, religion, and domestic politics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Vlast</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/vlast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/vlast/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vlast.kz/&#34;&gt;Vlast&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, as well as various editorial projects.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Adilet.Zan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/adilet_zan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/adilet_zan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/&#34;&gt;Adilet.Zan&lt;/a&gt; is a legal information system of Regulatory Legal Acts under the Ministry of Justice Institute of Legislation and Legal Information. The database contains more than 330 thousand legal documents, including Kazakhstan’s Concept of Family and Gender Policies.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Aiman Umarova School of Rights</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/aiman_umratova_school_of_rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/aiman_umratova_school_of_rights/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://womenrights.kz/&#34;&gt;Aiman Umarova School of Rights&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots informational platform focusing on the problems of women and girls from socially vulnerable background, including gender-based violence. The portal provides brief information on legislative contexts and statistical summaries on the issues of sexual violence, domestic violence, violence against children, LGBTQ rights, etc. Information is available in Kazakh and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Aiman Umarova’s Rights School</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/aiman_umarova_school_of_rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/aiman_umarova_school_of_rights/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://womenrights.kz/&#34;&gt;Aiman Umarova’s Rights School&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots informational platform focusing on the problems of women and girls from socially vulnerable background, including gender-based violence. The portal provides brief information on legislative contexts and statistical summaries on the issues of sexual violence, domestic violence, violence against children, LGBTQ rights, etc. Information is available in Kazakh and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ak Orda</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ak_orda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ak_orda/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.akorda.kz/&#34;&gt;Ak Orda&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, such as the constitution, state strategies and programs, and constitutional laws, as well as an archive of the documents. The website is not search friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Akimat of the city of Almaty</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_almaty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/akimat_of_the_city_of_almaty/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/almaty?lang=en&#34;&gt;Akimat of the city of Almaty&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the akimat (regional administration) of Almaty, the largest city in Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, press releases, and statistical data of the city. Offers latest news about Almaty’s governance. The information is divided into several directions, including social sphere, culture, society, youth policies, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Artyq Emes</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/artyq_emes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/artyqemes&#34;&gt;Artyq Emes&lt;/a&gt; is a human rights project that researches fat phobia and fat-shaming in Kazakhstan. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram and YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Azattyq</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/azattyq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/azattyq/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.azattyq.org/&#34;&gt;Azattyq&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani branch of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, a US Congress-funded broadcasting organization. Offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan, as well as various editorial projects.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Batyr Jamal</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/batyr_jamal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/batyr_jamal/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/batyrjamal/&#34;&gt;Batyr Jamal&lt;/a&gt; is a women-oriented media with coverage primarily focusing on women’s rights, safety, and self-worth. Available on Instagram and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Bureau of National Statistics / Gender</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/bureau_of_national_statistics_gender/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gender.stat.gov.kz/en&#34;&gt;Bureau of National Statistics / Gender&lt;/a&gt; is the official government resource representing a collection of gendered data on population, family, healthcare, education and communication, employment, human rights, and politics. The Bureau has received criticism of its data from a feminist organization &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CUmGoyNsJPu/&#34;&gt;Kaz Fem&lt;/a&gt;. Kaz Fem created &lt;a href=&#34;https://schitaetsya.kz/&#34;&gt;its own alternative platform&lt;/a&gt; about the domestic violence situation in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Central Communication Service under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/central_communication_service_under_the_president_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/central_communication_service_under_the_president_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ortcom.kz/en/&#34;&gt;Central Communication Service under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is the official communication service for presidential and state affairs aimed at fostering communication between the government bodies and media. Contains latest news (including regional news), press releases, infographics, video announcements, and expert discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Crisis Centers Union</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/crisis_centers_union/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2005, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telefon150.kz/&#34;&gt;Crisis Centers Union&lt;/a&gt; unites 18 organizations from 12 regions of Kazakhstan. The Union is aimed at prevention and eradication of all forms of gender-based violence, formation of a non-violent culture in Kazakhstani society. The website offers news articles, photo and video materials, informational materials, webinars, and infographics.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Factcheck.kz</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/factcheck_/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/factcheck_/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/factcheck.kz/&#34;&gt;Factcheck.kz&lt;/a&gt; is a publication focuses on fact checking news and viral media. Available on Instagram, Telegram, TikTok, and YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Fading.TSE</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fading_tse/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/fading.tse/&#34;&gt;Fading.TSE&lt;/a&gt; is a grassroots project documenting urban history of Kazakhstan and its capital. Primary focused on photography, oral histories, and cultural heritage. Available in Kazakh and Russian on Instagram, Facebook, TikTok, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Friedrich Ebert Stiftung</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1925 in Germany with a Kazakhstani office opened in 1993, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.fes.de/&#34;&gt;Friedrich Ebert Stiftung&lt;/a&gt; is a foundation funded by the German government. The INGO focuses on social and gender justice issues, as well as political participation and youth leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications on Kazakhstan include population surveys, particularly focused on youth, and are available in English, Kazakh, and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published surveys include &amp;ldquo;Youth and Education,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Values,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Social Justice.&amp;rdquo; Gendered breakdown of data is included for some survey questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://library.fes.de/pdf-files/bueros/kasachstan/18450.pdf&#34;&gt;Youth in Kazakhstan 2021 survey&lt;/a&gt; has five main section, including (1) values and orientations, (2) life plans, education, employment, and immigration, (3) youth and politics, and (4) foreign policy and attitudes toward Central Asia. The values and orientation section incorporates questions on attitudes toward abortion, homosexuality, different sexual practices, and other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey uses mixed method approach and includes a methodology chapter.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Gender Economics Research Center</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/gerc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/gerc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018 with the assistance of the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.narxoz.kz/research/institutes/gerc&#34;&gt;Gender Economics Research Center (GERC)&lt;/a&gt; is a research center at Narxoz University, Almaty. GERC is dedicated to development and coordination of research on gender and economy. The center publishes research articles and reports on the topics of labor market, education, COVID-19 impact, and others.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: HolaNews</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/holanews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/holanews/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/holanewskz/&#34;&gt;HolaNews&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events in Kazakhstan on Instagram, Facebook, and Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Human Rights KZ</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/human_rights_kz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/human_rights_kz/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/humanrightskz/&#34;&gt;Human Rights KZ&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to sharing domestic and international human rights information and news in Kazakh. Available on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Informburo</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/informburo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/informburo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015 and affiliated with 31st Channel television station, &lt;a href=&#34;https://informburo.kz/&#34;&gt;Informburo&lt;/a&gt; offers news coverage, informational and analytical materials.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Masa Media</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/masa_media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/masa_media/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://masa.media/&#34;&gt;Masa Media&lt;/a&gt; strives to explain political, legal, and legislative systems in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: National Commission for Women Affairs and Familial Demographic Policies</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/national_commission_for_women_affairs_and_familial_demographic_policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/national_commission_for_women_affairs_and_familial_demographic_policies/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Established in 2006 by the first president Nursultan Nazarbayev, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.akorda.kz/ru/executive_office/presidential_commissions/commission_for_women&#34;&gt;National Commission for Women Affairs and Familial Demographic Policies&lt;/a&gt; serves as a consultative and advisory body under the President of the Republic of Kazakhstan. One of the main goals of the commission is the development of recommendations for setting priorities and forming and implementing a comprehensive state policy regarding the family, equality of women and men in the context of the &amp;ldquo;Strategy &amp;ldquo;Kazakhstan - 2050: a new political course of an established state.&amp;rdquo; The text of the original 2006 decree could be found in Russian &lt;a href=&#34;https://adilet.zan.kz/rus/docs/U060000056_&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. As of May 2022, the composition of the commission can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.akorda.kz/ru/o-vnesenii-izmeneniy-i-dopolneniya-v-ukaz-prezidenta-respubliki-kazahstan-ot-1-fevralya-2006-goda-56-o-nacionalnoy-komissii-po-delam-zhenshchin-i-semeyno-demograficheskoy-politike-pri-prezidente-respubliki-kazahstan-1842638&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Current president of the commission, Karakat Abden, Kazakhstani author, politician, and public figure, &lt;a href=&#34;https://esquire.kz/t-v-kazashka-smirisy/&#34;&gt;received public criticism&lt;/a&gt; after the release of her controversial book titled &amp;ldquo;You are a Kazakh Girl. Be Proud!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Official Information Source of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/official_information_source_of_the_prime_minister_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/official_information_source_of_the_prime_minister_of_the_republic_of_kazakhstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://primeminister.kz/&#34;&gt;Official Information Source of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; is the official website of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Kazakhstan. Contains official documents, such as the state addresses, policies breakdown of the state and advisory bodies, government composition, as well as an archive of the documents. The website is not search friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Oyan, Qazaqstan!</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oyan_qazaqstan/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/oyanqazaqstankz/&#34;&gt;Oyan, Qazaqstan!&lt;/a&gt; is a social movement advocating for political reforms in Kazakhstan. The organization shares news about political events, activist campaigns, organizing efforts, as well as prosecution of activists by the state authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: PaperLab</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/paperlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/paperlab/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015 and supported by the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://paperlab.kz/&#34;&gt;PaperLab&lt;/a&gt; is a public policy research organization in Kazakhstan. PaperLab publishes research, organizes public discussions, and offers training and networking opportunities to Central Asian experts. Most publications are in Kazakh and Russian and sometimes in English. PaperLab has done extensive research on sex education in Kazakhstan and frequently collaborates with other NGOs and INGOs on the topic of violence against women. Methodology note and description of sources are not always included in the publications.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: </title>
      <link>/sources/sources/public_opinion_research_institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/public_opinion_research_institute/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opinions.kz/&#34;&gt;Public Opinion Research Institute&lt;/a&gt; is a Kazakhstani sociological institute specializes in public opinion, marketing, and sociological studies of Kazakhstan and other countries. The institute publishes research reports on various topics, including COVID-19, migration, social values, etc. Most publications are available in Kazakh and Russian with occasional translation to English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Ratel</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/ratel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/ratel/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ratel.kz/&#34;&gt;Ratel&lt;/a&gt; offers coverage of current events, opinion pieces, and journalistic investigations in Kazakhstan, specifically concerning corruption. The publication had its license rescinded in 2018 in a court ruling on the grounds of spreading misinformation due to the published investigations of various corruption cases. The site resumed its work in 2019. Available primarily in Russian with occasional publications in Kazakh and English.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
