<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – statistics</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: National Statistical Committee of the Kyrgyz Republic</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/stat_gov_kg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/stat_gov_kg/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg&#34;&gt;National Statistical Committee of the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt; provides fundamental economic, social, and other demographic statistics about Kyrgyzstan. Education, healthcare, economy, population, employment, and living standards are among the many categories of data available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistics are available as downloadable tables in Excel format and as publications, including a special section on &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/gendernaya-statistika/&#34;&gt;Gender Statistics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications include the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/publications/statisticheskij-ezhegodnik-kyrgyzskoj-respubliki/&#34;&gt;Statistical Yearbook of the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/publications/publikaciya-socialnye-tendencii-kyrgyzskoj-respubliki/&#34;&gt;Social Trends of the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/publications/sbornik-zhenshiny-i-muzhchiny-kyrgyzskoj-respubliki/&#34;&gt;Women and Men in the Kyrgyz Republic&lt;/a&gt;, and many other regular and special publications available for download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special &lt;a href=&#34;https://stat.gov.kg/en/opendata/&#34;&gt;Open Data&lt;/a&gt; section provides downloadable data in additional formats (XML, JSON, and Excel).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extensive information about definitions, methodologies, and updates is generally available for the data collected. An &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stat.gov.kg/ru/rmc/institut/&#34;&gt;online learning&lt;/a&gt; section provides another avenue for learning about the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is navigable in Kyrgyz, Russian, and English. Most downloads of publications and tables are in Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Caspiana</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/caspiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/caspiana/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/&#34;&gt;Caspiana&lt;/a&gt;: A Digital Toolbox for Students and Scholars of Central Asia and the South Caucasus is a website created to facilitate research on the fascinating regions spreading east and west of the Caspian Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notably the site contains sections on &lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/exhibits/show/governance&#34;&gt;Governance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/exhibits/show/media&#34;&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://caspiana.omeka.fas.harvard.edu/exhibits/show/statistics&#34;&gt;Statistics&lt;/a&gt; that link to major government offices and information providers. Additional material includes academic resources such as conferences and language learning links.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
