<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Report on CAMGDP</title>
    <link>https://camgdp.org/data_type/report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Report on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 23:08:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://camgdp.org/data_type/report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>European Sex Workers Rights Alliance</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/eswra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/eswra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002 under the name of International Committee for Sex Workers in Europe (ICRSE), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eswalliance.org/&#34;&gt;European Sex Workers Rights Alliance&lt;/a&gt; is a sex worker-led network representing more than 100 organizations in 30 countries across Europe and Central Asia. One of its recent publication is &amp;ldquo;Sex work &amp;amp; racism: the impact of structural racism on racialized sex workers in Europe and Central Asia&amp;rdquo; report.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ILGA-Europe</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ilga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ilga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ilga-europe.org/&#34;&gt;ILGA-Europe&lt;/a&gt; is an International NGO advocating for the protection of LGBTI people and uniting over 600 organizations from 54 countries across Europe and Central Asia. ILGA conducts its work through resourcing and connecting communities, driving political change, and amplifying voices. Its mission is to provide a solid foundation for activists and organizations. ILGA publishes reports on the protection of rights of LGBTI people in Central Asia, specifically related to violence and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECOM</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ecom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/ecom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecom.ngo/&#34;&gt;ECOM (Eurasian Coalition for Health, Rights, Gender and Sexual Diversity)&lt;/a&gt; is a regional NGO working the sphere of health of LGBTI communities in Eastern Europe and Central Asia. It is a membership association open to non-profit organizations and activists working in the field. ECOM publishes regular reports on violation of rights of the LGBTI people in various Central Asian countries, including Uzbekistan and Tajikistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Policy Research Institute</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/foreign_policy_research_institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/foreign_policy_research_institute/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002, based in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fpri.org/central-asia-initiative/&#34;&gt;Foreign Policy Research Institute&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to producing research and policy analysis with the focus on foreign policy and national security challenges facing the US. Its Central Asia Initiative produces analyses of trends in the region concerning the US national security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friedrich Ebert Stiftung</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/fes_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/fes_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/fesuzbekistan/&#34;&gt;FES Uzbekistan&lt;/a&gt; was founded in 1997. The foundation&amp;rsquo;s mission in the country is stated as promoting ideas of inclusive society and contributing to the development of just economic and social politics, as well as supporting civil society, labor unions, and gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Organization for Migration</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/iom_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/iom_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iom.int/countries/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;IOM&lt;/a&gt; presence in Uzbekistan began in 2003. In 2019, Uzbekistan officially became a member-state of the IOM. The organization was officially accredited in April 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are currently no reports or country-specific research conducted by the IOM in Uzbekistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OECD</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/oecd_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/oecd_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Uzbekistan is not a member of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/uzbekistan/&#34;&gt;OECD&lt;/a&gt;. It has recently joined the OECD/G20 Inclusive Framework on BEPS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No gender-sensitive data appears to be available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/spotlight_initiative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/central-asia&#34;&gt;Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt; is a research and advocacy campaign dedicated to eliminating sexual and gender-based violence and harmful practices in Central Asia. The program involves UN Women, UNDP, and UNFPA with funding from the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan 2020 report is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spotlightinitiative.org/publications/spotlight-initiative-central-asia-and-afghanistan-programme-report-2020&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt; in English. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/kazakhstan/projects/spotlight-initiative-regional-programme-central-asia-and-afghanistan&#34;&gt;UNDP project page for the Spotlight Initiative Regional Programme for Central Asia and Afghanistan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNDP</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/un_uz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/un_uz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;UN Development Program&lt;/a&gt; became active in Uzbekistan in 1993 and works on projects related to the national government, business, civil society and academic affairs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UNDP regularly published press releases on the topic of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undp.org/uzbekistan/gender-equality&#34;&gt;gender equality development&lt;/a&gt; in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://evaw-global-database.unwomen.org/en/countries/asia/uzbekistan&#34;&gt;Global database on violence against women&lt;/a&gt; assembles UN data on different forms of violence against women, including all UN-issued reports and updates on Gender Equality Indexes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://uzbekistan.unfpa.org&#34;&gt;UN Population Fund&lt;/a&gt; produces country-specific landing pages. The work of the Fund includes data on sexual and reproductive health, gender equality, young people, and population matters. Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unfpa.org/data/UZ&#34;&gt;Data Portal for Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt; gender-related data across six main components: population, sexual and reproductive health, family planning, education, gender, rights, and human capital, and harmful practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friedrich Ebert Stiftung</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/fes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/fes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1925 in Germany with a Kazakhstani office opened in 1993, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.fes.de/&#34;&gt;Friedrich Ebert Stiftung&lt;/a&gt; is a foundation funded by the German government. The INGO focuses on social and gender justice issues, as well as political participation and youth leadership.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Publications on Kazakhstan include population surveys, particularly focused on youth, and are available in English, Kazakh, and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Published surveys include &amp;ldquo;Youth and Education,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Values,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Social Justice.&amp;rdquo; Gendered breakdown of data is included for some survey questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Organization for Migration</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/iom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/iom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.iom.int/&#34;&gt;International Organization for Migration&lt;/a&gt; publishes &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.iom.int/data-and-resources&#34;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; on migration issues in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data is usually presented in gendered format splitting respondents between male and female. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available. Reports are available in English, Kazakh, and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/oecd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/oecd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is not a member of the OECD and acts as its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;partner for the Eurasian region&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Out of available data on Kazakhstan found on the OECD portal, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/gender-policy-delivery-in-kazakhstan-9789264280359-en.htm&#34;&gt;2017 Gender Policy Delivery in Kazakhstan review&lt;/a&gt; is so far the only gender-related publication on Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The review contains policy assessment and recommendation. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Economic Forum’s Global Gender Gap Report</title>
      <link>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://camgdp.org/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weforum.org/reports/global-gender-gap-report-2022&#34;&gt;World Economic Forum’s Global Gender Gap Report&lt;/a&gt; includes countries’ score cards summarizing key gendered data findings broken down into 11 categories: economic participation and opportunity, educational attainment, health and survival, political empowerment, general indicators, work participation and leadership, access to finance, civil and political freedom, family and care, education and skills, and health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available. User’s guide how to read the economy profiles &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weforum.org/reports/global-gender-gap-report-2022/in-full/user-s-guide-how-to-read-the-economy-profiles&#34;&gt;is provided&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
