<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – sex education</title>
    <link>/tags/sex-education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sex education on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/sex-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Queernyi squirt</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/queernyi-squirt/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2022 by Mira Ungarova and Mutali Moskeu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://podcast.kz/1657513218/info&#34;&gt;Queernyi Squirt&lt;/a&gt; is an 18+ podcast dedicated to inclusive LGBTQIA+ sex education in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Manarifat</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/manarifat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/manarifat/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/manarifat/&#34;&gt;Manarifat&lt;/a&gt; is a social media initiative dedicated to matters of sexual and reproductive health of women. It offers educational content on often stigmatized topics related to sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: PaperLab</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/paperlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/paperlab/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015 and supported by the Soros Foundation-Kazakhstan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://paperlab.kz/&#34;&gt;PaperLab&lt;/a&gt; is a public policy research organization in Kazakhstan. PaperLab publishes research, organizes public discussions, and offers training and networking opportunities to Central Asian experts. Most publications are in Kazakh and Russian and sometimes in English. PaperLab has done extensive research on sex education in Kazakhstan and frequently collaborates with other NGOs and INGOs on the topic of violence against women. Methodology note and description of sources are not always included in the publications.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Uyat Emes</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/uyat_emes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/uyat_emes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://uyatemes.kz/&#34;&gt;Uyat Emes&lt;/a&gt; is an educational site about sex and relationships for Kazakhstani teenagers and their parents. The mission of the initiative is to help young people become more literate about reproductive health and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
