<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMGDP – general INGO</title>
    <link>/tags/general-ingo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in general INGO on CAMGDP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/general-ingo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Eurasia Foundation</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/eurasia_foundation/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2004 and based in Washington, DC, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/where-we-work/asia/&#34;&gt;Eurasia Foundation&lt;/a&gt; works with international, national, and local partners for community action. The foundation has a variety of international and local donors. Areas of expertise include civil society, youth and leadership, media, governance, and [gender and marginalized communities] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&#34;&gt;https://www.eurasia.org/what-we-do/gender-and-marginalized-groups/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Foreign Policy Research Institute</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/foreign_policy_research_institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/foreign_policy_research_institute/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2002, based in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fpri.org/central-asia-initiative/&#34;&gt;Foreign Policy Research Institute&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to producing research and policy analysis with the focus on foreign policy and national security challenges facing the US. Its Central Asia Initiative produces analyses of trends in the region concerning the US national security.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Friedrich Ebert Stiftung</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/fes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/fes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1925 in Germany with a Kazakhstani office opened in 1993, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.fes.de/&#34;&gt;Friedrich Ebert Stiftung&lt;/a&gt; is a foundation funded by the German government. The INGO focuses on social and gender justice issues, as well as political participation and youth leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publications on Kazakhstan include population surveys, particularly focused on youth, and are available in English, Kazakh, and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published surveys include &amp;ldquo;Youth and Education,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Values,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Youth and Social Justice.&amp;rdquo; Gendered breakdown of data is included for some survey questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://library.fes.de/pdf-files/bueros/kasachstan/18450.pdf&#34;&gt;Youth in Kazakhstan 2021 survey&lt;/a&gt; has five main section, including (1) values and orientations, (2) life plans, education, employment, and immigration, (3) youth and politics, and (4) foreign policy and attitudes toward Central Asia. The values and orientation section incorporates questions on attitudes toward abortion, homosexuality, different sexual practices, and other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey uses mixed method approach and includes a methodology chapter.   &lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: International Organization for Migration</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/iom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/iom/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.iom.int/&#34;&gt;International Organization for Migration&lt;/a&gt; publishes &lt;a href=&#34;https://kazakhstan.iom.int/data-and-resources&#34;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; on migration issues in Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is usually presented in gendered format splitting respondents between male and female. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available. Reports are available in English, Kazakh, and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/oecd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/oecd/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan is not a member of the OECD and acts as its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/&#34;&gt;partner for the Eurasian region&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of available data on Kazakhstan found on the OECD portal, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oecd.org/countries/kazakhstan/gender-policy-delivery-in-kazakhstan-9789264280359-en.htm&#34;&gt;2017 Gender Policy Delivery in Kazakhstan review&lt;/a&gt; is so far the only gender-related publication on Kazakhstan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The review contains policy assessment and recommendation. Methodological note and information on data collection are not available.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: Prague Civil Society Centre</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/prague_civil_society_centre/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Founded in 2014 and based in Prague, the Czech Republic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.praguecivilsociety.org/&#34;&gt;Prague Civil Society Centre&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to enabling civic groups and journalists to connect with their communities through grant making, capacity building, and learning. The Centre is funded by governments of Sweden, the Czech Republic, the UK, and the US, as well as the European Commission, the Oak Foundation, and the Wellspring Philanthropic Fund. Focuses on Eastern Europe and Central Asia. In addition to civil society programs, the Centre publishes media and publications on various topics related to the civic groups in Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sources: World Economic Forum’s Global Gender Gap Report</title>
      <link>/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sources/sources/wef_global_gender_gap_report/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weforum.org/reports/global-gender-gap-report-2022&#34;&gt;World Economic Forum’s Global Gender Gap Report&lt;/a&gt; includes countries’ score cards summarizing key gendered data findings broken down into 11 categories: economic participation and opportunity, educational attainment, health and survival, political empowerment, general indicators, work participation and leadership, access to finance, civil and political freedom, family and care, education and skills, and health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological note and information on data collection are not available. User’s guide how to read the economy profiles &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weforum.org/reports/global-gender-gap-report-2022/in-full/user-s-guide-how-to-read-the-economy-profiles&#34;&gt;is provided&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
